<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>APEC on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/apec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in APEC on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/apec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inductorless Soft Switching DC-DC Converter with an Optimized Piezoelectric Resonator</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</guid>
      <description>The inductor presents one of the biggest obstacles in miniaturizing power electronics. In this paper we present a piezoelectric resonator for power conversion fabricated out of lithium niobate, a material that has several advantages for high frequency power conversion compared to the more commonly used PZT ceramics. The piezoelectric resonator is used in a step-down dc-dc converter that achieves zero voltage soft switching and a continuously variable conversion ratio without the use of magnetic components. The converter operates at 6.3MHz and has a maximum power output of 30W at an efficiency of 92.7%, achieving a power density of 16.7 W/cm 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device for MHz Switching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present a WBG high-voltage GaN/SiC cascode device, combining the advantages of both a GaN and a SiC device: simple gate drive requirements, E oss loss per cycle roughly independent of frequency, and relatively high voltage blocking capability. This cascode device is capable of blocking 1.2 kV, while consuming 558 mW at the gate when operating at 13.56 MHz. A 700 W Class E inverter implemented with the proposed cascoded device achieves 91 % efficiency at 13.56 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In recent reports, a variety of power devices, including wide-bandgap transistors, SiC diodes, and Si superjuction MOSFETs, exhibit losses occurring from hysteretic charging and discharging of their output capacitance (COSS for MOSFETs and CJ for Schottky diodes). Manufacturer SPICE models and datasheets do not report these losses, and are why device power dissipation in simulation significantly contrasts with that in actual converters. However, we propose a viable empirical circuit model that incorporates these losses, with capabilities to integrate into circuit simulation tools such as SPICE.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
