<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>APEC on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/apec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in APEC on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/apec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inductorless Soft Switching DC-DC Converter with an Optimized Piezoelectric Resonator</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</guid>
      <description>The inductor presents one of the biggest obstacles in miniaturizing power electronics. In this paper we present a piezoelectric resonator for power conversion fabricated out of lithium niobate, a material that has several advantages for high frequency power conversion compared to the more commonly used PZT ceramics. The piezoelectric resonator is used in a step-down dc-dc converter that achieves zero voltage soft switching and a continuously variable conversion ratio without the use of magnetic components. The converter operates at 6.3MHz and has a maximum power output of 30W at an efficiency of 92.7%, achieving a power density of 16.7 W/cm 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device for MHz Switching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present a WBG high-voltage GaN/SiC cascode device, combining the advantages of both a GaN and a SiC device: simple gate drive requirements, E oss loss per cycle roughly independent of frequency, and relatively high voltage blocking capability. This cascode device is capable of blocking 1.2 kV, while consuming 558 mW at the gate when operating at 13.56 MHz. A 700 W Class E inverter implemented with the proposed cascoded device achieves 91 % efficiency at 13.56 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In recent reports, a variety of power devices, including wide-bandgap transistors, SiC diodes, and Si superjuction MOSFETs, exhibit losses occurring from hysteretic charging and discharging of their output capacitance (COSS for MOSFETs and CJ for Schottky diodes). Manufacturer SPICE models and datasheets do not report these losses, and are why device power dissipation in simulation significantly contrasts with that in actual converters. However, we propose a viable empirical circuit model that incorporates these losses, with capabilities to integrate into circuit simulation tools such as SPICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60 V-to-35 kV input-parallel output-series DC-DC converter using multi-level class-DE rectifiers</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-35kv-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-35kv-park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a high-voltage dc-dc converter that includes inductively-isolated rectifiers. Previous work on multi-stage class-DE rectifiers only included capacitive dc isolation, limiting the output voltage to twice of the capacitor voltage rating. By adding an air-core transformer before the rectifier for inductive isolation, the maximum output voltage can be twice the breakdown voltage of the insulation between the transformer&amp;rsquo;s primary and secondary windings, thus allowing the implementation of a small, lightweight, and fast transient high-voltage dc-dc converter. We experimentally demonstrate a multi-modular converter design with 60 V input voltage and 35 kV output voltage with 73 % efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output capacitance losses in 600 V GaN power semiconductors with large voltage swings at high- and very-high-frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we construct three Class-Φ 2 resonant converters with GaN HEMT power devices, 1 kW output power, and switching frequencies of 10 MHz, 30 MHz, and 54.24 MHz. The GaN HEMTs in these converters exhibit losses, approximated thermally, that are significantly higher (up to an order of magnitude) than those predicted by simulation. To investigate, we use a Sawyer-Tower circuit to evaluate the losses in the output capacitance, C OSS , of GaN devices from each manufacturer with commercially-available power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power loss of GaN transistor reverse diodes in a high frequency high voltage resonant rectifier</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-gan-rectifier_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-gan-rectifier_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents power loss measurements of GaN transistor reverse diodes in high frequency high voltage conditions. To evaluate their performance, we use GaN transistor reverse diodes as rectifying devices in a class-DE resonant rectifier and operate the circuit at switching frequencies of 10s of MHz and with output voltages reaching 100s of volts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structurally supportive RF power inverter for a CubeSat electrothermal plasma micro-thruster with PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with air core inductors for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are low volume and are part of an investigation seeking to add propulsion to low cost CubeSats. The air core inductors used in the proposed RF power inverter are formed with PCB traces allowing for a planar and compact design. Advantages of air core inductors include not being subject to saturation or variations from changing material properties of a magnetic core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal line input power factor preregulator using VFX technique</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a power factor preregulator design in which the energy buffer capacitor is placed at the output of the converter. In this implementation, a resonant LLC converter supplies power to a boost converter operating in continuous conduction mode. Here, a variable frequency (VFX) technique is used in the resonant LLC converter stage to achieve a lower variation in the overall efficiency across the universal input voltage range (85 - 265V rms ).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
