<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sanghyeon Park on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/sanghyeon-park/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sanghyeon Park on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/sanghyeon-park/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sanghyeon Park, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/sanghyeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/sanghyeon/</guid>
      <description> Doctoral Dissertation   Circuit techniques for compact and lightweight high-voltage dc power supplies      Presented on April 13, 2021  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight High Voltage Generator for Untethered Electroadhesive Perching of Micro Air Vehicles</title>
      <link>/publication/hv-untethered-perching_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hv-untethered-perching_park/</guid>
      <description>In this letter, we motivate the need for application-specific power electronics solutions for electroadhesive perching, develop a useful figure of merit (the “specific voltage”) for comparing and guiding efforts, and walk through the design methodology of a system implementation. We conclude by showing that this high voltage power supply enables, for the first time in the literature, tetherless electroadhesive perching of a commercial micro quadrotor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Design of Multi-MHz Frequency Isolated Auxiliary Power Supply for Gate Drivers in Medium-Voltage Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/mhz-isolated-auxps-gatedrive_spro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mhz-isolated-auxps-gatedrive_spro/</guid>
      <description>This article presents the design and optimization of a suitable topology for an isolated dc–dc auxiliary power supply with high isolation voltage and low coupling capacitance. The converter consists of a GaN HEMT inverter operating at 6.78 MHz, an LCC resonance tank, and a class-E low dv/dt rectifier.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
