<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JiaLe Xu on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/jiale-xu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JiaLe Xu on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/jiale-xu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JiaLe Xu</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jialexu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jialexu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiC, GaN and Si technology comparison for high power RF plasma generators</title>
      <link>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</guid>
      <description>   Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Summary We are studying the electric properties of SiC and GaN devices to design high power, high frequency RF plasma generators
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC: A Wide-Bandgap Heterogenous Power Device for High-Frequency Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>operating at higher frequencies requires faster switching devices in packages with low parasitics. Wide-bandgap (WBG) power devices, such as gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) devices, have high-critical fields and high-thermal conductivity that make them good candidates for efficient high-voltage and high-frequency operations. Commercially available GaN and SiC devices have ratings targeting different applications. Lateral GaN devices dominate in lower voltage(&amp;lt;; 650V) and high-frequency applications as they have relatively small device capacitances (C oss , C iss ), which make them easy to drive at high frequencies. This paper presents a cascoded GaN/SiC device that overcome many of these limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitor Variations on Switched-Capacitor and Resonant Switched-Capacitor Converters,</title>
      <link>/publication/class2caps-variation-switchedcap_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/class2caps-variation-switchedcap_xu/</guid>
      <description>Class 2 ceramic capacitors, such as X7R, have relatively high energy density compared to Class 1 ceramic capacitors. However, they experience changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1%-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25 °C to 125 °C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. The measured equivalent series resistance (ESR) of the X7R capacitors shows an increase of 20% to 70% due to aging of 1680 h, and a 50% fluctuation in value when we apply 20% to 80% of the rated voltage</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
