<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Amplifiers on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/power-amplifiers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Amplifiers on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/power-amplifiers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>6.78-MHz Wireless Power Transfer With Self-Resonant Coils at 95% DC–DC Efficiency</title>
      <link>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</guid>
      <description>This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and a better understanding of C oss losses in wide-bandgap power semiconductors, we demonstrate 6.78- MHz wireless power transfer systems that achieve 95% dc-dc efficiency at power levels up to and beyond 1 kW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push–Pull Class Φ2  RF Power Amplifier</title>
      <link>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</guid>
      <description>This work focuses on improving the design and operating characteristics of a push–pull $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier with a $T$ network connected between the switch nodes, or a PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier. The PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier has less circulating energy and achieves higher cutoff frequency &lt;sub&gt;T&lt;/sub&gt; than other $\Phi _\text2$/EF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; circuits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC: A Wide-Bandgap Heterogenous Power Device for High-Frequency Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>operating at higher frequencies requires faster switching devices in packages with low parasitics. Wide-bandgap (WBG) power devices, such as gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) devices, have high-critical fields and high-thermal conductivity that make them good candidates for efficient high-voltage and high-frequency operations. Commercially available GaN and SiC devices have ratings targeting different applications. Lateral GaN devices dominate in lower voltage(&amp;lt;; 650V) and high-frequency applications as they have relatively small device capacitances (C oss , C iss ), which make them easy to drive at high frequencies. This paper presents a cascoded GaN/SiC device that overcome many of these limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This article proposes an HF/very HF (VHF) resonant converter structure in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal. The presented structure enables efficient bidirectional power delivery in the HF/VHF range for applications that require a large voltage conversion ratio. A 64-MHz, 12-W, 36-12-V prototype converter verifies the operation of the structure. This article further explores an interleaved architecture of the same circuit to improve efficiency and transient performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
