<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke Raymond on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/luke-raymond/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Luke Raymond on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/luke-raymond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Luke Raymond, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/lukeraymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/lukeraymond/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated RF Power Delivery and Plasma Micro-Thruster System for Nano-Satellites</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</guid>
      <description>Progress in satellite technologies is ongoing and eventually finds applications back on Earth. Electric propulsion systems have been proven effective on large scale satellites (NASA DAWN) with better propellant efficiency than chemical or cold gas propulsion, and if miniaturized can be promising for long term operation of nano-satellites (e.g., CubeSats) in low Earth orbit or in deep space (NASA MarCO). Here we present a compact and efficient switched mode dc-RF power inverter integrated with an electro-thermal plasma micro-thruster for nano-satellite (e.g., Cubesats) propulsion. The integrated system can serve as side panels and structural support of CubeSats, saving precious on-board volume for propellant and/or payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact RF power inverter with reduced EMI for a CubeSat electrothermal micro-thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>TThis paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with a PCB multi-resonant input filter for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are part of an investigation seeking to add micro propulsion systems to low cost CubeSats. The proposed RF power inverter and multi-resonant input filter use only air core inductors. All inductors are toroidal and formed by PCB traces and vias allowing a planar and compact design. The PCB structure serves as structural support to save space and volume for propulsion propellant and other payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structurally supportive RF power inverter for a CubeSat electrothermal plasma micro-thruster with PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with air core inductors for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are low volume and are part of an investigation seeking to add propulsion to low cost CubeSats. The air core inductors used in the proposed RF power inverter are formed with PCB traces allowing for a planar and compact design. Advantages of air core inductors include not being subject to saturation or variations from changing material properties of a magnetic core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Mass RF Power Inverter for CubeSat Applications Using 3-D Printed Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low-mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g., tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as CubeSat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3-D printing of lightweight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2-MHz 50-W resonant dc-RF power inverter implemented with 3-D printed and copper plated air core toroidal inductors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Testing of a Miniaturized Switch Mode Amplifier Powering an Electrothermal Plasma Micro-Thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</guid>
      <description>A structurally supportive miniaturized low-weight (≤150 g) radiofrequency switch mode amplifier developed to power the small diameter Pocket Rocket electrothermal plasma micro-thruster called MiniPR is tested in vacuum conditions representative of space to demonstrate its suitability for use on nano-satellites such as “CubeSats.” The switch mode amplifier design is finely tuned to the input impedance of the thruster (~16 pF) to provide a power efficiency of 88% at the resonant frequency and a direct feed to a low-loss (~10 %) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inductance cancellation in RF resonant power converters</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-inductance-cancellation_praglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-inductance-cancellation_praglin/</guid>
      <description>Parasitic inductance cancellation is employed in order to operate a resonant power inverter at 27.12 MHz using a TO-220 through-hole package.The elimination of parasitic inductances allows for system cost reduction, increased power handling, and/or relaxation of PCB layout constraints. The inductance cancellation technique is demonstrated through two prototypes (based upon the same silicon MOSFET die) providing 60 W of RF power to a 50 Ω load from a 48 V DC input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low mass RF power inverter for cubesat plasma thruster using 3D printed inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-thurster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-thurster_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g. tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as cubesat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3D printing of light-weight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2 MHz 50 W resonant DC-RF power inverter implemented with 3D printed and plated air core toroidal inductors. The inverter achieves 90% electrical efficiency when operated on a 50 Ω resistive load at an input voltage of 50 V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonant bi-polar DC pulse power supply for electroporation applications</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-electroporation_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-electroporation_raymond/</guid>
      <description>Electroporation is a technique that uses high pulsed electric fields to create pores in biological cell walls for medical, liquid sterilization and other applications. Many systems use mono-polar pulses for simplicity but electro-migration can limit electrode life. The following paper demonstrates a resonant circuit design for creating high voltage bi-polar dc pulses using a simple control strategy. The circuit topology consists of two Radio Frequency (RF) amplifiers each coupled to a multi-level resonant rectifier employing capacitive isolation and operating at 15 MHz. The RF signals generated by the amplifiers themselves are used to control the pulse duration and output polarity. Any sequence of positive and negative pulse trains can be generated between several μs through dc. This paper presents a proof of concept design providing 800 V positive and negative pulses into a resistive load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz isolated high voltage gain multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a high efficiency, high power density, and fast transient response dc-dc converter design capable of providing a high-voltage isolated output from a low-voltage input. Specifically, we demonstrate two 100 W, 2000 Vdc proof of concept prototype dc-dc converters operating at a switching frequency of 27.12 MHz with input voltages of 40 V and 100 V respectively. Capacitive isolation provides an efficient means of allowing for multiple rectified outputs to be combined serially without exceeding semi-conductor device limits. Further, it can provide a more efficient means of impedance matching at frequencies of 10s of MHz than traditional methods such as passive matching networks or transformers by the reduction of or elimination of those stages altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN resonant power converter with PCB embedded resonant air core inductors and capacitors</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a 27.12 MHz, 320 W, 170 V to 28 V dc-dc resonant power converter with resonant inductors and capacitors embedded into the Printed Circuit Board (PCB). Operating at 27.12 MHz allows for small value and size resonant passive components to be implemented using traces on or within a PCB. A prototype dc-dc converter was built to verify the concept and it reaches an efficiency of 73.6%. A simulated loss analysis is also presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network. Multiple stages are stacked in a way that allows for higher output voltages without suffering efficiency penalties common to traditional serial type high-voltage converter topologies such as the Crockroft-Walton Multiplier. Application of this design results in an isolated resonant dc-dc converter design that promises high efficiency, fast transient response, and high power density while providing a high-voltage isolated output from a lower-voltage input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN Bi-directional resonant power converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>Resonant dc-dc converter regularly use Schottky diodes for high frequency rectification. Si Schottky diodes have relatively low voltage ratings and present reverse-recovery type losses when driven hard enough. SiC Schottky diodes can operate at high frequencies, but incur higher conduction losses. This paper presents a bidirectional dc-dc resonant converter having two ground referenced switches. The prototype converter delivers 400 W between a source of 170 V and a load of 50 V while delivering 250 W in the opposite direction. The converter presented herein can potentially be used in applications such as wireless power transfer, fuel cell and battery applications, bus converters, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D-Printed Air-Core Inductors for High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling, and characterization of 3-D-printed air-core inductors for high-frequency power electronics circuits. The use of 3-D modeling techniques to make passive components extends the design flexibility and addresses some of the fabrication limitations of traditional processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air-core inductors realized using 3-D printing and casting/plating techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to design. Toward this goal, we present a 70-W prototype 27.12-MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3-D-printed components developed for this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
