<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Luke Raymond on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/luke-raymond/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Luke Raymond on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/luke-raymond/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Luke Raymond, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/lukeraymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/lukeraymond/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated RF Power Delivery and Plasma Micro-Thruster System for Nano-Satellites</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</guid>
      <description>Progress in satellite technologies is ongoing and eventually finds applications back on Earth. Electric propulsion systems have been proven effective on large scale satellites (NASA DAWN) with better propellant efficiency than chemical or cold gas propulsion, and if miniaturized can be promising for long term operation of nano-satellites (e.g., CubeSats) in low Earth orbit or in deep space (NASA MarCO). Here we present a compact and efficient switched mode dc-RF power inverter integrated with an electro-thermal plasma micro-thruster for nano-satellite (e.g., Cubesats) propulsion. The integrated system can serve as side panels and structural support of CubeSats, saving precious on-board volume for propellant and/or payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact RF power inverter with reduced EMI for a CubeSat electrothermal micro-thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>TThis paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with a PCB multi-resonant input filter for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are part of an investigation seeking to add micro propulsion systems to low cost CubeSats. The proposed RF power inverter and multi-resonant input filter use only air core inductors. All inductors are toroidal and formed by PCB traces and vias allowing a planar and compact design. The PCB structure serves as structural support to save space and volume for propulsion propellant and other payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Mass RF Power Inverter for CubeSat Applications Using 3-D Printed Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low-mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g., tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as CubeSat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3-D printing of lightweight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2-MHz 50-W resonant dc-RF power inverter implemented with 3-D printed and copper plated air core toroidal inductors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Testing of a Miniaturized Switch Mode Amplifier Powering an Electrothermal Plasma Micro-Thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</guid>
      <description>A structurally supportive miniaturized low-weight (≤150 g) radiofrequency switch mode amplifier developed to power the small diameter Pocket Rocket electrothermal plasma micro-thruster called MiniPR is tested in vacuum conditions representative of space to demonstrate its suitability for use on nano-satellites such as “CubeSats.” The switch mode amplifier design is finely tuned to the input impedance of the thruster (~16 pF) to provide a power efficiency of 88% at the resonant frequency and a direct feed to a low-loss (~10 %) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D-Printed Air-Core Inductors for High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling, and characterization of 3-D-printed air-core inductors for high-frequency power electronics circuits. The use of 3-D modeling techniques to make passive components extends the design flexibility and addresses some of the fabrication limitations of traditional processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air-core inductors realized using 3-D printing and casting/plating techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to design. Toward this goal, we present a 70-W prototype 27.12-MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3-D-printed components developed for this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
