<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ICN on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/icn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ICN on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/icn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design of a 13.56 MHz dc-to-dc resonant converter using an impedance compression network to mitigate misalignments in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency resonant converter with an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct horizontal alignment variations between coils in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system. In order to mitigate variations in coil impedance, we propose an ICN that simultaneously compresses magnitude and phase changes of coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an impedance compression network to correct misalignment in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct distance variation or misalignment between coils in wireless power transfer (WPT) systems. Magnetic resonant coupling (MRC) coils provide high efficiency for charging mid-range WPT applications. However, a distance variation or misalignment between coils causes a coil-impedance change and significantly affects performances of WPT systems. In order to mitigate a coil-impedance variation, we propose an ICN simultaneously compressing changes in magnitude and phase of impedance. The ICN consists of a resistance compression network (RCN) and phase compression network (PCN). While the RCN effectively compresses the variation in the magnitude of impedance by using one pair consisting of an inductor and a capacitor, the PCN is designed using a Smith chart to reduce a phase variation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
