<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grayson Zulauf on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/grayson-zulauf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grayson Zulauf on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/grayson-zulauf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Grayson Zulauf, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/graysonzulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/graysonzulauf/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   Wide-bandgap semiconductors for next-generation power electronics systems      Presented on May 19, 2020 Availabe for download here.  Summary     Wide-bandgap power semiconductors promise to reshape the power electronics landscape, opening completely new use cases and increasing efficiency and power density in existing ones. Most notably, gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) were successfully commercialized in the past decades, with theoretical benefits over silicon of multiple orders-of-magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of ${C}_{{\mathrm {oss}}}$ and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 kW, Multi-MHz Wireless Charging for Electric Transportation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</guid>
      <description>We design and build a DC-DC wireless power system for electric vehicles charging at 6.78 MHz. With a gap of 34 cm, the air-core system can transfer up to 1 kW with 82% efficiency. It can operate continuously without failure even when the gap varies from 26 to 38 cm, and though the output power changes with distance, the efficiency does not vary appreciably. Due to the high operating frequency, the transfer coils are lightweight, inexpensive, and mechanically robust, even with a gap much larger than in previous literature. The systems low cost and resilience across coupling makes it amenable to mass deployment in commercial systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Self-Resonant Coils</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</guid>
      <description>MHz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer holds the promise of increased power density and high- efficiency wireless power transfer. Unfortunately, due to high- frequency losses in wide-bandgap semiconductors and low-Q high-frequency coil designs, these systems are universally less efficient, on a dc-dc basis, than wireless power systems operating at conventional frequency regimes. This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. Particularly, we present the optimal compensation strategy for parallel compensated coils, which is a topic less frequently discussed in literature than the series compensated coils. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and an optimal design strategy, we demonstrate a 6.78 MHz, 300 W wireless power transfer system that achieves 95 % dc-dc efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A physical investigation of large-signal dynamic output capacitance and energy loss in GaN-on-Si power HEMTs at high-frequency applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-physical-large-signal-dynamic-output-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-physical-large-signal-dynamic-output-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of Coss and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of GaN buffer layers and Si-substrate. These loss components can be potentially improved by re-engineering the doping concentrations in the buffer stacks and substrate layer. This paper presents a physics view of the trapping dynamics that is related to C oss in the GaN HEMT under large-signal excitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.78-MHz Wireless Power Transfer With Self-Resonant Coils at 95% DC–DC Efficiency</title>
      <link>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</guid>
      <description>This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and a better understanding of C oss losses in wide-bandgap power semiconductors, we demonstrate 6.78- MHz wireless power transfer systems that achieve 95% dc-dc efficiency at power levels up to and beyond 1 kW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Multi-MHz Switching Frequencies on Dynamic On-Resistance in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/impact-mhz-dynamicrdson_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/impact-mhz-dynamicrdson_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic on-resistance (dRon), where the on-resistance immediately after turn-on is higher than the DC resistance, increases the conduction losses in power converters with gallium nitride high-electron-mobility transistors (GaN HEMTs). There exist no direct dR on measurements in the literature above 1 MHz, leaving designers unable to predict conduction losses in emerging multi-MHz applications. We address this literature gap by collecting the first on-state voltage dR on measurements at multi-MHz frequencies, with a focus on the zero-voltage-switching conditions that are predominantly employed at high frequency. On the selected commercially-available HEMT with a breakdown voltage below 200 V, the dynamic contribution asymptotes above ≈ 2 MHz, a finding predicted by the slow time constants of the traps that cause dR on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push–Pull Class Φ2  RF Power Amplifier</title>
      <link>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</guid>
      <description>This work focuses on improving the design and operating characteristics of a push–pull $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier with a $T$ network connected between the switch nodes, or a PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier. The PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier has less circulating energy and achieves higher cutoff frequency &lt;sub&gt;T&lt;/sub&gt; than other $\Phi _\text2$/EF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; circuits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This article proposes an HF/very HF (VHF) resonant converter structure in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal. The presented structure enables efficient bidirectional power delivery in the HF/VHF range for applications that require a large voltage conversion ratio. A 64-MHz, 12-W, 36-12-V prototype converter verifies the operation of the structure. This article further explores an interleaved architecture of the same circuit to improve efficiency and transient performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Turn Air-Core Coils for High-Frequency Inductive Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>The efficiency of megahertz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer designs is currently limited by the quality factor of the resonant tanks and the coils. In this article, we use two-dimensional finite-element analysis to optimize the cross section of single-turn air-core inductors for this application and demonstrate coils for wireless power at high-frequency and very-high-frequency industrial, scientific, and medical (ISM) bands. Our resonant tanks achieve diameter-normalized quality factors (Q d ) that are 25%-70% better than the state of the art for air-core coils at 6.78 MHz (Q d = 73 cm -1 ) and 13.56 MHz (102), and we show significant improvements at the 27.12 MHz (123) and 40.68 MHz (137) ISM bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation into the Causes of COSS Losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we investigate the origin of these losses in GaN-on-Si High Electron Mobility Transistors (HEMTs) using TCAD simulation and experimental techniques, and find that COSS losses can be separated into resistive loss and GaN-stack trap related loss. From device simulation, we observe the expected dependence of substrate displacement current on dV/dt, and the importance of resistive loss is further confirmed with an experimental Sawyer-Tower test with an external resistor attached to the substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output Capacitance Loss Characterization of Silicon Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>In high-frequency (HF) and very-high-frequency (VHF) rectifiers, silicon carbide (SiC) Schottky diodes exhibit higher losses compared to what is reported in manufacturer-provided simulation models, with additional power loss stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the junction output capacitance (CJ). Here, we compare measured losses across manufacturers, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging of variouis SiC Schottkey diodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to provide a road map for selecting power devices in soft-switched, megahertz (MHz) frequency power converters. Minimizing $C_{OSS}$ losses, which occur when charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor of power semiconductors, is critical to efficient operation. These losses are excluded from manufacturer-provided information, and measurements are either sparse or not reported at all in the existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coss Measurements for Superjunction MOSFETs: Limitations and Opportunities</title>
      <link>/publication/ted-coss-superjunction-zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ted-coss-superjunction-zulauf/</guid>
      <description>Small-signal measurements of output capacitance ( $C_{OSS}$ ) are ubiquitous in power semiconductor datasheets and determine critical features of power converters. For silicon superjunction power MOSFETs (SJs), we report $C_{OSS}$  measurements with two key anomalies: variation with ac perturbation frequency and hysteresis with dc sweep direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSS Losses in 600 V GaN Power Semiconductors in Soft-Switched, High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We report losses from charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, COSS , in Gallium Nitride (GaN) power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS. These losses are of particular importance in soft-switched circuits used at MHz switching frequencies, where the output capacitance of the device is charged and discharged once per switching cycle during the device off-time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
