<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resonant on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/resonant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resonant on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/resonant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Miniature High-Voltage DC-DC Power Converters for Space and Micro-Robotic Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</guid>
      <description>We develop a small and lightweight high-voltage high-gain power converter for applications where weight and size are premium. By driving a Dickson and Cockcroft-Walton voltage multiplier with a megahertz-frequency class-E inverter, we implement two converters, one that achieves 40 V-to-2 kV conversion with 16 cm 3 box volume and the other that achieves 3.7 V-to-2.9 kV conversion with 0.2 cm 3 box volume and 0.49 g weight. Presented converters achieve comparable or better power density and specific power to those of commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI Compatible DC Modulator for an Envelope Tracking Transmitter,</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</guid>
      <description>Typical MRI power amplifiers are characterized by the requirement for high linearity and a high peak-to-average power ratio. Here we present a MRI compatible DC modulator for envelope tracking applications based on a 4-phase interleaved buck converter using air core magnetics and utilizing a FPGA based digital controller. The modulator is capable of delivering 500 W into a 2.5 Ω load at an efficiency of 95.6%, has a 3 dB modulation bandwidth of 50 kHz, and has been tested with a Class-AB linear amplifier operating at 64 MHz to produce a modulated RF envelope with a peak power of 320 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase GaN Class-D Resonant Amplifier for High-Intensity Focused Ultrasound</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</guid>
      <description>Focused ultrasound treats tissue deep in the body without damaging surrounding structures. Driven by large-amplitude RF electrical signals, ultrasonic transducers can generate large pressure acoustic wave. Wide-bandgap semiconductors, e.g., Gallium Nitride (GaN), greatly simplify the design and reduce the requisite size and weight of RF amplifiers, and so improves the portability of focused ultrasound device. Here, we demonstrate a compact 8-phase 5 MHz Class-D resonant amplifier for a focused ultrasound cancer therapy application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide Input Range Isolated Stacked Resonant Switched-Capacitor dc-dc Converter for High Conversion Ratios</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an isolated dc-dc converter architecture for high conversion ratios using the stacked resonant switched-capacitor topology. Capacitive isolation is adopted in place of transformer isolation for saving cost and platform size. With phase shift operation, the topology can support a wide input range with a simple regulation scheme while enabling zero-voltage switching. The topology can be adapted to high conversion ratios via addition of stacking levels while keeping the same magnetics. The experimental results demonstrate a 2-Stack example achieving a peak efficiency of 92.8% and a peak power density of 283 W/inch 3 with 92% efficiency. The converter can also maintain within 3% efficiency drop over 25%-100% load range, and 50%-100% input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitance Variations on Switched Capacitor and Resonant Switched Capacitor Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the impact of Class 2 ceramic capacitance (such as X7R) variations on switched capacitor (SC) and resonant switched capacitor (ReSC) converters. Capacitance changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field are studied and modeled in LTSpice simulations. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25°C to 125°C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. Converter performance degradation is quantified in simulation and demonstrated by implementing a 1 MHz 25 W 1:4 Dickson ReSC converter. The converter efficiency decreases from 93.1% to 90.7% due to capacitance variations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
