<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Max Praglin on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/max-praglin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Max Praglin on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/max-praglin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Wide-Input-Range High-Efficiency Step-Down Power Factor Correction Converter Using a Variable Frequency Multiplier Technique,</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a step-down power factor preregulator design that achieves a high efficiency across the entire universal input voltage range (85-265 V rms ) for an offline power supply application. The proposed circuit allows MOSFETs with lower voltage ratings and better conduction/switching characteristics to be used in both converter stages. A scaling law of power losses versus breakdown voltage requirement for boost circuit under the condition of the same output power is presented. Experimental results demonstrated a flatter high efficiency performance across a wide input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Mass RF Power Inverter for CubeSat Applications Using 3-D Printed Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low-mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g., tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as CubeSat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3-D printing of lightweight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2-MHz 50-W resonant dc-RF power inverter implemented with 3-D printed and copper plated air core toroidal inductors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
