<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GaN on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/gan/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GaN on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/gan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of ${C}_{{\mathrm {oss}}}$ and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Method to Combine the Output Power from Multiple Class-E Power Amplifiers</title>
      <link>/publication/combiner-classe_north/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/combiner-classe_north/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present an alternative approach to designing a high-efficiency high power RF amplifier system. Here, we offer a simple tuning method that allows output powers from multiple power amplifiers to be combined directly without the need for an extra combiner network, given that the mismatches between the amplifiers are sufficiently small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Multi-MHz Switching Frequencies on Dynamic On-Resistance in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/impact-mhz-dynamicrdson_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/impact-mhz-dynamicrdson_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic on-resistance (dRon), where the on-resistance immediately after turn-on is higher than the DC resistance, increases the conduction losses in power converters with gallium nitride high-electron-mobility transistors (GaN HEMTs). There exist no direct dR on measurements in the literature above 1 MHz, leaving designers unable to predict conduction losses in emerging multi-MHz applications. We address this literature gap by collecting the first on-state voltage dR on measurements at multi-MHz frequencies, with a focus on the zero-voltage-switching conditions that are predominantly employed at high frequency. On the selected commercially-available HEMT with a breakdown voltage below 200 V, the dynamic contribution asymptotes above ≈ 2 MHz, a finding predicted by the slow time constants of the traps that cause dR on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC: A Wide-Bandgap Heterogenous Power Device for High-Frequency Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>operating at higher frequencies requires faster switching devices in packages with low parasitics. Wide-bandgap (WBG) power devices, such as gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) devices, have high-critical fields and high-thermal conductivity that make them good candidates for efficient high-voltage and high-frequency operations. Commercially available GaN and SiC devices have ratings targeting different applications. Lateral GaN devices dominate in lower voltage(&amp;lt;; 650V) and high-frequency applications as they have relatively small device capacitances (C oss , C iss ), which make them easy to drive at high frequencies. This paper presents a cascoded GaN/SiC device that overcome many of these limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Method to Eliminate Discrete Inductors in a Class-E Inverter Used in Wireless Power Transfer Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/eliminate-discrete-inductors-classe-wpt_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/eliminate-discrete-inductors-classe-wpt_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>we demonstrate a printed circuit board (PCB)-based WPT circuit operating at 40.68 MHz, utilizing no discrete inductors other than the WPT coils themselves and weighing only 7 g. This article describes the design methodology as well as the procedure to eliminate the discrete resonant inductors used in the implementation of our designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimization of a Class-E Power Amplifier With GaN HEMTs at Megahertz Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We examine the constraints that dictate when this optimization equations can and cannot be used, as well as propose a distributed loss model for the C oss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE) to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated. To verify our mathematical analysis and to demonstrate the applications of the proposed GSE-based C oss loss model, two design examples are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Turn Air-Core Coils for High-Frequency Inductive Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>The efficiency of megahertz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer designs is currently limited by the quality factor of the resonant tanks and the coils. In this article, we use two-dimensional finite-element analysis to optimize the cross section of single-turn air-core inductors for this application and demonstrate coils for wireless power at high-frequency and very-high-frequency industrial, scientific, and medical (ISM) bands. Our resonant tanks achieve diameter-normalized quality factors (Q d ) that are 25%-70% better than the state of the art for air-core coils at 6.78 MHz (Q d = 73 cm -1 ) and 13.56 MHz (102), and we show significant improvements at the 27.12 MHz (123) and 40.68 MHz (137) ISM bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation into the Causes of COSS Losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we investigate the origin of these losses in GaN-on-Si High Electron Mobility Transistors (HEMTs) using TCAD simulation and experimental techniques, and find that COSS losses can be separated into resistive loss and GaN-stack trap related loss. From device simulation, we observe the expected dependence of substrate displacement current on dV/dt, and the importance of resistive loss is further confirmed with an experimental Sawyer-Tower test with an external resistor attached to the substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loss Gate Driving Techniques of the Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device at High Frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</guid>
      <description>Cascoding a GaN HEMT and a SiC JFET best utilizes the advantages of both of these WBG power devices. Like GaN devices, the cascode GaN/SiC device is easy to drive at high frequencies and has low gate loss; like SiC devices, it also has relatively high voltage rating and low Coss energy loss at high frequencies. In this paper, we present our investigation of the gate loss mechanism of the SiC JFET in the cascode structure and our finding that the loss can be greatly reduced by minimizing the gate resistance of the SiC JFET (R g,Jfet ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimal Input Voltage of a Class-E Power Amplifier with GaN HEMTs at MHz Frequency Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We mathematically analyze the operation of a Class-E amplifier when facing with this Coss loss term. We have found that the conventional wisdom of using the highest input voltage to get the best efficiency no longer holds above a certain frequency. Furthermore, to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated, we propose a distributed loss model for the Coss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device for MHz Switching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present a WBG high-voltage GaN/SiC cascode device, combining the advantages of both a GaN and a SiC device: simple gate drive requirements, E oss loss per cycle roughly independent of frequency, and relatively high voltage blocking capability. This cascode device is capable of blocking 1.2 kV, while consuming 558 mW at the gate when operating at 13.56 MHz. A 700 W Class E inverter implemented with the proposed cascoded device achieves 91 % efficiency at 13.56 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substrate Bias Effect on E-Mode GaN-on-Si HEMT Coss Losses</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-substrate-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-substrate-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>Here, we use a back-gate bias between the source and Si substrate to investigate the capacitance characteristics of commercially-available GaN HEMTs. The small-signal capacitance is reduced significantly - up to 2 × for a 650 V HEMT and 4× for a 100 V HEMT - indicating that the drain-substrate capacitance is a significant portion of the total output capacitance. Our findings indicate that the buffer-substrate stack is likely an important driver of Coss losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs, and its optimization must be considered to efficiently use GaN HEMTs at high-frequencies. Traditional C oss measurements with the DC bias swept in both directions may give an indication of the relative level of trapping in this stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a 40.68 MHz power-combining resonant inverter with eGaN FETs for plasma generation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-40m68-gan_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-40m68-gan_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a 40.68 MHz, 1.2 kW power-combining resonant inverter using eGaN FETs for plasma generation. To provide high power at 40.68 MHz switching frequency, a class Φ2 inverter topology with wide band gap (WBG) devices such as eGaN FETs was selected. The proposed inverter topology reduces the power loss in each switching device, which can decrease the size of the heat sink. This study demonstrates that power-combining resonant inverters using eGaN FETs can increase efficiency and power density while operating at 40.68 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a 13.56 MHz dc-to-dc resonant converter using an impedance compression network to mitigate misalignments in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency resonant converter with an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct horizontal alignment variations between coils in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system. In order to mitigate variations in coil impedance, we propose an ICN that simultaneously compresses magnitude and phase changes of coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a GaN-Based, Inductor-less, Wireless Power Transfer System at 40.68 MHz</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>Wireless power transfer systems have attracted tremendous attention over the past decade. The design of most small size, low power, WPT systems; however, utilizes ferrite to shield and redirect the magnetic fields. This add to the weight and bulk of the system. In this paper, a small and extremely lightweight, PCB based, proof-of-concept WPT system is demonstrated. The circuit operates at 40.68 MHz and is capable of 20 W of output power. It utilizes no discrete inductors other than the WPT coils themselves and weights only 7 grams. The following paper shows the design methodology and the inductor elimination technique used to achieve such design.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
