<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Semiconductor Device Modeling on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/semiconductor-device-modeling/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Semiconductor Device Modeling on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/semiconductor-device-modeling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimization of a Class-E Power Amplifier With GaN HEMTs at Megahertz Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We examine the constraints that dictate when this optimization equations can and cannot be used, as well as propose a distributed loss model for the C oss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE) to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated. To verify our mathematical analysis and to demonstrate the applications of the proposed GSE-based C oss loss model, two design examples are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to provide a road map for selecting power devices in soft-switched, megahertz (MHz) frequency power converters. Minimizing $C_{OSS}$ losses, which occur when charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor of power semiconductors, is critical to efficient operation. These losses are excluded from manufacturer-provided information, and measurements are either sparse or not reported at all in the existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
