<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coss Loss on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/coss-loss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coss Loss on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/coss-loss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Selecting the Right Power Semiconductor for Multi-MHz Power Converters-Slides</title>
      <link>/talk/20200902_pels_webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/20200902_pels_webinar/</guid>
      <description>Abstract:     With the commercialization of wide-bandgap power semiconductors, multi-MHz switching frequencies are more compelling and critical to meet new applications demanding leaps in power density and efficiency. In the past, studies of these converters reported significant gaps between measured and modeled performance, often attributed to dynamic RDS, ON in GaN HEMTs. In particular, the power semiconductors – which often drive thermal constraints – dissipated much more power than expected, rendering designs based on simulated values unusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimization of a Class-E Power Amplifier With GaN HEMTs at Megahertz Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We examine the constraints that dictate when this optimization equations can and cannot be used, as well as propose a distributed loss model for the C oss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE) to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated. To verify our mathematical analysis and to demonstrate the applications of the proposed GSE-based C oss loss model, two design examples are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation into the Causes of COSS Losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we investigate the origin of these losses in GaN-on-Si High Electron Mobility Transistors (HEMTs) using TCAD simulation and experimental techniques, and find that COSS losses can be separated into resistive loss and GaN-stack trap related loss. From device simulation, we observe the expected dependence of substrate displacement current on dV/dt, and the importance of resistive loss is further confirmed with an experimental Sawyer-Tower test with an external resistor attached to the substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimal Input Voltage of a Class-E Power Amplifier with GaN HEMTs at MHz Frequency Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We mathematically analyze the operation of a Class-E amplifier when facing with this Coss loss term. We have found that the conventional wisdom of using the highest input voltage to get the best efficiency no longer holds above a certain frequency. Furthermore, to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated, we propose a distributed loss model for the Coss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In recent reports, a variety of power devices, including wide-bandgap transistors, SiC diodes, and Si superjuction MOSFETs, exhibit losses occurring from hysteretic charging and discharging of their output capacitance (COSS for MOSFETs and CJ for Schottky diodes). Manufacturer SPICE models and datasheets do not report these losses, and are why device power dissipation in simulation significantly contrasts with that in actual converters. However, we propose a viable empirical circuit model that incorporates these losses, with capabilities to integrate into circuit simulation tools such as SPICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substrate Bias Effect on E-Mode GaN-on-Si HEMT Coss Losses</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-substrate-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-substrate-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>Here, we use a back-gate bias between the source and Si substrate to investigate the capacitance characteristics of commercially-available GaN HEMTs. The small-signal capacitance is reduced significantly - up to 2 × for a 650 V HEMT and 4× for a 100 V HEMT - indicating that the drain-substrate capacitance is a significant portion of the total output capacitance. Our findings indicate that the buffer-substrate stack is likely an important driver of Coss losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs, and its optimization must be considered to efficiently use GaN HEMTs at high-frequencies. Traditional C oss measurements with the DC bias swept in both directions may give an indication of the relative level of trapping in this stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Off-State Losses in Silicon-Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/coss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/coss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>Among HF/VHF rectifiers, SiC Schottky diodes exhibit larger losses compared to those captured in simulation, with additional off-state losses stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the CJ. Because these losses are not included in manufacturer simulation models nor have they been well-studied for SiC Schottky diodes, we experimentally measured them using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and compared the losses across manufacturer, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging. Furthermore, we analyzed the performances of these devices on a class-DE rectifier and compared their power dissipation from the simulation and experimental measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-powerdevice-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-powerdevice-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we extend recent work on COSS losses, which have a significant impact on high- and very-high-frequency resonant converters, from GaN HEMTs to the remainder of the core active power devices used in medium- and highvoltage power conversion. Here, we characterize COSS losses in Silicon MOSFETs - including superjunctions and traditional constructions - and Silicon Carbide MOSFETs. The measured COSS losses in SiC MOSFETs do not increase with dV/dt at frequencies from 1-35 MHz and applied voltages up to 900 V. Across the tested SiC MOSFETs, 3-10% of the energy stored in the output capacitor is dissipated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coss losses in silicon superjunction MOSFETs across constructions and generations</title>
      <link>/publication/ispsd-coss-superjunction_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ispsd-coss-superjunction_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>The superjunction (SJ) structure breaks the unipolar material limit of silicon power MOSFETs, and has achieved widespread adoption in commercial power converters. In resonant applications, these SJ devices experience losses due to charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, Coss, resulting in losses that increase with switching frequency. We document C OSS losses in commercially-available 600 V superjunction devices, showing that even devices grown with the trench-filling epitaxial method have non-negligible losses in MHz converters. Further, progressing in generations within a manufacturer appears to correspond to higher C OSS losses as the cell pitch is reduced and doping is increased. The C OSS losses may exceed conduction losses in many applications for the devices tested here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output capacitance losses in 600 V GaN power semiconductors with large voltage swings at high- and very-high-frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we construct three Class-Φ 2 resonant converters with GaN HEMT power devices, 1 kW output power, and switching frequencies of 10 MHz, 30 MHz, and 54.24 MHz. The GaN HEMTs in these converters exhibit losses, approximated thermally, that are significantly higher (up to an order of magnitude) than those predicted by simulation. To investigate, we use a Sawyer-Tower circuit to evaluate the losses in the output capacitance, C OSS , of GaN devices from each manufacturer with commercially-available power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of GaN transistor losses at MHz frequencies in soft switching converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>On paper, Gallium nitride (GaN) transistor promises exceptional performance when used in converters operating at high switching frequency; nonetheless, reduction in their performance when used in real circuits have been observed. Previous experiments show that tested GaN transistors can display excessive loss of up to three times their predicted values under certain test conditions. This paper evaluates power losses in GaN transistors when used in class Φ 2 resonant soft-switching inverter topologies at MHz frequencies. Thermometric loss calibration technique is used to calculate the power losses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
