<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wei Liang on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/wei-liang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wei Liang on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wei-liang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wei Liang, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/weiliang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/weiliang/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
