<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wei Liang on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/wei-liang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wei Liang on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wei-liang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wei Liang, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/weiliang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/weiliang/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive components for electronic circuits using conformal deposition on a scaffold</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us11031179/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us11031179/</guid>
      <description>Precision fabrication of 3D objects is used for fabricating passive electrical components. A 3D scaffold is fabricated and then electrically conductive and/or insulating layers are deposited on the scaffold to form the electrical component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bipolar DC-DC converter topology using passive voltage reversal</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us10998823/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us10998823/</guid>
      <description>A resonant DC-DC converter for generating high voltage MHz bi-polar DC pulses includes a left multi-level resonant rectifier bank [100] connected to a positive electrode [104] and coupled via capacitive isolation to a left RF amplifier terminal [128]; a right multi-level resonant rectifier bank [102] connected to a negative electrode [106] and coupled via capacitive isolation to a right RF amplifier terminal [130]. Each multi-level resonant rectifier bank comprises multiple resonant rectifier stages [112-122], where each stage comprises two capacitors for capacitively isolating the stage, an output capacitor, a MOSFET switch connected to an adjacent MOSFET switch of an adjacent stage, and a gating resonant circuit connected to the MOSFET switch, whereby MOSFET switches in the banks can be passively controlled by RF signals from a left RF amplifier and a right RF amplifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated multi-level resonant topologies for wide-range power conversion and impedance matching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</guid>
      <description>Resonant power converters that replace the conventional impedance matching stage with series or parallel connections between resonant inverters and resonant rectifiers are provided. Two or more resonant rectifiers can be connected in series or in parallel to the resonant inverter to provide impedance matching. Similarly, two or more resonant inverters can be connected in series or in parallel to the resonant rectifier to provide impedance matching. Electrical isolation of DC voltage between input and output is provided using only capacitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated RF Power Delivery and Plasma Micro-Thruster System for Nano-Satellites</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</guid>
      <description>Progress in satellite technologies is ongoing and eventually finds applications back on Earth. Electric propulsion systems have been proven effective on large scale satellites (NASA DAWN) with better propellant efficiency than chemical or cold gas propulsion, and if miniaturized can be promising for long term operation of nano-satellites (e.g., CubeSats) in low Earth orbit or in deep space (NASA MarCO). Here we present a compact and efficient switched mode dc-RF power inverter integrated with an electro-thermal plasma micro-thruster for nano-satellite (e.g., Cubesats) propulsion. The integrated system can serve as side panels and structural support of CubeSats, saving precious on-board volume for propellant and/or payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSS Losses in 600 V GaN Power Semiconductors in Soft-Switched, High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We report losses from charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, COSS , in Gallium Nitride (GaN) power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS. These losses are of particular importance in soft-switched circuits used at MHz switching frequencies, where the output capacitance of the device is charged and discharged once per switching cycle during the device off-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide-Input-Range High-Efficiency Step-Down Power Factor Correction Converter Using a Variable Frequency Multiplier Technique,</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a step-down power factor preregulator design that achieves a high efficiency across the entire universal input voltage range (85-265 V rms ) for an offline power supply application. The proposed circuit allows MOSFETs with lower voltage ratings and better conduction/switching characteristics to be used in both converter stages. A scaling law of power losses versus breakdown voltage requirement for boost circuit under the condition of the same output power is presented. Experimental results demonstrated a flatter high efficiency performance across a wide input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output capacitance losses in 600 V GaN power semiconductors with large voltage swings at high- and very-high-frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we construct three Class-Φ 2 resonant converters with GaN HEMT power devices, 1 kW output power, and switching frequencies of 10 MHz, 30 MHz, and 54.24 MHz. The GaN HEMTs in these converters exhibit losses, approximated thermally, that are significantly higher (up to an order of magnitude) than those predicted by simulation. To investigate, we use a Sawyer-Tower circuit to evaluate the losses in the output capacitance, C OSS , of GaN devices from each manufacturer with commercially-available power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of very-high-frequency synchronous resonant DC-DC converter for variable load operation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a simple solution to implement synchronous rectification for resonant dc-dc power converters operating in the Very-High-Frequency (VHF) range, by using a symmetric bandpass matching network between the inverter and rectifier. A bandpass matching network maintains a close-to-zero phase shift between the inverter and rectifier voltage, enabling the synchronous switch to be driven by the same clock signal as the inverter switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact RF power inverter with reduced EMI for a CubeSat electrothermal micro-thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>TThis paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with a PCB multi-resonant input filter for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are part of an investigation seeking to add micro propulsion systems to low cost CubeSats. The proposed RF power inverter and multi-resonant input filter use only air core inductors. All inductors are toroidal and formed by PCB traces and vias allowing a planar and compact design. The PCB structure serves as structural support to save space and volume for propulsion propellant and other payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-resonant gate driver for Very-High-Frequency (VHF) resonant converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a Very-High-Frequency (VHF) multi-resonant gate drive circuit. The design procedure is greatly simplified compared with some VHF self-oscillating multi-resonant gate drivers presented in previous works. The proposed circuit has the potential to reduce long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and to better utilize fast transient capability of VHF converters. A prototype resonant gate driver is demonstrated and able to reduce 60 % of the gate driving loss of a 20 MHz 32 W Class-E power amplifier with Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A unified model for high-power, air-core toroidal PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-aircore_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-aircore_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We present the first unified electrical model for high-power, air-core toroidal inductors implemented as PCB traces, which includes closed-form calculations for the lumped capacitance, resistance, and inductance of the structure. In this regime, the self-resonant frequency (SRF) of the inductor may be of the same order of magnitude as the circuit operating frequency, so the capacitance must be carefully modeled and tightly controlled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structurally supportive RF power inverter for a CubeSat electrothermal plasma micro-thruster with PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with air core inductors for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are low volume and are part of an investigation seeking to add propulsion to low cost CubeSats. The air core inductors used in the proposed RF power inverter are formed with PCB traces allowing for a planar and compact design. Advantages of air core inductors include not being subject to saturation or variations from changing material properties of a magnetic core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal line input power factor preregulator using VFX technique</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a power factor preregulator design in which the energy buffer capacitor is placed at the output of the converter. In this implementation, a resonant LLC converter supplies power to a boost converter operating in continuous conduction mode. Here, a variable frequency (VFX) technique is used in the resonant LLC converter stage to achieve a lower variation in the overall efficiency across the universal input voltage range (85 - 265V rms ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Mass RF Power Inverter for CubeSat Applications Using 3-D Printed Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low-mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g., tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as CubeSat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3-D printing of lightweight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2-MHz 50-W resonant dc-RF power inverter implemented with 3-D printed and copper plated air core toroidal inductors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Testing of a Miniaturized Switch Mode Amplifier Powering an Electrothermal Plasma Micro-Thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</guid>
      <description>A structurally supportive miniaturized low-weight (≤150 g) radiofrequency switch mode amplifier developed to power the small diameter Pocket Rocket electrothermal plasma micro-thruster called MiniPR is tested in vacuum conditions representative of space to demonstrate its suitability for use on nano-satellites such as “CubeSats.” The switch mode amplifier design is finely tuned to the input impedance of the thruster (~16 pF) to provide a power efficiency of 88% at the resonant frequency and a direct feed to a low-loss (~10 %) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low mass RF power inverter for cubesat plasma thruster using 3D printed inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-thurster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-thurster_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g. tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as cubesat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3D printing of light-weight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2 MHz 50 W resonant DC-RF power inverter implemented with 3D printed and plated air core toroidal inductors. The inverter achieves 90% electrical efficiency when operated on a 50 Ω resistive load at an input voltage of 50 V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonant bi-polar DC pulse power supply for electroporation applications</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-electroporation_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-electroporation_raymond/</guid>
      <description>Electroporation is a technique that uses high pulsed electric fields to create pores in biological cell walls for medical, liquid sterilization and other applications. Many systems use mono-polar pulses for simplicity but electro-migration can limit electrode life. The following paper demonstrates a resonant circuit design for creating high voltage bi-polar dc pulses using a simple control strategy. The circuit topology consists of two Radio Frequency (RF) amplifiers each coupled to a multi-level resonant rectifier employing capacitive isolation and operating at 15 MHz. The RF signals generated by the amplifiers themselves are used to control the pulse duration and output polarity. Any sequence of positive and negative pulse trains can be generated between several μs through dc. This paper presents a proof of concept design providing 800 V positive and negative pulses into a resistive load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz isolated high voltage gain multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a high efficiency, high power density, and fast transient response dc-dc converter design capable of providing a high-voltage isolated output from a low-voltage input. Specifically, we demonstrate two 100 W, 2000 Vdc proof of concept prototype dc-dc converters operating at a switching frequency of 27.12 MHz with input voltages of 40 V and 100 V respectively. Capacitive isolation provides an efficient means of allowing for multiple rectified outputs to be combined serially without exceeding semi-conductor device limits. Further, it can provide a more efficient means of impedance matching at frequencies of 10s of MHz than traditional methods such as passive matching networks or transformers by the reduction of or elimination of those stages altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN resonant power converter with PCB embedded resonant air core inductors and capacitors</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a 27.12 MHz, 320 W, 170 V to 28 V dc-dc resonant power converter with resonant inductors and capacitors embedded into the Printed Circuit Board (PCB). Operating at 27.12 MHz allows for small value and size resonant passive components to be implemented using traces on or within a PCB. A prototype dc-dc converter was built to verify the concept and it reaches an efficiency of 73.6%. A simulated loss analysis is also presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network. Multiple stages are stacked in a way that allows for higher output voltages without suffering efficiency penalties common to traditional serial type high-voltage converter topologies such as the Crockroft-Walton Multiplier. Application of this design results in an isolated resonant dc-dc converter design that promises high efficiency, fast transient response, and high power density while providing a high-voltage isolated output from a lower-voltage input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN Bi-directional resonant power converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>Resonant dc-dc converter regularly use Schottky diodes for high frequency rectification. Si Schottky diodes have relatively low voltage ratings and present reverse-recovery type losses when driven hard enough. SiC Schottky diodes can operate at high frequencies, but incur higher conduction losses. This paper presents a bidirectional dc-dc resonant converter having two ground referenced switches. The prototype converter delivers 400 W between a source of 170 V and a load of 50 V while delivering 250 W in the opposite direction. The converter presented herein can potentially be used in applications such as wireless power transfer, fuel cell and battery applications, bus converters, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz High Density DC–DC Converter With PCB Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-13m56-dcdc-pcb-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-13m56-dcdc-pcb-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high density 150-200 V to 28 V, 200-400 W resonant dc-dc converter with embedded inductors. The converter has a switching frequency of 13.56 MHz and uses air-core toroidal inductors fabricated with printed circuit board (PCB) technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D-Printed Air-Core Inductors for High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling, and characterization of 3-D-printed air-core inductors for high-frequency power electronics circuits. The use of 3-D modeling techniques to make passive components extends the design flexibility and addresses some of the fabrication limitations of traditional processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air-core inductors realized using 3-D printing and casting/plating techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to design. Toward this goal, we present a 70-W prototype 27.12-MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3-D-printed components developed for this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A High-Frequency Resonant Converter Based on the Class Phi2 Inverter for Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/vtc-phi2-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/vtc-phi2-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of high frequency resonant converter based on the Class Φ 2 inverter for inductive power transfer. MHz frequency operation can allow for higher power density than conventional switching frequencies. The converter is based on the Class Φ 2 inverter, reducing the voltage stress across the switch compared to other resonant topologies. A prototype of converter and a few cm airgap inductive coupling system with resistive load was implemented. We will demonstrate a greater than hundred Watt push-pull resonant converter for inductive power transfer at 13.56MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D printed air core inductors for high frequency power converters</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-3d-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-3d-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling and characterization of 3D printed air core inductors for high frequency power electronics circuits. The use of additive manufacturing techniques in passive components design extends the design flexibility and offers ways to overcome some of the fabrication limitations of today&amp;rsquo;s planar processes. Recent work [1]-[4] has demonstrated the feasibility of incorporating air core inductors in high frequency (&amp;gt;10 MHz) switching power converters. These implementations have used discrete wire wound solenoids and toroids, and planar components that use Printed Circuit Board (PCB) traces or photolithographic techniques to make air core inductors. However, realizations of such components have limitations in performance and applicability: wire wound and PCB devices leave open paths conducive to the flow of leakage fields, and photolithography yields devices with geometric constraints and limited cross section aspect ratios. We propose the use of 3D printing and molding techniques to add flexibility and functionality in the design as they allow the manufacturing of components with rounded edges and overhanging structures impossible for planar processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air core inductors designed using 3D printing and molding techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to realize. Moreover, we show that some of these designs can lead to improved electrical performance. The paper also describes the tools used by the authors to design, fabricate and characterize the electromagnetic performance of the air core inductors. As progress in additive manufacturing continues, we envision a fully 3D printed power converter that obviates the need of printed circuits board. Toward this goal, we present a 70 W prototype 27.12 MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3D printed components developed for this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance evaluation of diodes in 27.12 MHz Class-D resonant rectifiers under high voltage and high slew rate conditions</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-coss-diodes_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-coss-diodes_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper provides a performance review of select diodes for use in high frequency resonant rectifiers at modest power levels. Specifically, we evaluate the performance of several leading edge diodes for use in a 27.12 MHz Class-D type rectifier for output voltages from 170 V to 1000 V dc, and corresponding power levels between 8.5 W and 100 W. The authors suspect these losses are due in part to the high equation experienced by the Silicon Carbide (SiC) Schottky diodes used in that design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz large voltage gain resonant converter with low voltage stress</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-large-gain-dcdc_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-large-gain-dcdc_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high frequency switching power converter with a large voltage gain and air core inductors. Specifically, we demonstrate a 40 W, 30 V to 300 V dc-dc converter switching at 27.12 MHz.We evaluate and compare two rectifier topologies with lower voltage stress than the class E rectifiers described in [2], to get large voltage ratios. Unique to this design is the ability to provide short bursts of high voltage while promising excellent performance and high power density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz high density dc-dc converter with PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high density 150 V-200 V to 28 V, 200 W-400 W resonant dc-dc converter with embedded inductors. The converter has a switching frequency of 13.56 MHz and uses air-core toroidal inductors fabricated with printed circuit board (PCB) technology. Moreover, the paper discusses the trade-offs between simplicity and performance of implementing a hard-switched gate drive at MHz switching frequencies. We describe the advantages of resonant power converter topologies in applications requiring high density and high performance in demanding environmental conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
