<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SiC on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/sic/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SiC on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/sic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC: A Wide-Bandgap Heterogenous Power Device for High-Frequency Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>operating at higher frequencies requires faster switching devices in packages with low parasitics. Wide-bandgap (WBG) power devices, such as gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) devices, have high-critical fields and high-thermal conductivity that make them good candidates for efficient high-voltage and high-frequency operations. Commercially available GaN and SiC devices have ratings targeting different applications. Lateral GaN devices dominate in lower voltage(&amp;lt;; 650V) and high-frequency applications as they have relatively small device capacitances (C oss , C iss ), which make them easy to drive at high frequencies. This paper presents a cascoded GaN/SiC device that overcome many of these limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loss Gate Driving Techniques of the Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device at High Frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</guid>
      <description>Cascoding a GaN HEMT and a SiC JFET best utilizes the advantages of both of these WBG power devices. Like GaN devices, the cascode GaN/SiC device is easy to drive at high frequencies and has low gate loss; like SiC devices, it also has relatively high voltage rating and low Coss energy loss at high frequencies. In this paper, we present our investigation of the gate loss mechanism of the SiC JFET in the cascode structure and our finding that the loss can be greatly reduced by minimizing the gate resistance of the SiC JFET (R g,Jfet ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device for MHz Switching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present a WBG high-voltage GaN/SiC cascode device, combining the advantages of both a GaN and a SiC device: simple gate drive requirements, E oss loss per cycle roughly independent of frequency, and relatively high voltage blocking capability. This cascode device is capable of blocking 1.2 kV, while consuming 558 mW at the gate when operating at 13.56 MHz. A 700 W Class E inverter implemented with the proposed cascoded device achieves 91 % efficiency at 13.56 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In recent reports, a variety of power devices, including wide-bandgap transistors, SiC diodes, and Si superjuction MOSFETs, exhibit losses occurring from hysteretic charging and discharging of their output capacitance (COSS for MOSFETs and CJ for Schottky diodes). Manufacturer SPICE models and datasheets do not report these losses, and are why device power dissipation in simulation significantly contrasts with that in actual converters. However, we propose a viable empirical circuit model that incorporates these losses, with capabilities to integrate into circuit simulation tools such as SPICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
