<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Weston Braun on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/weston-braun/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Weston Braun on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/weston-braun/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Weston Braun</title>
      <link>/labpeople/weston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/weston/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Resonators for Piezoelectric Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</guid>
      <description>The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inductorless Soft Switching DC-DC Converter with an Optimized Piezoelectric Resonator</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</guid>
      <description>The inductor presents one of the biggest obstacles in miniaturizing power electronics. In this paper we present a piezoelectric resonator for power conversion fabricated out of lithium niobate, a material that has several advantages for high frequency power conversion compared to the more commonly used PZT ceramics. The piezoelectric resonator is used in a step-down dc-dc converter that achieves zero voltage soft switching and a continuously variable conversion ratio without the use of magnetic components. The converter operates at 6.3MHz and has a maximum power output of 30W at an efficiency of 92.7%, achieving a power density of 16.7 W/cm 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Fabrication of Three-Dimensional Printed Air-Core Transformers for High-Frequency Power Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</guid>
      <description>This article presents various designs of toroidal air-core transformers utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D Printed Air-Core Toroidal Transformer for High-Frequency Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a nested toroidal air-core transformer utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology. The first part of this work discusses design equations to achieve the target inductance matrix. Lastly, this work provides experimental demonstrations of the transformer design including a 40.68 MHz 48-to-350 V resonant dc-dc converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI Compatible DC Modulator for an Envelope Tracking Transmitter,</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</guid>
      <description>Typical MRI power amplifiers are characterized by the requirement for high linearity and a high peak-to-average power ratio. Here we present a MRI compatible DC modulator for envelope tracking applications based on a 4-phase interleaved buck converter using air core magnetics and utilizing a FPGA based digital controller. The modulator is capable of delivering 500 W into a 2.5 Ω load at an efficiency of 95.6%, has a 3 dB modulation bandwidth of 50 kHz, and has been tested with a Class-AB linear amplifier operating at 64 MHz to produce a modulated RF envelope with a peak power of 320 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High density power converters with Piezo-electric resonators</title>
      <link>/project/tisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Photograph of prototype piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter.  The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters. In this paper we analyze the impact of resonator parameters on the performance of the piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter, derive the optimal load impedance and efficiency limits, and analyze the impacts of varying conversion ratio and load impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
