<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Power Semiconductor Devices on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/power-semiconductor-devices/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Power Semiconductor Devices on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/power-semiconductor-devices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Output Capacitance Loss Characterization of Silicon Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>In high-frequency (HF) and very-high-frequency (VHF) rectifiers, silicon carbide (SiC) Schottky diodes exhibit higher losses compared to what is reported in manufacturer-provided simulation models, with additional power loss stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the junction output capacitance (CJ). Here, we compare measured losses across manufacturers, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging of variouis SiC Schottkey diodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSS Losses in 600 V GaN Power Semiconductors in Soft-Switched, High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We report losses from charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, COSS , in Gallium Nitride (GaN) power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS. These losses are of particular importance in soft-switched circuits used at MHz switching frequencies, where the output capacitance of the device is charged and discharged once per switching cycle during the device off-time.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
