<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prof. Juan M. Rivas Davila on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prof. Juan M. Rivas Davila on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Chaffee</title>
      <link>/labpeople/doug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/doug/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Pranglin, M.S.</title>
      <link>/alumni/maxpraglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/maxpraglin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calvin Lin</title>
      <link>/labpeople/calvinlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/calvinlin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clarissa Daniel</title>
      <link>/labpeople/clarissadaniel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/clarissadaniel/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Hernandez, M.S.</title>
      <link>/alumni/emilyhernandez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/emilyhernandez/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaolin Wu</title>
      <link>/labpeople/xiaolinwu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/xiaolinwu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhechi Ye</title>
      <link>/labpeople/zhechiye/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/zhechiye/</guid>
      <description>yezc15@stanford.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Stolt</title>
      <link>/labpeople/ericstolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/ericstolt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wei Liang, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/weiliang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/weiliang/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luke Raymond, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/lukeraymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/lukeraymond/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weston Braun</title>
      <link>/labpeople/weston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/weston/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jungwon Choi, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/jungwonchoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/jungwonchoi/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   High-frequency, high-power resonant converter with wide bandgap devices for wireless power transfer systems      Presented in 2018 Manuscript availabe here.  Summary     As demand for electric vehicles (EVs) grows, wireless power transfer (WPT) technology becomes beneficial by removing the need for manual intervention to charge EV batteries. These high-power applications require power electronics systems that not only efficiently deliver sufficient power, but are also small enough to be embedded in the EV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zikang Tong</title>
      <link>/labpeople/zikangtong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/zikangtong/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jia Zhuang</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jiazhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jiazhuang/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lei Gu, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/leigu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/leigu/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   Design considerations for radio frequency power converters      Presented in 2019 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Compact and efficient high-frequency power converters and amplifiers are needed in a variety of applications, including base stations, mobile devices, and medical equipment. The ever-growing need for a smaller size, longer battery life, and lower cost introduces challenging design considerations for radio-frequency power converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grayson Zulauf, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/graysonzulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/graysonzulauf/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   Wide-bandgap semiconductors for next-generation power electronics systems      Presented on May 19, 2020 Availabe for download here.  Summary     Wide-bandgap power semiconductors promise to reshape the power electronics landscape, opening completely new use cases and increasing efficiency and power density in existing ones. Most notably, gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) were successfully commercialized in the past decades, with theoretical benefits over silicon of multiple orders-of-magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JiaLe Xu</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jialexu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jialexu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jason Poon</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jasonpoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jasonpoon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanghyeon Park, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/sanghyeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/sanghyeon/</guid>
      <description> Doctoral Dissertation   Circuit techniques for compact and lightweight high-voltage dc power supplies      Presented on April 13, 2021  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kawin Surakitbovorn</title>
      <link>/labpeople/kawin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/kawin/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   On the design and optimization of RF power amplifiers using wide bandgap devices      Presented March 2021 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Compact radio-frequency (RF) power amplifiers are essential building blocks in various applications, including radio transmission, medical imaging, wireless power transfer, industrial plasma generation, and micro-satellite propulsion. Over the past decades, new wide bandgap (WBG) semiconductor devices, particularly gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), were successfully commercialized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed-Frequency Control of Piezoelectric Resonator DC-DC Converters for Spurious Mode Avoidance</title>
      <link>/publication/fixed-frequency-piezo-spurious-avoidance_stolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fixed-frequency-piezo-spurious-avoidance_stolt/</guid>
      <description>Piezoelectric resonators have shown promise as efficient, power-dense energy storage element alternatives to continue the miniaturization of DC-DC converters. However, practical piezoelectric resonators diverge from their ideal behavior due to spurious modes that cause high loss regions throughout their operating frequency range. This paper presents a fixed-frequency control mode utilizing the high-quality factor of piezoelectric resonators to avoid spurious modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Selective Harmonic Minimization using a Hybrid Analog/Digital Computing Method</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-harmonic-analog-digital-computing_poon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-harmonic-analog-digital-computing_poon/</guid>
      <description>We present a hybrid analog/digital computing circuit to solve a selective harmonic minimization problem. The approach leverages favorable attributes of digital and analog controllers to yield a fast and scalable optimization solver. We present a specific realization of the computing circuit that solves for eight independent switching angles for a quarter-wave symmetric PWM driven two-level single-phase inverter. Seven undesired harmonics are minimized while retaining control over modulation index. The proposed computing circuit is verified with simulations and a PCB hardware implementation. The experimental results demonstrate that the proposed circuit can converge to the optimal solution in less than 5 ms, which is substantially faster than existing methods and facilitates real-time implementation. Moreover, the steady-state power consumption of the PCB implementation is approximately 750 mW, which is also significantly lower than published methods for comparable applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Recovery Testing of Small-Signal Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-reverse_recovery_diodes-braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-reverse_recovery_diodes-braun/</guid>
      <description>Ideally, Schottky diodes have little to no reverse recovery charge due to the lack of a PN junction or associated minority carriers. However, commercial Schottky diodes incorporate a PN junction guard ring under the electrode edge. At high currents, conduction through the guard ring structure can occur, injecting minority carriers and increasing reverse recovery charge. This behavior can lead to adverse circuit effects and increased loss, especially in high frequency dc-dc converters. Moreover, this effect is little-discussed in technical literature, not captured in datasheet provided values, and not typically incorporated into manufacture provided simulation models. This paper provides an open source and low-cost diode recovery test circuit and uses it to evaluate a selection of small-signal Schottky diodes and rectifiers. In several of the diodes, we find a significant increase in the recovery charge at high currents, characteristic of the PN junction guard ring’s conduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed-signal computing for online optimization of power electronics systems</title>
      <link>/project/mixedsignalcomputing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mixedsignalcomputing/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: PCB prototype  Mixed-signal computing for online optimization of power electronics systems Online optimization and optimal control techniques can substantially improve the efficiency, performance, and reliability of many power electronics systems. Some examples include model predictive direct torque control for motor drives, maximum power point tracking for renewable energy applications, and the optimal power flow problem for electric grids. Moreover, there are emerging trends towards increasingly advanced optimization techniques based on machine learning and artificial intelligence that can provide further benefit to many applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circuitry and methodology benefiting from reduced gate loss</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us11101792b2_sic-gan-cascode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us11101792b2_sic-gan-cascode/</guid>
      <description>In specific examples, aspects are directed towards eliminating, mitigating or reducing gate loss in circuits including, for example, WBG power devices. One such example is directed towards an apparatus including first and second types of field-effect transistor (FET), where the first type is characterized as being a normally-on FET in a switching-circuit operation with a high-voltage rating, and the second type of FET is characterized as being a normally-off FET in a switching-circuit operation with a voltage rating that is much less than the high-voltage rating of the first type of FET circuit. The FET are arranged in a cascode manner so that, in response to a switching control signal received by the second type of FET circuit, the second type of FET circuit is active to drive the first type of FET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wideband PPT Class Φ2 Inverter using Phase-Switched Impedance Modulation and Reactance Compensation</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-wideband-pp2-phi2-reactance-compensatoin_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-wideband-pp2-phi2-reactance-compensatoin_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper we experimentally demonstrate a 300 W PA for a 50 Ω load impedance using silicon (Si) devices. The PA achieves above 90% efficiency over approximately a 30% fractional bandwidth. In addition, the PA can also operate across broadband with light loads, where above 80% efficiency is maintained for up to 5 times higher load resistances. This switch-mode PA is one of the first to demonstrate such performance under load variation across a wide bandwidth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1.7 kW 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Air-Core Coils at 95.7% DC-DC Efficiency</title>
      <link>/publication/wptc-1k7w-wpt_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wptc-1k7w-wpt_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper describes the design and implementation of a 1.7 kW wireless power transfer system that operates at 6.78 MHz and uses low-cost air-core coils. The demonstration achieves a dc-dc efficiency of 95.7% at 1.7 kW and maintains above 93% efficiency between 100 W and 1.7 kW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 15:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder **
** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 IEEE MTTS Student Design Competition</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-zk-mtts-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-zk-mtts-award/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: 13.56 MHz Converter   Figure 2: MTTS award  2021 Student Design Competition on High-efficiency power amplifier for 13.56 MHz The 2021 IEEE International Microwave Symposium (IMS) was held in June 7-10 at Atlanta, Georgia. IMS is one of the largest events for the RF and Microwave Industry attended by hundreds of academic institutions and companies across the world. During this conference, student attendees were able to participate in a Student Design Competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive components for electronic circuits using conformal deposition on a scaffold</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us11031179/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us11031179/</guid>
      <description>Precision fabrication of 3D objects is used for fabricating passive electrical components. A 3D scaffold is fabricated and then electrically conductive and/or insulating layers are deposited on the scaffold to form the electrical component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bipolar DC-DC converter topology using passive voltage reversal</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us10998823/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us10998823/</guid>
      <description>A resonant DC-DC converter for generating high voltage MHz bi-polar DC pulses includes a left multi-level resonant rectifier bank [100] connected to a positive electrode [104] and coupled via capacitive isolation to a left RF amplifier terminal [128]; a right multi-level resonant rectifier bank [102] connected to a negative electrode [106] and coupled via capacitive isolation to a right RF amplifier terminal [130]. Each multi-level resonant rectifier bank comprises multiple resonant rectifier stages [112-122], where each stage comprises two capacitors for capacitively isolating the stage, an output capacitor, a MOSFET switch connected to an adjacent MOSFET switch of an adjacent stage, and a gating resonant circuit connected to the MOSFET switch, whereby MOSFET switches in the banks can be passively controlled by RF signals from a left RF amplifier and a right RF amplifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Resonators for Piezoelectric Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</guid>
      <description>The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of ${C}_{{\mathrm {oss}}}$ and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a high-efficiency RF power amplifier for plasma generation</title>
      <link>/project/daihensystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/daihensystemx/</guid>
      <description>   Figure 1: Photograph of a 40.68MHz PA develped for this project  Summary There are two main objectives centering around making the previously proposed technology viable for generating plasma The first goal is to develop the control technology for multilevel pulsing and arbitrary waveform envelope. The second goal is to improve and expand the mismatch load range of the amplifier.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiC, GaN and Si technology comparison for high power RF plasma generators</title>
      <link>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</guid>
      <description>   Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Summary We are studying the electric properties of SiC and GaN devices to design high power, high frequency RF plasma generators
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The modeling and understanding high frequency losses in SiC and GaN devices</title>
      <link>/project/onsemisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/onsemisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs The origin of Coss and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Fast-Switching DC and Resonant RF Drivers for a Dual-Mode Imaging and HIFU 2D CMUT Array</title>
      <link>/publication/hifu-2d-cmut_stedman/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hifu-2d-cmut_stedman/</guid>
      <description>We developed previously a 2D CMUT array with capability to both do imaging and generate HIFU for ablation of targeted tissues without collateral damage. This new technology allows a more compact HIFU system, when compared to conventional systems composed of HIFU transducers made of PZT, cooling systems for PZT and additional imaging guidance systems. In this paper we present new dc and RF power electronics that drive our 2D CMUT array. The new electronics are significantly more compact and capable of fast-switching between imaging and HIFU mode.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1 kW, Multi-MHz Wireless Charging for Electric Transportation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</guid>
      <description>We design and build a DC-DC wireless power system for electric vehicles charging at 6.78 MHz. With a gap of 34 cm, the air-core system can transfer up to 1 kW with 82% efficiency. It can operate continuously without failure even when the gap varies from 26 to 38 cm, and though the output power changes with distance, the efficiency does not vary appreciably. Due to the high operating frequency, the transfer coils are lightweight, inexpensive, and mechanically robust, even with a gap much larger than in previous literature. The systems low cost and resilience across coupling makes it amenable to mass deployment in commercial systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Self-Resonant Coils</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</guid>
      <description>MHz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer holds the promise of increased power density and high- efficiency wireless power transfer. Unfortunately, due to high- frequency losses in wide-bandgap semiconductors and low-Q high-frequency coil designs, these systems are universally less efficient, on a dc-dc basis, than wireless power systems operating at conventional frequency regimes. This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. Particularly, we present the optimal compensation strategy for parallel compensated coils, which is a topic less frequently discussed in literature than the series compensated coils. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and an optimal design strategy, we demonstrate a 6.78 MHz, 300 W wireless power transfer system that achieves 95 % dc-dc efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A physical investigation of large-signal dynamic output capacitance and energy loss in GaN-on-Si power HEMTs at high-frequency applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-physical-large-signal-dynamic-output-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-physical-large-signal-dynamic-output-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of Coss and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of GaN buffer layers and Si-substrate. These loss components can be potentially improved by re-engineering the doping concentrations in the buffer stacks and substrate layer. This paper presents a physics view of the trapping dynamics that is related to C oss in the GaN HEMT under large-signal excitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Ripple High-Voltage DC Generation Using a Serially Segmented Multiphase Voltage Multiplier</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-lowripple-hv-dc-multiphase_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-lowripple-hv-dc-multiphase_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a voltage multiplier topology that is suitable for a low-ripple high-voltage dc generation. The topology has a number of voltage multipliers connected in series and driven at different phases. Compared to a single-phase multiplier, an n-phase voltage multiplier has an output ripple that is smaller by n times. We demonstrate the ripple reduction of the proposed topology using a 6 V-to-800 V power supply with a 16-stage four-phase bipolar voltage multiplier. The output ripple frequency is eight times the converter&amp;rsquo;s switching frequency and the ripple amplitude is significantly smaller than the conventional single-phase voltage multiplier</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origins of Soft-switching Coss Losses in SiC Power MOSFETs and Diodes for Resonant Converter Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</guid>
      <description>The recent development and commercialization of wide bandgap (WBG) power semiconductors, specifically gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), has driven the increase in switching frequency for soft-switching power converters like the Class E, Class Φ2, and Class DE resonant inverters and rectifiers. However, prior literature has characterized numerous commercial GaN and SiC devices using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and discovered significant large-signal charge-voltage hysteresis of the Coss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Carrier Phase Shifting for Optimal Harmonic Minimization in Asymmetric Parallel-Connected Inverters</title>
      <link>/publication/decentralized-harmonic-minimization-parallel-inverters_poon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/decentralized-harmonic-minimization-parallel-inverters_poon/</guid>
      <description>This article presents a carrier phase shifting technique for minimizing the aggregate harmonics in networks of asymmetric parallel-connected inverters for distributed power generation system applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular ON/OFF and Phase-Shifting for High-Speed Radio Frequency Power Modulation</title>
      <link>/publication/modular-onoff-phaseshift-rfpm_north/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/modular-onoff-phaseshift-rfpm_north/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present an alternative power modulation method to create a high-efficiency high-speed RF amplifier system. This control technique utilizes two mechanisms, modular on/off and phase-shifting. In modular on/off, a different number of sub-circuits are turned “on” or “off” to crudely adjust the output power.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Selecting the Right Power Semiconductor for Multi-MHz Power Converters-Slides</title>
      <link>/talk/20200902_pels_webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/20200902_pels_webinar/</guid>
      <description>Abstract:     With the commercialization of wide-bandgap power semiconductors, multi-MHz switching frequencies are more compelling and critical to meet new applications demanding leaps in power density and efficiency. In the past, studies of these converters reported significant gaps between measured and modeled performance, often attributed to dynamic RDS, ON in GaN HEMTs. In particular, the power semiconductors – which often drive thermal constraints – dissipated much more power than expected, rendering designs based on simulated values unusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and voltage domain load models for appliance-level grid edge simulation and control</title>
      <link>/publication/tandv-load-models-grid_goldin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tandv-load-models-grid_goldin/</guid>
      <description>Developments in simulation and distributed control of distributed energy resources require increasingly granular characterization and modeling of load behavior. Previous work has demonstrated the viability of voltage-based power control of residential appliances to enable load flexibility without service interruption. However, conventional static and dynamic load models fail to capture the coupled voltage and state dynamics relevant for this type of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.78-MHz Wireless Power Transfer With Self-Resonant Coils at 95% DC–DC Efficiency</title>
      <link>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</guid>
      <description>This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and a better understanding of C oss losses in wide-bandgap power semiconductors, we demonstrate 6.78- MHz wireless power transfer systems that achieve 95% dc-dc efficiency at power levels up to and beyond 1 kW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simple Method to Combine the Output Power from Multiple Class-E Power Amplifiers</title>
      <link>/publication/combiner-classe_north/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/combiner-classe_north/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present an alternative approach to designing a high-efficiency high power RF amplifier system. Here, we offer a simple tuning method that allows output powers from multiple power amplifiers to be combined directly without the need for an extra combiner network, given that the mismatches between the amplifiers are sufficiently small.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonstration of GaN Impact Ionization Avalanche Transit-Time (IMPATT) Diode</title>
      <link>/publication/drc-gan-impatt_ji/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/drc-gan-impatt_ji/</guid>
      <description>The following topics are dealt with: III-V semiconductors; wide band gap semiconductors; gallium compounds; random-access storage; field effect transistors; semiconductor growth; aluminium compounds; indium compounds; semiconductor device breakdown; hafnium compounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Gu awarded the IEEE PELS PhD Thesis Talk Award</title>
      <link>/blog/ieeep3talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ieeep3talk/</guid>
      <description>The Selection Committee for the PELS Ph.D.Thesis Talk (P3) consisted of worldwide Distinguished Professors in the Power Electronics community. Each video submission was reviewed by a panel of three judges who have now completed their evaluations, this was a difficult task because of the high quality of nominations. I&amp;rsquo;d like to now congratulate the following winners.
2020 IEEE PELS Ph.D. Thesis Talk Award (P3) Winners:
  Design Considerations for Radio Frequency Power Converters by Lei Gu, Stanford University, USA Synchronised Control of Grid-Interactive Inverters using Stationary Frame Resonant Regulators by Afif Nazib, RMIT University, Australia Mission Profile based System-Level Lifetime Prediction of Modular Multilevel Converters by Yi Zhang, Aalborg University, Denmark Three-Layer Control Strategy for LLC Converters: Large-Signal, Small Signal, and Steady-State Operation by Mehdi Mohammadi, University of British Columbia, Canada Torque Estimation in Permanent Magnet Synchronous Machines by Maria Martinez Gomez, University of Oviedo, Spain  The Award Consists of $1000 + Certificate + up to a maximum of $500 towards travel reimbursement to attend IEEE ECCE 2020 in Detroit to receive the award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Multi-MHz Switching Frequencies on Dynamic On-Resistance in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/impact-mhz-dynamicrdson_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/impact-mhz-dynamicrdson_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>Dynamic on-resistance (dRon), where the on-resistance immediately after turn-on is higher than the DC resistance, increases the conduction losses in power converters with gallium nitride high-electron-mobility transistors (GaN HEMTs). There exist no direct dR on measurements in the literature above 1 MHz, leaving designers unable to predict conduction losses in emerging multi-MHz applications. We address this literature gap by collecting the first on-state voltage dR on measurements at multi-MHz frequencies, with a focus on the zero-voltage-switching conditions that are predominantly employed at high frequency. On the selected commercially-available HEMT with a breakdown voltage below 200 V, the dynamic contribution asymptotes above ≈ 2 MHz, a finding predicted by the slow time constants of the traps that cause dR on</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inductorless Soft Switching DC-DC Converter with an Optimized Piezoelectric Resonator</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</guid>
      <description>The inductor presents one of the biggest obstacles in miniaturizing power electronics. In this paper we present a piezoelectric resonator for power conversion fabricated out of lithium niobate, a material that has several advantages for high frequency power conversion compared to the more commonly used PZT ceramics. The piezoelectric resonator is used in a step-down dc-dc converter that achieves zero voltage soft switching and a continuously variable conversion ratio without the use of magnetic components. The converter operates at 6.3MHz and has a maximum power output of 30W at an efficiency of 92.7%, achieving a power density of 16.7 W/cm 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lightweight High Voltage Generator for Untethered Electroadhesive Perching of Micro Air Vehicles</title>
      <link>/publication/hv-untethered-perching_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hv-untethered-perching_park/</guid>
      <description>In this letter, we motivate the need for application-specific power electronics solutions for electroadhesive perching, develop a useful figure of merit (the “specific voltage”) for comparing and guiding efforts, and walk through the design methodology of a system implementation. We conclude by showing that this high voltage power supply enables, for the first time in the literature, tetherless electroadhesive perching of a commercial micro quadrotor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Design of Multi-MHz Frequency Isolated Auxiliary Power Supply for Gate Drivers in Medium-Voltage Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/mhz-isolated-auxps-gatedrive_spro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mhz-isolated-auxps-gatedrive_spro/</guid>
      <description>This article presents the design and optimization of a suitable topology for an isolated dc–dc auxiliary power supply with high isolation voltage and low coupling capacitance. The converter consists of a GaN HEMT inverter operating at 6.78 MHz, an LCC resonance tank, and a class-E low dv/dt rectifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push–Pull Class Φ2  RF Power Amplifier</title>
      <link>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</guid>
      <description>This work focuses on improving the design and operating characteristics of a push–pull $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier with a $T$ network connected between the switch nodes, or a PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier. The PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier has less circulating energy and achieves higher cutoff frequency &lt;sub&gt;T&lt;/sub&gt; than other $\Phi _\text2$/EF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; circuits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Fabrication of Three-Dimensional Printed Air-Core Transformers for High-Frequency Power Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</guid>
      <description>This article presents various designs of toroidal air-core transformers utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miniature High-Voltage DC-DC Power Converters for Space and Micro-Robotic Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</guid>
      <description>We develop a small and lightweight high-voltage high-gain power converter for applications where weight and size are premium. By driving a Dickson and Cockcroft-Walton voltage multiplier with a megahertz-frequency class-E inverter, we implement two converters, one that achieves 40 V-to-2 kV conversion with 16 cm 3 box volume and the other that achieves 3.7 V-to-2.9 kV conversion with 0.2 cm 3 box volume and 0.49 g weight. Presented converters achieve comparable or better power density and specific power to those of commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC: A Wide-Bandgap Heterogenous Power Device for High-Frequency Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>operating at higher frequencies requires faster switching devices in packages with low parasitics. Wide-bandgap (WBG) power devices, such as gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) devices, have high-critical fields and high-thermal conductivity that make them good candidates for efficient high-voltage and high-frequency operations. Commercially available GaN and SiC devices have ratings targeting different applications. Lateral GaN devices dominate in lower voltage(&amp;lt;; 650V) and high-frequency applications as they have relatively small device capacitances (C oss , C iss ), which make them easy to drive at high frequencies. This paper presents a cascoded GaN/SiC device that overcome many of these limitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitor Variations on Switched-Capacitor and Resonant Switched-Capacitor Converters,</title>
      <link>/publication/class2caps-variation-switchedcap_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/class2caps-variation-switchedcap_xu/</guid>
      <description>Class 2 ceramic capacitors, such as X7R, have relatively high energy density compared to Class 1 ceramic capacitors. However, they experience changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1%-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25 °C to 125 °C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. The measured equivalent series resistance (ESR) of the X7R capacitors shows an increase of 20% to 70% due to aging of 1680 h, and a 50% fluctuation in value when we apply 20% to 80% of the rated voltage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Method to Eliminate Discrete Inductors in a Class-E Inverter Used in Wireless Power Transfer Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/eliminate-discrete-inductors-classe-wpt_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/eliminate-discrete-inductors-classe-wpt_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>we demonstrate a printed circuit board (PCB)-based WPT circuit operating at 40.68 MHz, utilizing no discrete inductors other than the WPT coils themselves and weighing only 7 g. This article describes the design methodology as well as the procedure to eliminate the discrete resonant inductors used in the implementation of our designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimization of a Class-E Power Amplifier With GaN HEMTs at Megahertz Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We examine the constraints that dictate when this optimization equations can and cannot be used, as well as propose a distributed loss model for the C oss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE) to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated. To verify our mathematical analysis and to demonstrate the applications of the proposed GSE-based C oss loss model, two design examples are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This article proposes an HF/very HF (VHF) resonant converter structure in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal. The presented structure enables efficient bidirectional power delivery in the HF/VHF range for applications that require a large voltage conversion ratio. A 64-MHz, 12-W, 36-12-V prototype converter verifies the operation of the structure. This article further explores an interleaved architecture of the same circuit to improve efficiency and transient performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Turn Air-Core Coils for High-Frequency Inductive Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>The efficiency of megahertz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer designs is currently limited by the quality factor of the resonant tanks and the coils. In this article, we use two-dimensional finite-element analysis to optimize the cross section of single-turn air-core inductors for this application and demonstrate coils for wireless power at high-frequency and very-high-frequency industrial, scientific, and medical (ISM) bands. Our resonant tanks achieve diameter-normalized quality factors (Q d ) that are 25%-70% better than the state of the art for air-core coils at 6.78 MHz (Q d = 73 cm -1 ) and 13.56 MHz (102), and we show significant improvements at the 27.12 MHz (123) and 40.68 MHz (137) ISM bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D Printed Air-Core Toroidal Transformer for High-Frequency Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a nested toroidal air-core transformer utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology. The first part of this work discusses design equations to achieve the target inductance matrix. Lastly, this work provides experimental demonstrations of the transformer design including a 40.68 MHz 48-to-350 V resonant dc-dc converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Compact 45 V-to-54 kV Modular DC-DC Converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-40to54kv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-40to54kv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a compact 45 V-to-54 kV dc-dc converter for high-energy beam applications with the focus on X-ray generation. We describe key design choices for a high power density including a modular structure, high-frequency switching, planar transformers and Dickson topology. High-voltage insulation and thermal management are also described in detail. The experimental data with with a 5 kV single module and a 10-module 54 kV converter indicate that the proposed structure can generate high dc voltage while achieving a several times higher power density compared to commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation into the Causes of COSS Losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we investigate the origin of these losses in GaN-on-Si High Electron Mobility Transistors (HEMTs) using TCAD simulation and experimental techniques, and find that COSS losses can be separated into resistive loss and GaN-stack trap related loss. From device simulation, we observe the expected dependence of substrate displacement current on dV/dt, and the importance of resistive loss is further confirmed with an experimental Sawyer-Tower test with an external resistor attached to the substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loss Gate Driving Techniques of the Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device at High Frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</guid>
      <description>Cascoding a GaN HEMT and a SiC JFET best utilizes the advantages of both of these WBG power devices. Like GaN devices, the cascode GaN/SiC device is easy to drive at high frequencies and has low gate loss; like SiC devices, it also has relatively high voltage rating and low Coss energy loss at high frequencies. In this paper, we present our investigation of the gate loss mechanism of the SiC JFET in the cascode structure and our finding that the loss can be greatly reduced by minimizing the gate resistance of the SiC JFET (R g,Jfet ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI Compatible DC Modulator for an Envelope Tracking Transmitter,</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</guid>
      <description>Typical MRI power amplifiers are characterized by the requirement for high linearity and a high peak-to-average power ratio. Here we present a MRI compatible DC modulator for envelope tracking applications based on a 4-phase interleaved buck converter using air core magnetics and utilizing a FPGA based digital controller. The modulator is capable of delivering 500 W into a 2.5 Ω load at an efficiency of 95.6%, has a 3 dB modulation bandwidth of 50 kHz, and has been tested with a Class-AB linear amplifier operating at 64 MHz to produce a modulated RF envelope with a peak power of 320 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase GaN Class-D Resonant Amplifier for High-Intensity Focused Ultrasound</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</guid>
      <description>Focused ultrasound treats tissue deep in the body without damaging surrounding structures. Driven by large-amplitude RF electrical signals, ultrasonic transducers can generate large pressure acoustic wave. Wide-bandgap semiconductors, e.g., Gallium Nitride (GaN), greatly simplify the design and reduce the requisite size and weight of RF amplifiers, and so improves the portability of focused ultrasound device. Here, we demonstrate a compact 8-phase 5 MHz Class-D resonant amplifier for a focused ultrasound cancer therapy application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimal Input Voltage of a Class-E Power Amplifier with GaN HEMTs at MHz Frequency Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We mathematically analyze the operation of a Class-E amplifier when facing with this Coss loss term. We have found that the conventional wisdom of using the highest input voltage to get the best efficiency no longer holds above a certain frequency. Furthermore, to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated, we propose a distributed loss model for the Coss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hybrid Cockcroft–Walton/Dickson Multiplier for High Voltage Generation</title>
      <link>/publication/hybrid_cockroft-walton-dickson-hv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hybrid_cockroft-walton-dickson-hv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a voltage multiplier topology that is a hybrid between a Cockcroft-Walton multiplier and a Dickson charge pump. The Cockcroft-Walton structure exhibits significant output voltage drop under load as the number of multiplier stage increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device for MHz Switching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-cascode-gan-sic_xu/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present a WBG high-voltage GaN/SiC cascode device, combining the advantages of both a GaN and a SiC device: simple gate drive requirements, E oss loss per cycle roughly independent of frequency, and relatively high voltage blocking capability. This cascode device is capable of blocking 1.2 kV, while consuming 558 mW at the gate when operating at 13.56 MHz. A 700 W Class E inverter implemented with the proposed cascoded device achieves 91 % efficiency at 13.56 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In recent reports, a variety of power devices, including wide-bandgap transistors, SiC diodes, and Si superjuction MOSFETs, exhibit losses occurring from hysteretic charging and discharging of their output capacitance (COSS for MOSFETs and CJ for Schottky diodes). Manufacturer SPICE models and datasheets do not report these losses, and are why device power dissipation in simulation significantly contrasts with that in actual converters. However, we propose a viable empirical circuit model that incorporates these losses, with capabilities to integrate into circuit simulation tools such as SPICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output Capacitance Loss Characterization of Silicon Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>In high-frequency (HF) and very-high-frequency (VHF) rectifiers, silicon carbide (SiC) Schottky diodes exhibit higher losses compared to what is reported in manufacturer-provided simulation models, with additional power loss stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the junction output capacitance (CJ). Here, we compare measured losses across manufacturers, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging of variouis SiC Schottkey diodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APEC 2019 Outstanding Presentation Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/19apeczk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/19apeczk/</guid>
      <description>Z. Tong, S. Park and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices,&amp;rdquo; 2019 IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition (APEC), 2019, pp. 998-1003, doi: 10.1109/APEC.2019.8721907.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated multi-level resonant topologies for wide-range power conversion and impedance matching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</guid>
      <description>Resonant power converters that replace the conventional impedance matching stage with series or parallel connections between resonant inverters and resonant rectifiers are provided. Two or more resonant rectifiers can be connected in series or in parallel to the resonant inverter to provide impedance matching. Similarly, two or more resonant inverters can be connected in series or in parallel to the resonant rectifier to provide impedance matching. Electrical isolation of DC voltage between input and output is provided using only capacitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High density power converters with Piezo-electric resonators</title>
      <link>/project/tisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Photograph of prototype piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter.  The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters. In this paper we analyze the impact of resonator parameters on the performance of the piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter, derive the optimal load impedance and efficiency limits, and analyze the impacts of varying conversion ratio and load impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Substrate Bias Effect on E-Mode GaN-on-Si HEMT Coss Losses</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-substrate-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-substrate-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>Here, we use a back-gate bias between the source and Si substrate to investigate the capacitance characteristics of commercially-available GaN HEMTs. The small-signal capacitance is reduced significantly - up to 2 × for a 650 V HEMT and 4× for a 100 V HEMT - indicating that the drain-substrate capacitance is a significant portion of the total output capacitance. Our findings indicate that the buffer-substrate stack is likely an important driver of Coss losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs, and its optimization must be considered to efficiently use GaN HEMTs at high-frequencies. Traditional C oss measurements with the DC bias swept in both directions may give an indication of the relative level of trapping in this stack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a 40.68 MHz power-combining resonant inverter with eGaN FETs for plasma generation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-40m68-gan_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-40m68-gan_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a 40.68 MHz, 1.2 kW power-combining resonant inverter using eGaN FETs for plasma generation. To provide high power at 40.68 MHz switching frequency, a class Φ2 inverter topology with wide band gap (WBG) devices such as eGaN FETs was selected. The proposed inverter topology reduces the power loss in each switching device, which can decrease the size of the heat sink. This study demonstrates that power-combining resonant inverters using eGaN FETs can increase efficiency and power density while operating at 40.68 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to provide a road map for selecting power devices in soft-switched, megahertz (MHz) frequency power converters. Minimizing $C_{OSS}$ losses, which occur when charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor of power semiconductors, is critical to efficient operation. These losses are excluded from manufacturer-provided information, and measurements are either sparse or not reported at all in the existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coss Measurements for Superjunction MOSFETs: Limitations and Opportunities</title>
      <link>/publication/ted-coss-superjunction-zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ted-coss-superjunction-zulauf/</guid>
      <description>Small-signal measurements of output capacitance ( $C_{OSS}$ ) are ubiquitous in power semiconductor datasheets and determine critical features of power converters. For silicon superjunction power MOSFETs (SJs), we report $C_{OSS}$  measurements with two key anomalies: variation with ac perturbation frequency and hysteresis with dc sweep direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a GaN-Based Wireless Power Transfer System at 13.56 MHz to Replace Conventional Wired Connection in a Vehicle</title>
      <link>/publication/ipec-gan-wpt-surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ipec-gan-wpt-surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>Wired connections running through the doors, hatchbacks, and trunks of a vehicle are subjected to extensive mechanical wear from repeated bending caused by the open-and-close motion. By employing wireless power transfer, this failure mode can be completely eliminated. In this paper, a 300 W 48-to-48 V WPT system with above 90% efficiency designed for such application is demonstrated. To achieve a system that is small, light-weight, and highly efficient as desired by the automotive industry, a novel inductor elimination technique is developed. The following paper shows the system design methodology, the inductor elimination technique, and the control scheme used in this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Resonant Converter with Synchronous Rectification for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/ipec-syncrec-variable-load-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ipec-syncrec-variable-load-gu/</guid>
      <description>Applying RF circuit design techniques to dc-dc power conversion has pushed the switching frequency of power converters using discrete components well beyond 10 MHz. This paper proposes a simple solution to implement synchronous rectification for resonant dc-dc power converters operating at above 10 MHz, by using a symmetric bandpass matching network between the inverter and rectifier. The bandpass matching network enables the synchronous switch to be driven by the same clock signal as the inverter switch. Furthermore, this family of high frequency converter is able to maintain zero-voltage-switching operation over a wide load range. A 200 W 13.56 MHz 210 V-to-30 V bidirectional converter with a peak efficiency of 90% is demonstrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated RF Power Delivery and Plasma Micro-Thruster System for Nano-Satellites</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</guid>
      <description>Progress in satellite technologies is ongoing and eventually finds applications back on Earth. Electric propulsion systems have been proven effective on large scale satellites (NASA DAWN) with better propellant efficiency than chemical or cold gas propulsion, and if miniaturized can be promising for long term operation of nano-satellites (e.g., CubeSats) in low Earth orbit or in deep space (NASA MarCO). Here we present a compact and efficient switched mode dc-RF power inverter integrated with an electro-thermal plasma micro-thruster for nano-satellite (e.g., Cubesats) propulsion. The integrated system can serve as side panels and structural support of CubeSats, saving precious on-board volume for propellant and/or payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Off-State Losses in Silicon-Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/coss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/coss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>Among HF/VHF rectifiers, SiC Schottky diodes exhibit larger losses compared to those captured in simulation, with additional off-state losses stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the CJ. Because these losses are not included in manufacturer simulation models nor have they been well-studied for SiC Schottky diodes, we experimentally measured them using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and compared the losses across manufacturer, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging. Furthermore, we analyzed the performances of these devices on a class-DE rectifier and compared their power dissipation from the simulation and experimental measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide Input Range Isolated Stacked Resonant Switched-Capacitor dc-dc Converter for High Conversion Ratios</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an isolated dc-dc converter architecture for high conversion ratios using the stacked resonant switched-capacitor topology. Capacitive isolation is adopted in place of transformer isolation for saving cost and platform size. With phase shift operation, the topology can support a wide input range with a simple regulation scheme while enabling zero-voltage switching. The topology can be adapted to high conversion ratios via addition of stacking levels while keeping the same magnetics. The experimental results demonstrate a 2-Stack example achieving a peak efficiency of 92.8% and a peak power density of 283 W/inch 3 with 92% efficiency. The converter can also maintain within 3% efficiency drop over 25%-100% load range, and 50%-100% input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-powerdevice-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-powerdevice-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we extend recent work on COSS losses, which have a significant impact on high- and very-high-frequency resonant converters, from GaN HEMTs to the remainder of the core active power devices used in medium- and highvoltage power conversion. Here, we characterize COSS losses in Silicon MOSFETs - including superjunctions and traditional constructions - and Silicon Carbide MOSFETs. The measured COSS losses in SiC MOSFETs do not increase with dV/dt at frequencies from 1-35 MHz and applied voltages up to 900 V. Across the tested SiC MOSFETs, 3-10% of the energy stored in the output capacitor is dissipated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a 13.56 MHz dc-to-dc resonant converter using an impedance compression network to mitigate misalignments in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency resonant converter with an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct horizontal alignment variations between coils in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system. In order to mitigate variations in coil impedance, we propose an ICN that simultaneously compresses magnitude and phase changes of coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a GaN-Based, Inductor-less, Wireless Power Transfer System at 40.68 MHz</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>Wireless power transfer systems have attracted tremendous attention over the past decade. The design of most small size, low power, WPT systems; however, utilizes ferrite to shield and redirect the magnetic fields. This add to the weight and bulk of the system. In this paper, a small and extremely lightweight, PCB based, proof-of-concept WPT system is demonstrated. The circuit operates at 40.68 MHz and is capable of 20 W of output power. It utilizes no discrete inductors other than the WPT coils themselves and weights only 7 grams. The following paper shows the design methodology and the inductor elimination technique used to achieve such design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitance Variations on Switched Capacitor and Resonant Switched Capacitor Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the impact of Class 2 ceramic capacitance (such as X7R) variations on switched capacitor (SC) and resonant switched capacitor (ReSC) converters. Capacitance changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field are studied and modeled in LTSpice simulations. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25°C to 125°C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. Converter performance degradation is quantified in simulation and demonstrated by implementing a 1 MHz 25 W 1:4 Dickson ReSC converter. The converter efficiency decreases from 93.1% to 90.7% due to capacitance variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the Reliability of Series-Connected Schottky Diodes for High-Frequency Rectification</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-series-diodes_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-series-diodes_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a method to predict the overvoltage failure rate of diodes connected in series under high-frequency reverse bias. Conventional approaches use balancing capacitors to ensure the reliability of series-connected diodes at high frequency. Instead, we investigate the viability of achieving voltage balance between devices solely by the match between their junction capacitances. Serializing diodes without extra balancing components increases the blocking voltage and decreases the capacitance, allowing high-voltage conversion at high frequencies for applications such as X-ray. We measure statistical properties of junction capacitances to estimate the reverse voltage limit of 2, 3, and 4 diodes in series. The predicted failure rate shows a good agreement with experimental results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a bidirectional resonant converter design in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal at frequencies above 10 MHz. The proposed design enables efficient operation at &amp;gt; 10 MHz for applications which require high conversion-ratio bidirectional power delivery. We demonstrate a 200 W 13.56 MHz 210 V-to-30 V bidirectional converter with a peak efficiency of 90%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas received NSF award to develop high-voltage power supplies for medical, environmental, and aerospace applications.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nsfhv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nsfhv/</guid>
      <description>High-Voltage High-Power-Density Power Electronics for Emerging Medical, Environmental, and Aerospace Applications   High-voltage low-current power-electronic converters that can deliver voltages between 10s to 100s of kV and currents in the 1-100 mA range play a critical role in many medical, environmental, and aerospace applications, established or emerging. In many of those applications, a compact and lightweight high-voltage power supply is desirable if not essential. Unfortunately, conventional technologies are inefficient, heavy, and bulky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an Impedance Compression Network to Compensate for Misalignments in a Wireless Power Transfer System</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-icn-wpt-choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-icn-wpt-choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an impedance compression network (ICN) design in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system to compensate for distance or alignment variations between coils. In order to reduce coil impedance variation, we propose an ICN that compresses variations in coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan Lab &amp; SUPERlab are one of three winners of NASA iTech’s 2018 Energy Cycle</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nasaitech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nasaitech/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Grayson Zulauf (third from left) is an EE PhD candidate. He is a researcher in the SUPERLab, directed by Professor Juan Rivas-Davila. the Fan Lab is directed by professor Jonathan Fan.  Congratulations to professors Jon Fan and Juan Rivas-Davila! Two of their researchers won the 2018 NASA iTech Forum. The event is a collaborative effort between NASA and the U.S. Department (DOE) of Energy’s Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) to find and foster innovative solutions for critical energy challenges on Earth and in space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coss losses in silicon superjunction MOSFETs across constructions and generations</title>
      <link>/publication/ispsd-coss-superjunction_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ispsd-coss-superjunction_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>The superjunction (SJ) structure breaks the unipolar material limit of silicon power MOSFETs, and has achieved widespread adoption in commercial power converters. In resonant applications, these SJ devices experience losses due to charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, Coss, resulting in losses that increase with switching frequency. We document C OSS losses in commercially-available 600 V superjunction devices, showing that even devices grown with the trench-filling epitaxial method have non-negligible losses in MHz converters. Further, progressing in generations within a manufacturer appears to correspond to higher C OSS losses as the cell pitch is reduced and doping is increased. The C OSS losses may exceed conduction losses in many applications for the devices tested here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 COMPEL Best Paper Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018compel_lei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018compel_lei/</guid>
      <description>L. Gu, K. Surakitbovorn, G. Zulauf, S. Chakraborty and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation,&amp;rdquo; 2018 IEEE 19th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics (COMPEL), 2018, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109/COMPEL.2018.8459962.
Summary:     Applying RF circuit design techniques to dc-dc resonant converters has enabled the switching frequency to be pushed well beyond 10 MHz, resulting in higher power densities and faster transient response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Student Paper Award</title>
      <link>/blog/2018ecceasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018ecceasia/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Kawin (North) Surakitbovorn at the award ceremony  K. Surakitbovorn and J. Rivas-Davilla, “Design of a GaN-Based Wireless Power Transfer System at 13.56 MHz to Replace Conventional Wired Connection in a Vehicle,” 2018 International Power Electronics Conference (IPEC-Niigata 2018 -ECCE Asia), 2018, pp. 3848-3854, doi: 10.23919/IPEC.2018.8507473.
Abstract Wired connections running through the doors, hatchbacks, and trunks of a vehicle are subjected to extensive mechanical wear from repeated bending caused by the open-and-close motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60 V-to-35 kV input-parallel output-series DC-DC converter using multi-level class-DE rectifiers</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-35kv-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-35kv-park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a high-voltage dc-dc converter that includes inductively-isolated rectifiers. Previous work on multi-stage class-DE rectifiers only included capacitive dc isolation, limiting the output voltage to twice of the capacitor voltage rating. By adding an air-core transformer before the rectifier for inductive isolation, the maximum output voltage can be twice the breakdown voltage of the insulation between the transformer&amp;rsquo;s primary and secondary windings, thus allowing the implementation of a small, lightweight, and fast transient high-voltage dc-dc converter. We experimentally demonstrate a multi-modular converter design with 60 V input voltage and 35 kV output voltage with 73 % efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duty Cycle and Frequency Modulations in Class-E DC–DC Converters for a Wide Range of Input and Output Voltages</title>
      <link>/publication/duty-cycle-fm-classe-dcdc-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/duty-cycle-fm-classe-dcdc-park/</guid>
      <description>We present an operation scheme for a dc-dc converter consisting of a class-E inverter and a class-E rectifier to always achieve zero-voltage zero-dv/dt switching at a wide range of input and output voltages. Experiments demonstrate the prototype converter maintaining the desired soft-switching condition under 80-200-V input voltage and 5-20-V output voltage variations. In an additional prototype, we implemented a similar design with synchronous rectification that achieves a peak efficiency of 92.3% at an input voltage of 80 V, an output voltage of 12 V, and an output power of 26.9 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSS Losses in 600 V GaN Power Semiconductors in Soft-Switched, High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We report losses from charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, COSS , in Gallium Nitride (GaN) power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS. These losses are of particular importance in soft-switched circuits used at MHz switching frequencies, where the output capacitance of the device is charged and discharged once per switching cycle during the device off-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide-Input-Range High-Efficiency Step-Down Power Factor Correction Converter Using a Variable Frequency Multiplier Technique,</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a step-down power factor preregulator design that achieves a high efficiency across the entire universal input voltage range (85-265 V rms ) for an offline power supply application. The proposed circuit allows MOSFETs with lower voltage ratings and better conduction/switching characteristics to be used in both converter stages. A scaling law of power losses versus breakdown voltage requirement for boost circuit under the condition of the same output power is presented. Experimental results demonstrated a flatter high efficiency performance across a wide input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output capacitance losses in 600 V GaN power semiconductors with large voltage swings at high- and very-high-frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/wipda-coss-gan-zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we construct three Class-Φ 2 resonant converters with GaN HEMT power devices, 1 kW output power, and switching frequencies of 10 MHz, 30 MHz, and 54.24 MHz. The GaN HEMTs in these converters exhibit losses, approximated thermally, that are significantly higher (up to an order of magnitude) than those predicted by simulation. To investigate, we use a Sawyer-Tower circuit to evaluate the losses in the output capacitance, C OSS , of GaN devices from each manufacturer with commercially-available power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of very-high-frequency synchronous resonant DC-DC converter for variable load operation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a simple solution to implement synchronous rectification for resonant dc-dc power converters operating in the Very-High-Frequency (VHF) range, by using a symmetric bandpass matching network between the inverter and rectifier. A bandpass matching network maintains a close-to-zero phase shift between the inverter and rectifier voltage, enabling the synchronous switch to be driven by the same clock signal as the inverter switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact RF power inverter with reduced EMI for a CubeSat electrothermal micro-thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>TThis paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with a PCB multi-resonant input filter for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are part of an investigation seeking to add micro propulsion systems to low cost CubeSats. The proposed RF power inverter and multi-resonant input filter use only air core inductors. All inductors are toroidal and formed by PCB traces and vias allowing a planar and compact design. The PCB structure serves as structural support to save space and volume for propulsion propellant and other payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-resonant gate driver for Very-High-Frequency (VHF) resonant converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a Very-High-Frequency (VHF) multi-resonant gate drive circuit. The design procedure is greatly simplified compared with some VHF self-oscillating multi-resonant gate drivers presented in previous works. The proposed circuit has the potential to reduce long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and to better utilize fast transient capability of VHF converters. A prototype resonant gate driver is demonstrated and able to reduce 60 % of the gate driving loss of a 20 MHz 32 W Class-E power amplifier with Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A portable electrostatic precipitator to reduce respiratory death in rural environments</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-precipitator-talukder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-precipitator-talukder/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design methodology of a miniaturized, portable, and low power electrostatic precipitator (ESP) to reduce indoor air pollution (IAP) from rural cookstoves. Decreasing the concentration of aerosol particles helps reduce the incidence of respiratory tract infections that can lead to disease and even death. We trace existing technologies and standards to combat IAP in cookstoves, design an ESP that allows precipitation at lower voltages via an electrode design that utilizes sub 5 kV voltages, and explore how rapidly pulsed converters decrease the power consumption of the circuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A unified model for high-power, air-core toroidal PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-aircore_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-aircore_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We present the first unified electrical model for high-power, air-core toroidal inductors implemented as PCB traces, which includes closed-form calculations for the lumped capacitance, resistance, and inductance of the structure. In this regime, the self-resonant frequency (SRF) of the inductor may be of the same order of magnitude as the circuit operating frequency, so the capacitance must be carefully modeled and tightly controlled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of GaN transistor losses at MHz frequencies in soft switching converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>On paper, Gallium nitride (GaN) transistor promises exceptional performance when used in converters operating at high switching frequency; nonetheless, reduction in their performance when used in real circuits have been observed. Previous experiments show that tested GaN transistors can display excessive loss of up to three times their predicted values under certain test conditions. This paper evaluates power losses in GaN transistors when used in class Φ 2 resonant soft-switching inverter topologies at MHz frequencies. Thermometric loss calibration technique is used to calculate the power losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an impedance compression network to correct misalignment in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct distance variation or misalignment between coils in wireless power transfer (WPT) systems. Magnetic resonant coupling (MRC) coils provide high efficiency for charging mid-range WPT applications. However, a distance variation or misalignment between coils causes a coil-impedance change and significantly affects performances of WPT systems. In order to mitigate a coil-impedance variation, we propose an ICN simultaneously compressing changes in magnitude and phase of impedance. The ICN consists of a resistance compression network (RCN) and phase compression network (PCN). While the RCN effectively compresses the variation in the magnitude of impedance by using one pair consisting of an inductor and a capacitor, the PCN is designed using a Smith chart to reduce a phase variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated resonant DC-DC converters with a loosely coupled transformer</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-isolated-dcdc_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-isolated-dcdc_park/</guid>
      <description>We present a dc-dc resonant converter structure that has a pair of loosely coupled inductors in place of one filter inductor and two resonant inductors. Not only the number of inductors is reduced by one, but in this arrangment the transformer provides galvanic isolation and requires a sub-unity coupling coefficient which eases the implementation, especially at high switching frequencies. Various topologies, including class-E, DE, and Φ 2 , benefit from this structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Smart Dim Fuse”: A new approach to load control as a distributed energy resource</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-smart-fuse_goldin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-smart-fuse_goldin/</guid>
      <description>Aggregation of behind-the-meter distributed energy resources holds promise to provide valuable services to the grid, enabling greater penetration of intermittent renewable energy sources. We propose the Smart Dim Fuse system as an approach to utilize loads for aggregation services. The Smart Dim Fuse, installed on individual circuits at the breaker panel, enables load power control without service interruption via direct AC to AC voltage modulation, while reporting load measurement, identification, and resource a vailability forecasting to the aggregator. Using data from 131 homes, we evaluate the aggregate resource availability, and demonstrate a proof-of-concept prototype of the power electronics needed for this functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency, High-Power Resonant Inverter With eGaN FET for Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-high-freq-resonant-inverer-gan-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-high-freq-resonant-inverer-gan-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This letter presents a high-power resonant inverter using an enhancement mode gallium nitride (eGaN) device with magnetic resonant coupling (MRC) coils at 13.56 MHz for wireless power transfer (WPT). The power inverter driving the transmitting coils is based on a class Φ2 inverter, a single-switch topology with low switch-voltage stress, and fast transient response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUPER-Lab undergrad intern featured in Stanford EE Spotligh</title>
      <link>/blog/2017sabera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017sabera/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Sabera J. Talukder  How did you become interested in your research area? There are two research avenues that I am extremely interested in: one is neuroengineering and the second is creating systems to help people in third world countries. For as long as I can remember I have been interested in the brain, and experiences like interning for Medtronic’s Deep Brain Stimulation division cemented my desire to pursue neuroengineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Power loss of GaN transistor reverse diodes in a high frequency high voltage resonant rectifier</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-gan-rectifier_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-gan-rectifier_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents power loss measurements of GaN transistor reverse diodes in high frequency high voltage conditions. To evaluate their performance, we use GaN transistor reverse diodes as rectifying devices in a class-DE resonant rectifier and operate the circuit at switching frequencies of 10s of MHz and with output voltages reaching 100s of volts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structurally supportive RF power inverter for a CubeSat electrothermal plasma micro-thruster with PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with air core inductors for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are low volume and are part of an investigation seeking to add propulsion to low cost CubeSats. The air core inductors used in the proposed RF power inverter are formed with PCB traces allowing for a planar and compact design. Advantages of air core inductors include not being subject to saturation or variations from changing material properties of a magnetic core.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal line input power factor preregulator using VFX technique</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a power factor preregulator design in which the energy buffer capacitor is placed at the output of the converter. In this implementation, a resonant LLC converter supplies power to a boost converter operating in continuous conduction mode. Here, a variable frequency (VFX) technique is used in the resonant LLC converter stage to achieve a lower variation in the overall efficiency across the universal input voltage range (85 - 265V rms ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a Class-DE Rectifier with Shunt Inductance and Nonlinear Capacitance for High-Voltage Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-de-rectifier-hv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-de-rectifier-hv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a design method for a resonant class-DE rectifier with a shunt inductance input network. In this paper, we propose a design procedure that begins with universal design curves that are applicable regardless of the capacitance nonlinearity. This is followed by parameter selection and a convergence check to ensure the rectifier operates at the desired output voltage. Based on the outlined procedure, we design and experimentally verify a 27-MHz 350-V current-driven rectifier, a 25-MHz 500-V voltage-driven rectifier, and a 27.12-MHz 2-kV four-stage rectifier, all of which the resonant capacitor is nonlinear and the input impedance is resistive at the switching frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Mass RF Power Inverter for CubeSat Applications Using 3-D Printed Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-lowmass-rp-inverter-cubesat-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low-mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g., tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as CubeSat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3-D printing of lightweight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2-MHz 50-W resonant dc-RF power inverter implemented with 3-D printed and copper plated air core toroidal inductors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Testing of a Miniaturized Switch Mode Amplifier Powering an Electrothermal Plasma Micro-Thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-vacuum-testin-smpa-electrothermal-thruster_charles/</guid>
      <description>A structurally supportive miniaturized low-weight (≤150 g) radiofrequency switch mode amplifier developed to power the small diameter Pocket Rocket electrothermal plasma micro-thruster called MiniPR is tested in vacuum conditions representative of space to demonstrate its suitability for use on nano-satellites such as “CubeSats.” The switch mode amplifier design is finely tuned to the input impedance of the thruster (~16 pF) to provide a power efficiency of 88% at the resonant frequency and a direct feed to a low-loss (~10 %) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of SiC and eGaN devices in a 6.78 MHz 2.2 kW resonant inverter for wireless power transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-sic-gan-comparison_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-sic-gan-comparison_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a performance comparison of two wide band gap (WBG) devices, a silicon carbide (SiC) MOSFET and an enhancement mode gallium nitride (eGaN) FET in a resonant inverter operating at 6.78 MHz for wireless power transfer (WPT) applications. While SiC MOSFETs provide high breakdown voltage and good thermal characteristics, eGaN FETs can reduce gate losses due to small gate resistance and input capacitance. In this work, we compare a 1200 V SiC MOSFET in a single-ended class Φ 2 inverter to two 650 V eGaN FETs in a push-pull class Φ 2 inverter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inductance cancellation in RF resonant power converters</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-inductance-cancellation_praglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-inductance-cancellation_praglin/</guid>
      <description>Parasitic inductance cancellation is employed in order to operate a resonant power inverter at 27.12 MHz using a TO-220 through-hole package.The elimination of parasitic inductances allows for system cost reduction, increased power handling, and/or relaxation of PCB layout constraints. The inductance cancellation technique is demonstrated through two prototypes (based upon the same silicon MOSFET die) providing 60 W of RF power to a 50 Ω load from a 48 V DC input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A design methodology for class-D resonant rectifier with parallel LC tank</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classd-rectifier_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classd-rectifier_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a design methodology for the tuning of a class-D half-wave resonant rectifier with a parallel LC resonant tank input network. We propose a systematic design procedure that begins with universal design curves applicable to any rectifier design of this topology. This is followed by parameter selection and a convergence check that ensures the rectifier operates with the desired output voltage. Experimental results confirm the validity of the design method for both linear and nonlinear resonant capacitances. Based on the outlined procedure, a 25 MHz 500 V rectifier with resistive input impedance is designed and experimentally verified.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of a 900 V SiC MOSFET in a 13.56 MHz 2 kW resonant inverter for wireless power transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-sic-13m56-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-sic-13m56-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates the performance of a 900 V silicon carbide (SiC) power MOSFET operating at 13.56 MHz in a 2 kW resonant inverter targeted for wireless power transfer (WPT) systems. Operating at multi-MHz switching frequency leads to smaller passive components and has the potential to improve power density and reduce weight for weight-sensitive applications. In this work, we study and evaluate the electrical characteristics of a 900 V, 7L D2PAK SiC MOSFET and demonstrate the design of a 2 kW single-ended resonant inverter operating at 13.56 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low mass RF power inverter for cubesat plasma thruster using 3D printed inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-thurster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-thurster_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a low mass RF power inverter at moderate to high power levels (e.g. tens of watts and above) for weight critical applications such as cubesat plasma thrusters. Our approach for mass reduction includes resonant switching operation at tens of MHz, and the 3D printing of light-weight scaffolds that form air core inductors after plating with a thin layer of copper. Specifically, we present a 14.2 MHz 50 W resonant DC-RF power inverter implemented with 3D printed and plated air core toroidal inductors. The inverter achieves 90% electrical efficiency when operated on a 50 Ω resistive load at an input voltage of 50 V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resonant bi-polar DC pulse power supply for electroporation applications</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-electroporation_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-electroporation_raymond/</guid>
      <description>Electroporation is a technique that uses high pulsed electric fields to create pores in biological cell walls for medical, liquid sterilization and other applications. Many systems use mono-polar pulses for simplicity but electro-migration can limit electrode life. The following paper demonstrates a resonant circuit design for creating high voltage bi-polar dc pulses using a simple control strategy. The circuit topology consists of two Radio Frequency (RF) amplifiers each coupled to a multi-level resonant rectifier employing capacitive isolation and operating at 15 MHz. The RF signals generated by the amplifiers themselves are used to control the pulse duration and output polarity. Any sequence of positive and negative pulse trains can be generated between several μs through dc. This paper presents a proof of concept design providing 800 V positive and negative pulses into a resistive load.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz isolated high voltage gain multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a high efficiency, high power density, and fast transient response dc-dc converter design capable of providing a high-voltage isolated output from a low-voltage input. Specifically, we demonstrate two 100 W, 2000 Vdc proof of concept prototype dc-dc converters operating at a switching frequency of 27.12 MHz with input voltages of 40 V and 100 V respectively. Capacitive isolation provides an efficient means of allowing for multiple rectified outputs to be combined serially without exceeding semi-conductor device limits. Further, it can provide a more efficient means of impedance matching at frequencies of 10s of MHz than traditional methods such as passive matching networks or transformers by the reduction of or elimination of those stages altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN resonant power converter with PCB embedded resonant air core inductors and capacitors</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a 27.12 MHz, 320 W, 170 V to 28 V dc-dc resonant power converter with resonant inductors and capacitors embedded into the Printed Circuit Board (PCB). Operating at 27.12 MHz allows for small value and size resonant passive components to be implemented using traces on or within a PCB. A prototype dc-dc converter was built to verify the concept and it reaches an efficiency of 73.6%. A simulated loss analysis is also presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network. Multiple stages are stacked in a way that allows for higher output voltages without suffering efficiency penalties common to traditional serial type high-voltage converter topologies such as the Crockroft-Walton Multiplier. Application of this design results in an isolated resonant dc-dc converter design that promises high efficiency, fast transient response, and high power density while providing a high-voltage isolated output from a lower-voltage input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN Bi-directional resonant power converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>Resonant dc-dc converter regularly use Schottky diodes for high frequency rectification. Si Schottky diodes have relatively low voltage ratings and present reverse-recovery type losses when driven hard enough. SiC Schottky diodes can operate at high frequencies, but incur higher conduction losses. This paper presents a bidirectional dc-dc resonant converter having two ground referenced switches. The prototype converter delivers 400 W between a source of 170 V and a load of 50 V while delivering 250 W in the opposite direction. The converter presented herein can potentially be used in applications such as wireless power transfer, fuel cell and battery applications, bus converters, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz 1.3 kW resonant converter with GaN FET for wireless power transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/gan-wpt-choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/gan-wpt-choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a 1.3 kW resonant power amplifier using a Gallium Nitride (GaN) device at 13.56 MHz for wireless power transfer (WPT). The power amplifier driving the power transmitting coils is based on a Class Φ 2 inverter, a single switch topology with low switch voltage stress and fast transient response. This implementation utilizes a recently available GaN device in a low inductance package that is compatible with operation in the 10&amp;rsquo;s of MHz switching frequency. These power GaN switching devices have low gate resistance RG and low capacitance C GS which greatly reduces the power requirements of the gate drive circuitry. This paper shows experimental measurements of the inverter in a WPT application and characterization of the system performance over various distances and operating conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz High Density DC–DC Converter With PCB Inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-13m56-dcdc-pcb-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-13m56-dcdc-pcb-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high density 150-200 V to 28 V, 200-400 W resonant dc-dc converter with embedded inductors. The converter has a switching frequency of 13.56 MHz and uses air-core toroidal inductors fabricated with printed circuit board (PCB) technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D-Printed Air-Core Inductors for High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-3dprinted-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling, and characterization of 3-D-printed air-core inductors for high-frequency power electronics circuits. The use of 3-D modeling techniques to make passive components extends the design flexibility and addresses some of the fabrication limitations of traditional processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air-core inductors realized using 3-D printing and casting/plating techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to design. Toward this goal, we present a 70-W prototype 27.12-MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3-D-printed components developed for this paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 IEEE COMPEL Best Paper Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/2015compel_luke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015compel_luke/</guid>
      <description>L. Raymond, W. Liang, L. Gu and J. R. Davila, &amp;ldquo;13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter,&amp;rdquo; 2015 IEEE 16th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics (COMPEL), 2015, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109/COMPEL.2015.7236446.
Abstract     This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A High-Frequency Resonant Converter Based on the Class Phi2 Inverter for Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/vtc-phi2-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/vtc-phi2-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of high frequency resonant converter based on the Class Φ 2 inverter for inductive power transfer. MHz frequency operation can allow for higher power density than conventional switching frequencies. The converter is based on the Class Φ 2 inverter, reducing the voltage stress across the switch compared to other resonant topologies. A prototype of converter and a few cm airgap inductive coupling system with resistive load was implemented. We will demonstrate a greater than hundred Watt push-pull resonant converter for inductive power transfer at 13.56MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas featured in Stanford EE spotlight</title>
      <link>/blog/2014eespotlight_rivas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014eespotlight_rivas/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Electrical Engineering Professor Juan Rivas-Davila loves being in the midst of top-notch Stanford students, world-class research facilities and within a community brimming with entrepreneurial attitudes.  EE spotlight What made you decide to be a professor, and what made you want to be at Stanford? After grad school, I spent a few years working at GE Global Research. There I learned electrical engineering research can change (and has changed) the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D printed air core inductors for high frequency power converters</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-3d-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-3d-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling and characterization of 3D printed air core inductors for high frequency power electronics circuits. The use of additive manufacturing techniques in passive components design extends the design flexibility and offers ways to overcome some of the fabrication limitations of today&amp;rsquo;s planar processes. Recent work [1]-[4] has demonstrated the feasibility of incorporating air core inductors in high frequency (&amp;gt;10 MHz) switching power converters. These implementations have used discrete wire wound solenoids and toroids, and planar components that use Printed Circuit Board (PCB) traces or photolithographic techniques to make air core inductors. However, realizations of such components have limitations in performance and applicability: wire wound and PCB devices leave open paths conducive to the flow of leakage fields, and photolithography yields devices with geometric constraints and limited cross section aspect ratios. We propose the use of 3D printing and molding techniques to add flexibility and functionality in the design as they allow the manufacturing of components with rounded edges and overhanging structures impossible for planar processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air core inductors designed using 3D printing and molding techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to realize. Moreover, we show that some of these designs can lead to improved electrical performance. The paper also describes the tools used by the authors to design, fabricate and characterize the electromagnetic performance of the air core inductors. As progress in additive manufacturing continues, we envision a fully 3D printed power converter that obviates the need of printed circuits board. Toward this goal, we present a 70 W prototype 27.12 MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3D printed components developed for this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performance evaluation of diodes in 27.12 MHz Class-D resonant rectifiers under high voltage and high slew rate conditions</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-coss-diodes_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-coss-diodes_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper provides a performance review of select diodes for use in high frequency resonant rectifiers at modest power levels. Specifically, we evaluate the performance of several leading edge diodes for use in a 27.12 MHz Class-D type rectifier for output voltages from 170 V to 1000 V dc, and corresponding power levels between 8.5 W and 100 W. The authors suspect these losses are due in part to the high equation experienced by the Silicon Carbide (SiC) Schottky diodes used in that design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz large voltage gain resonant converter with low voltage stress</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-large-gain-dcdc_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-large-gain-dcdc_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high frequency switching power converter with a large voltage gain and air core inductors. Specifically, we demonstrate a 40 W, 30 V to 300 V dc-dc converter switching at 27.12 MHz.We evaluate and compare two rectifier topologies with lower voltage stress than the class E rectifiers described in [2], to get large voltage ratios. Unique to this design is the ability to provide short bursts of high voltage while promising excellent performance and high power density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz high density dc-dc converter with PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high density 150 V-200 V to 28 V, 200 W-400 W resonant dc-dc converter with embedded inductors. The converter has a switching frequency of 13.56 MHz and uses air-core toroidal inductors fabricated with printed circuit board (PCB) technology. Moreover, the paper discusses the trade-offs between simplicity and performance of implementing a hard-switched gate drive at MHz switching frequencies. We describe the advantages of resonant power converter topologies in applications requiring high density and high performance in demanding environmental conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the students, collaborators and company sponsors that have contributed to our research.
Sponsors      SystemX Texas Instruments LAM-Research Daihen ON-Semiconductors Precourt Institute for Energy TomKat Center for Suistainable Energy Stanford Woods Institute for the Environment National Science Foundation  Collaborators      Prof. Mark Capelli, Stanford University Prof. Srabanti Chowdhuri, Stanford University Prof. Christine Charles and Prof. Rod Boswell, Australian National University Prof.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
