<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Prof. Juan M. Rivas Davila on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Prof. Juan M. Rivas Davila on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile     https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Douglas Chaffee</title>
      <link>/labpeople/doug/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/doug/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Max Pranglin, M.S.</title>
      <link>/alumni/maxpraglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/maxpraglin/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emily Hernandez, M.S.</title>
      <link>/alumni/emilyhernandez/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/emilyhernandez/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhechi Ye</title>
      <link>/labpeople/zhechiye/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/zhechiye/</guid>
      <description>yezc15@stanford.edu</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eric Stolt</title>
      <link>/labpeople/ericstolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/ericstolt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wei Liang, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/weiliang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/weiliang/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Luke Raymond, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/lukeraymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/lukeraymond/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   * Compact high frequency power conversion for high voltage applications *      Presented in 2018 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Performance of high-voltage power converters has lagged their low-voltage counterparts on many metrics including power density, efficiency, transient response, and cost. This research presents newly developed circuit techniques and design strategies that allow high-voltage power supplies to be many times smaller and more efficient than the traditional high-voltage supplies on the market today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weston Braun</title>
      <link>/labpeople/weston/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/weston/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jungwon Choi, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/jungwonchoi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/jungwonchoi/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   High-frequency, high-power resonant converter with wide bandgap devices for wireless power transfer systems      Presented in 2018 Manuscript availabe here.  Summary     As demand for electric vehicles (EVs) grows, wireless power transfer (WPT) technology becomes beneficial by removing the need for manual intervention to charge EV batteries. These high-power applications require power electronics systems that not only efficiently deliver sufficient power, but are also small enough to be embedded in the EV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zikang Tong</title>
      <link>/labpeople/zikangtong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/zikangtong/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jia Zhuang</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jiazhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jiazhuang/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lei Gu, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/leigu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/leigu/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   Design considerations for radio frequency power converters      Presented in 2019 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Compact and efficient high-frequency power converters and amplifiers are needed in a variety of applications, including base stations, mobile devices, and medical equipment. The ever-growing need for a smaller size, longer battery life, and lower cost introduces challenging design considerations for radio-frequency power converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grayson Zulauf, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/graysonzulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/graysonzulauf/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   Wide-bandgap semiconductors for next-generation power electronics systems      Presented on May 19, 2020 Availabe for download here.  Summary     Wide-bandgap power semiconductors promise to reshape the power electronics landscape, opening completely new use cases and increasing efficiency and power density in existing ones. Most notably, gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC) were successfully commercialized in the past decades, with theoretical benefits over silicon of multiple orders-of-magnitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JiaLe Xu</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jialexu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jialexu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kawin Surakitbovorn</title>
      <link>/labpeople/kawin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/kawin/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   On the design and optimization of RF power amplifiers using wide bandgap devices      Presented March 2021 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Compact radio-frequency (RF) power amplifiers are essential building blocks in various applications, including radio transmission, medical imaging, wireless power transfer, industrial plasma generation, and micro-satellite propulsion. Over the past decades, new wide bandgap (WBG) semiconductor devices, particularly gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), were successfully commercialized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sanghyeon Park, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/sanghyeon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/sanghyeon/</guid>
      <description> Doctoral Dissertation   Circuit techniques for compact and lightweight high-voltage dc power supplies      Presented on April 13, 2021  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jason Poon</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jasonpoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jasonpoon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Resonators for Piezoelectric Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</guid>
      <description>The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/dynamic-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of ${C}_{{\mathrm {oss}}}$ and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origins of Soft-switching Coss Losses in SiC Power MOSFETs and Diodes for Resonant Converter Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</guid>
      <description>The recent development and commercialization of wide bandgap (WBG) power semiconductors, specifically gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), has driven the increase in switching frequency for soft-switching power converters like the Class E, Class Φ2, and Class DE resonant inverters and rectifiers. However, prior literature has characterized numerous commercial GaN and SiC devices using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and discovered significant large-signal charge-voltage hysteresis of the Coss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Carrier Phase Shifting for Optimal Harmonic Minimization in Asymmetric Parallel-Connected Inverters</title>
      <link>/publication/decentralized-harmonic-minimization-parallel-inverters_poon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/decentralized-harmonic-minimization-parallel-inverters_poon/</guid>
      <description>This article presents a carrier phase shifting technique for minimizing the aggregate harmonics in networks of asymmetric parallel-connected inverters for distributed power generation system applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and voltage domain load models for appliance-level grid edge simulation and control</title>
      <link>/publication/tandv-load-models-grid_goldin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tandv-load-models-grid_goldin/</guid>
      <description>Developments in simulation and distributed control of distributed energy resources require increasingly granular characterization and modeling of load behavior. Previous work has demonstrated the viability of voltage-based power control of residential appliances to enable load flexibility without service interruption. However, conventional static and dynamic load models fail to capture the coupled voltage and state dynamics relevant for this type of control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Gu awarded the IEEE PELS PhD Thesis Talk Award</title>
      <link>/blog/ieeep3talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ieeep3talk/</guid>
      <description>The Selection Committee for the PELS Ph.D.Thesis Talk (P3) consisted of worldwide Distinguished Professors in the Power Electronics community. Each video submission was reviewed by a panel of three judges who have now completed their evaluations, this was a difficult task because of the high quality of nominations. I&amp;rsquo;d like to now congratulate the following winners.
2020 IEEE PELS Ph.D. Thesis Talk Award (P3) Winners:
  Design Considerations for Radio Frequency Power Converters by Lei Gu, Stanford University, USA Synchronised Control of Grid-Interactive Inverters using Stationary Frame Resonant Regulators by Afif Nazib, RMIT University, Australia Mission Profile based System-Level Lifetime Prediction of Modular Multilevel Converters by Yi Zhang, Aalborg University, Denmark Three-Layer Control Strategy for LLC Converters: Large-Signal, Small Signal, and Steady-State Operation by Mehdi Mohammadi, University of British Columbia, Canada Torque Estimation in Permanent Magnet Synchronous Machines by Maria Martinez Gomez, University of Oviedo, Spain  The Award Consists of $1000 + Certificate + up to a maximum of $500 towards travel reimbursement to attend IEEE ECCE 2020 in Detroit to receive the award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tachyons for Style</title>
      <link>/project/giraffes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/giraffes/</guid>
      <description>Tachyons is a design system that allows you to design gorgeous interfaces in the browser with little effort.      Because Speed     Building this static site generator theme was the first time I used an Atomic (or Functional) CSS system like Tachyons. It&amp;rsquo;s a design system that provides very small (which means fast) CSS modules that you can use in your HTML. So, rather than writing every line of CSS, you apply the style you need as you write your HTML with easy to understand shorthand class names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Palmer Penguins</title>
      <link>/project/penguins/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/penguins/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bakeoff</title>
      <link>/project/bakeoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/bakeoff/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APEC 2019 Outstanding Presentation Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/19apeczk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/19apeczk/</guid>
      <description>Z. Tong, S. Park and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices,&amp;rdquo; 2019 IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition (APEC), 2019, pp. 998-1003, doi: 10.1109/APEC.2019.8721907.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas received NSF award to develop high-voltage power supplies for medical, environmental, and aerospace applications.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nsfhv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nsfhv/</guid>
      <description>High-Voltage High-Power-Density Power Electronics for Emerging Medical, Environmental, and Aerospace Applications   High-voltage low-current power-electronic converters that can deliver voltages between 10s to 100s of kV and currents in the 1-100 mA range play a critical role in many medical, environmental, and aerospace applications, established or emerging. In many of those applications, a compact and lightweight high-voltage power supply is desirable if not essential. Unfortunately, conventional technologies are inefficient, heavy, and bulky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan Lab &amp; SUPERlab are one of three winners of NASA iTech’s 2018 Energy Cycle</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nasaitech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nasaitech/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Grayson Zulauf (third from left) is an EE PhD candidate. He is a researcher in the SUPERLab, directed by Professor Juan Rivas-Davila. the Fan Lab is directed by professor Jonathan Fan.  Congratulations to professors Jon Fan and Juan Rivas-Davila! Two of their researchers won the 2018 NASA iTech Forum. The event is a collaborative effort between NASA and the U.S. Department (DOE) of Energy’s Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) to find and foster innovative solutions for critical energy challenges on Earth and in space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 COMPEL Best Paper Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018compel_lei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018compel_lei/</guid>
      <description>L. Gu, K. Surakitbovorn, G. Zulauf, S. Chakraborty and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation,&amp;rdquo; 2018 IEEE 19th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics (COMPEL), 2018, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109/COMPEL.2018.8459962.
Summary:     Applying RF circuit design techniques to dc-dc resonant converters has enabled the switching frequency to be pushed well beyond 10 MHz, resulting in higher power densities and faster transient response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Student Paper Award</title>
      <link>/blog/2018ecceasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018ecceasia/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Kawin (North) Surakitbovorn at the award ceremony  K. Surakitbovorn and J. Rivas-Davilla, “Design of a GaN-Based Wireless Power Transfer System at 13.56 MHz to Replace Conventional Wired Connection in a Vehicle,” 2018 International Power Electronics Conference (IPEC-Niigata 2018 -ECCE Asia), 2018, pp. 3848-3854, doi: 10.23919/IPEC.2018.8507473.
Abstract Wired connections running through the doors, hatchbacks, and trunks of a vehicle are subjected to extensive mechanical wear from repeated bending caused by the open-and-close motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUPER-Lab undergrad intern featured in Stanford EE Spotligh</title>
      <link>/blog/2017sabera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017sabera/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Sabera J. Talukder  How did you become interested in your research area? There are two research avenues that I am extremely interested in: one is neuroengineering and the second is creating systems to help people in third world countries. For as long as I can remember I have been interested in the brain, and experiences like interning for Medtronic’s Deep Brain Stimulation division cemented my desire to pursue neuroengineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 IEEE COMPEL Best Paper Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/2015compel_luke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015compel_luke/</guid>
      <description>L. Raymond, W. Liang, L. Gu and J. R. Davila, &amp;ldquo;13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter,&amp;rdquo; 2015 IEEE 16th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics (COMPEL), 2015, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109/COMPEL.2015.7236446.
Abstract     This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas featured in Stanford EE spotlight</title>
      <link>/blog/2014eespotlight_rivas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014eespotlight_rivas/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Electrical Engineering Professor Juan Rivas-Davila loves being in the midst of top-notch Stanford students, world-class research facilities and within a community brimming with entrepreneurial attitudes.  EE spotlight What made you decide to be a professor, and what made you want to be at Stanford? After grad school, I spent a few years working at GE Global Research. There I learned electrical engineering research can change (and has changed) the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
