<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Stolt on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/eric-stolt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric Stolt on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/eric-stolt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eric Stolt</title>
      <link>/labpeople/ericstolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/ericstolt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Resonators for Piezoelectric Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</guid>
      <description>The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High density power converters with Piezo-electric resonators</title>
      <link>/project/tisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Photograph of prototype piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter.  The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters. In this paper we analyze the impact of resonator parameters on the performance of the piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter, derive the optimal load impedance and efficiency limits, and analyze the impacts of varying conversion ratio and load impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
