<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric Stolt on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/eric-stolt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Eric Stolt on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/eric-stolt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Eric Stolt</title>
      <link>/labpeople/ericstolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/ericstolt/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixed-Frequency Control of Piezoelectric Resonator DC-DC Converters for Spurious Mode Avoidance</title>
      <link>/publication/fixed-frequency-piezo-spurious-avoidance_stolt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/fixed-frequency-piezo-spurious-avoidance_stolt/</guid>
      <description>Piezoelectric resonators have shown promise as efficient, power-dense energy storage element alternatives to continue the miniaturization of DC-DC converters. However, practical piezoelectric resonators diverge from their ideal behavior due to spurious modes that cause high loss regions throughout their operating frequency range. This paper presents a fixed-frequency control mode utilizing the high-quality factor of piezoelectric resonators to avoid spurious modes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Recovery Testing of Small-Signal Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-reverse_recovery_diodes-braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-reverse_recovery_diodes-braun/</guid>
      <description>Ideally, Schottky diodes have little to no reverse recovery charge due to the lack of a PN junction or associated minority carriers. However, commercial Schottky diodes incorporate a PN junction guard ring under the electrode edge. At high currents, conduction through the guard ring structure can occur, injecting minority carriers and increasing reverse recovery charge. This behavior can lead to adverse circuit effects and increased loss, especially in high frequency dc-dc converters. Moreover, this effect is little-discussed in technical literature, not captured in datasheet provided values, and not typically incorporated into manufacture provided simulation models. This paper provides an open source and low-cost diode recovery test circuit and uses it to evaluate a selection of small-signal Schottky diodes and rectifiers. In several of the diodes, we find a significant increase in the recovery charge at high currents, characteristic of the PN junction guard ring’s conduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Resonators for Piezoelectric Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimized-resonators-piezoelectric_braun/</guid>
      <description>The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High density power converters with Piezo-electric resonators</title>
      <link>/project/tisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/tisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Photograph of prototype piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter.  The performance of inductors at high frequencies and small sizes is one of the largest limiting factors in the continued miniaturization of dc-dc converters. Piezoelectric resonators can have a very high quality factor and provide an inductive impedance between their series and parallel resonant frequencies, making them a promising technology for further miniaturizing dc-dc converters. In this paper we analyze the impact of resonator parameters on the performance of the piezoelectric resonator based dc-dc converter, derive the optimal load impedance and efficiency limits, and analyze the impacts of varying conversion ratio and load impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
