<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ECCE on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/ecce/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ECCE on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/ecce/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Recovery Testing of Small-Signal Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-reverse_recovery_diodes-braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-reverse_recovery_diodes-braun/</guid>
      <description>Ideally, Schottky diodes have little to no reverse recovery charge due to the lack of a PN junction or associated minority carriers. However, commercial Schottky diodes incorporate a PN junction guard ring under the electrode edge. At high currents, conduction through the guard ring structure can occur, injecting minority carriers and increasing reverse recovery charge. This behavior can lead to adverse circuit effects and increased loss, especially in high frequency dc-dc converters. Moreover, this effect is little-discussed in technical literature, not captured in datasheet provided values, and not typically incorporated into manufacture provided simulation models. This paper provides an open source and low-cost diode recovery test circuit and uses it to evaluate a selection of small-signal Schottky diodes and rectifiers. In several of the diodes, we find a significant increase in the recovery charge at high currents, characteristic of the PN junction guard ring’s conduction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A physical investigation of large-signal dynamic output capacitance and energy loss in GaN-on-Si power HEMTs at high-frequency applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-physical-large-signal-dynamic-output-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-physical-large-signal-dynamic-output-capacitance-gan_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>The origin of Coss and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of GaN buffer layers and Si-substrate. These loss components can be potentially improved by re-engineering the doping concentrations in the buffer stacks and substrate layer. This paper presents a physics view of the trapping dynamics that is related to C oss in the GaN HEMT under large-signal excitations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Ripple High-Voltage DC Generation Using a Serially Segmented Multiphase Voltage Multiplier</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-lowripple-hv-dc-multiphase_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-lowripple-hv-dc-multiphase_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a voltage multiplier topology that is suitable for a low-ripple high-voltage dc generation. The topology has a number of voltage multipliers connected in series and driven at different phases. Compared to a single-phase multiplier, an n-phase voltage multiplier has an output ripple that is smaller by n times. We demonstrate the ripple reduction of the proposed topology using a 6 V-to-800 V power supply with a 16-stage four-phase bipolar voltage multiplier. The output ripple frequency is eight times the converter&amp;rsquo;s switching frequency and the ripple amplitude is significantly smaller than the conventional single-phase voltage multiplier</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miniature High-Voltage DC-DC Power Converters for Space and Micro-Robotic Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</guid>
      <description>We develop a small and lightweight high-voltage high-gain power converter for applications where weight and size are premium. By driving a Dickson and Cockcroft-Walton voltage multiplier with a megahertz-frequency class-E inverter, we implement two converters, one that achieves 40 V-to-2 kV conversion with 16 cm 3 box volume and the other that achieves 3.7 V-to-2.9 kV conversion with 0.2 cm 3 box volume and 0.49 g weight. Presented converters achieve comparable or better power density and specific power to those of commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a 40.68 MHz power-combining resonant inverter with eGaN FETs for plasma generation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-40m68-gan_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-40m68-gan_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a 40.68 MHz, 1.2 kW power-combining resonant inverter using eGaN FETs for plasma generation. To provide high power at 40.68 MHz switching frequency, a class Φ2 inverter topology with wide band gap (WBG) devices such as eGaN FETs was selected. The proposed inverter topology reduces the power loss in each switching device, which can decrease the size of the heat sink. This study demonstrates that power-combining resonant inverters using eGaN FETs can increase efficiency and power density while operating at 40.68 MHz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of very-high-frequency synchronous resonant DC-DC converter for variable load operation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a simple solution to implement synchronous rectification for resonant dc-dc power converters operating in the Very-High-Frequency (VHF) range, by using a symmetric bandpass matching network between the inverter and rectifier. A bandpass matching network maintains a close-to-zero phase shift between the inverter and rectifier voltage, enabling the synchronous switch to be driven by the same clock signal as the inverter switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparison of SiC and eGaN devices in a 6.78 MHz 2.2 kW resonant inverter for wireless power transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-sic-gan-comparison_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-sic-gan-comparison_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a performance comparison of two wide band gap (WBG) devices, a silicon carbide (SiC) MOSFET and an enhancement mode gallium nitride (eGaN) FET in a resonant inverter operating at 6.78 MHz for wireless power transfer (WPT) applications. While SiC MOSFETs provide high breakdown voltage and good thermal characteristics, eGaN FETs can reduce gate losses due to small gate resistance and input capacitance. In this work, we compare a 1200 V SiC MOSFET in a single-ended class Φ 2 inverter to two 650 V eGaN FETs in a push-pull class Φ 2 inverter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inductance cancellation in RF resonant power converters</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-inductance-cancellation_praglin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-inductance-cancellation_praglin/</guid>
      <description>Parasitic inductance cancellation is employed in order to operate a resonant power inverter at 27.12 MHz using a TO-220 through-hole package.The elimination of parasitic inductances allows for system cost reduction, increased power handling, and/or relaxation of PCB layout constraints. The inductance cancellation technique is demonstrated through two prototypes (based upon the same silicon MOSFET die) providing 60 W of RF power to a 50 Ω load from a 48 V DC input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz isolated high voltage gain multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a high efficiency, high power density, and fast transient response dc-dc converter design capable of providing a high-voltage isolated output from a low-voltage input. Specifically, we demonstrate two 100 W, 2000 Vdc proof of concept prototype dc-dc converters operating at a switching frequency of 27.12 MHz with input voltages of 40 V and 100 V respectively. Capacitive isolation provides an efficient means of allowing for multiple rectified outputs to be combined serially without exceeding semi-conductor device limits. Further, it can provide a more efficient means of impedance matching at frequencies of 10s of MHz than traditional methods such as passive matching networks or transformers by the reduction of or elimination of those stages altogether.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN resonant power converter with PCB embedded resonant air core inductors and capacitors</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a 27.12 MHz, 320 W, 170 V to 28 V dc-dc resonant power converter with resonant inductors and capacitors embedded into the Printed Circuit Board (PCB). Operating at 27.12 MHz allows for small value and size resonant passive components to be implemented using traces on or within a PCB. A prototype dc-dc converter was built to verify the concept and it reaches an efficiency of 73.6%. A simulated loss analysis is also presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3D printed air core inductors for high frequency power converters</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-3d-inductors_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-3d-inductors_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design, modeling and characterization of 3D printed air core inductors for high frequency power electronics circuits. The use of additive manufacturing techniques in passive components design extends the design flexibility and offers ways to overcome some of the fabrication limitations of today&amp;rsquo;s planar processes. Recent work [1]-[4] has demonstrated the feasibility of incorporating air core inductors in high frequency (&amp;gt;10 MHz) switching power converters. These implementations have used discrete wire wound solenoids and toroids, and planar components that use Printed Circuit Board (PCB) traces or photolithographic techniques to make air core inductors. However, realizations of such components have limitations in performance and applicability: wire wound and PCB devices leave open paths conducive to the flow of leakage fields, and photolithography yields devices with geometric constraints and limited cross section aspect ratios. We propose the use of 3D printing and molding techniques to add flexibility and functionality in the design as they allow the manufacturing of components with rounded edges and overhanging structures impossible for planar processes. In this paper, we present several examples of air core inductors designed using 3D printing and molding techniques to give an idea of the geometries that are possible to realize. Moreover, we show that some of these designs can lead to improved electrical performance. The paper also describes the tools used by the authors to design, fabricate and characterize the electromagnetic performance of the air core inductors. As progress in additive manufacturing continues, we envision a fully 3D printed power converter that obviates the need of printed circuits board. Toward this goal, we present a 70 W prototype 27.12 MHz resonant inverter that incorporates some of the 3D printed components developed for this work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12 MHz large voltage gain resonant converter with low voltage stress</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-large-gain-dcdc_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-large-gain-dcdc_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high frequency switching power converter with a large voltage gain and air core inductors. Specifically, we demonstrate a 40 W, 30 V to 300 V dc-dc converter switching at 27.12 MHz.We evaluate and compare two rectifier topologies with lower voltage stress than the class E rectifiers described in [2], to get large voltage ratios. Unique to this design is the ability to provide short bursts of high voltage while promising excellent performance and high power density.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
