<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lei Gu on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/lei-gu/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lei Gu on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/lei-gu/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Lei Gu, Ph.D.</title>
      <link>/alumni/leigu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/alumni/leigu/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   Design considerations for radio frequency power converters      Presented in 2019 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Compact and efficient high-frequency power converters and amplifiers are needed in a variety of applications, including base stations, mobile devices, and medical equipment. The ever-growing need for a smaller size, longer battery life, and lower cost introduces challenging design considerations for radio-frequency power converters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wideband PPT Class Φ2 Inverter using Phase-Switched Impedance Modulation and Reactance Compensation</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-wideband-pp2-phi2-reactance-compensatoin_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-wideband-pp2-phi2-reactance-compensatoin_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper we experimentally demonstrate a 300 W PA for a 50 Ω load impedance using silicon (Si) devices. The PA achieves above 90% efficiency over approximately a 30% fractional bandwidth. In addition, the PA can also operate across broadband with light loads, where above 80% efficiency is maintained for up to 5 times higher load resistances. This switch-mode PA is one of the first to demonstrate such performance under load variation across a wide bandwidth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Self-Resonant Coils</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</guid>
      <description>MHz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer holds the promise of increased power density and high- efficiency wireless power transfer. Unfortunately, due to high- frequency losses in wide-bandgap semiconductors and low-Q high-frequency coil designs, these systems are universally less efficient, on a dc-dc basis, than wireless power systems operating at conventional frequency regimes. This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. Particularly, we present the optimal compensation strategy for parallel compensated coils, which is a topic less frequently discussed in literature than the series compensated coils. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and an optimal design strategy, we demonstrate a 6.78 MHz, 300 W wireless power transfer system that achieves 95 % dc-dc efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6.78-MHz Wireless Power Transfer With Self-Resonant Coils at 95% DC–DC Efficiency</title>
      <link>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/6m78-wpt-src-dcdc_gu/</guid>
      <description>This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and a better understanding of C oss losses in wide-bandgap power semiconductors, we demonstrate 6.78- MHz wireless power transfer systems that achieve 95% dc-dc efficiency at power levels up to and beyond 1 kW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Demonstration of GaN Impact Ionization Avalanche Transit-Time (IMPATT) Diode</title>
      <link>/publication/drc-gan-impatt_ji/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/drc-gan-impatt_ji/</guid>
      <description>The following topics are dealt with: III-V semiconductors; wide band gap semiconductors; gallium compounds; random-access storage; field effect transistors; semiconductor growth; aluminium compounds; indium compounds; semiconductor device breakdown; hafnium compounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Push–Pull Class Φ2  RF Power Amplifier</title>
      <link>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ppphi2pa_gu/</guid>
      <description>This work focuses on improving the design and operating characteristics of a push–pull $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier with a $T$ network connected between the switch nodes, or a PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier. The PPT $\Phi _\text2$ amplifier has less circulating energy and achieves higher cutoff frequency &lt;sub&gt;T&lt;/sub&gt; than other $\Phi _\text2$/EF&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; circuits</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitor Variations on Switched-Capacitor and Resonant Switched-Capacitor Converters,</title>
      <link>/publication/class2caps-variation-switchedcap_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/class2caps-variation-switchedcap_xu/</guid>
      <description>Class 2 ceramic capacitors, such as X7R, have relatively high energy density compared to Class 1 ceramic capacitors. However, they experience changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1%-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25 °C to 125 °C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. The measured equivalent series resistance (ESR) of the X7R capacitors shows an increase of 20% to 70% due to aging of 1680 h, and a 50% fluctuation in value when we apply 20% to 80% of the rated voltage</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hf-bidirec-resonant-high-conversion-ratio-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This article proposes an HF/very HF (VHF) resonant converter structure in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal. The presented structure enables efficient bidirectional power delivery in the HF/VHF range for applications that require a large voltage conversion ratio. A 64-MHz, 12-W, 36-12-V prototype converter verifies the operation of the structure. This article further explores an interleaved architecture of the same circuit to improve efficiency and transient performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Compact 45 V-to-54 kV Modular DC-DC Converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-40to54kv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-40to54kv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a compact 45 V-to-54 kV dc-dc converter for high-energy beam applications with the focus on X-ray generation. We describe key design choices for a high power density including a modular structure, high-frequency switching, planar transformers and Dickson topology. High-voltage insulation and thermal management are also described in detail. The experimental data with with a 5 kV single module and a 10-module 54 kV converter indicate that the proposed structure can generate high dc voltage while achieving a several times higher power density compared to commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loss Gate Driving Techniques of the Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device at High Frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</guid>
      <description>Cascoding a GaN HEMT and a SiC JFET best utilizes the advantages of both of these WBG power devices. Like GaN devices, the cascode GaN/SiC device is easy to drive at high frequencies and has low gate loss; like SiC devices, it also has relatively high voltage rating and low Coss energy loss at high frequencies. In this paper, we present our investigation of the gate loss mechanism of the SiC JFET in the cascode structure and our finding that the loss can be greatly reduced by minimizing the gate resistance of the SiC JFET (R g,Jfet ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI Compatible DC Modulator for an Envelope Tracking Transmitter,</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</guid>
      <description>Typical MRI power amplifiers are characterized by the requirement for high linearity and a high peak-to-average power ratio. Here we present a MRI compatible DC modulator for envelope tracking applications based on a 4-phase interleaved buck converter using air core magnetics and utilizing a FPGA based digital controller. The modulator is capable of delivering 500 W into a 2.5 Ω load at an efficiency of 95.6%, has a 3 dB modulation bandwidth of 50 kHz, and has been tested with a Class-AB linear amplifier operating at 64 MHz to produce a modulated RF envelope with a peak power of 320 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase GaN Class-D Resonant Amplifier for High-Intensity Focused Ultrasound</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</guid>
      <description>Focused ultrasound treats tissue deep in the body without damaging surrounding structures. Driven by large-amplitude RF electrical signals, ultrasonic transducers can generate large pressure acoustic wave. Wide-bandgap semiconductors, e.g., Gallium Nitride (GaN), greatly simplify the design and reduce the requisite size and weight of RF amplifiers, and so improves the portability of focused ultrasound device. Here, we demonstrate a compact 8-phase 5 MHz Class-D resonant amplifier for a focused ultrasound cancer therapy application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimal Input Voltage of a Class-E Power Amplifier with GaN HEMTs at MHz Frequency Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We mathematically analyze the operation of a Class-E amplifier when facing with this Coss loss term. We have found that the conventional wisdom of using the highest input voltage to get the best efficiency no longer holds above a certain frequency. Furthermore, to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated, we propose a distributed loss model for the Coss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Resonant Converter with Synchronous Rectification for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/ipec-syncrec-variable-load-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ipec-syncrec-variable-load-gu/</guid>
      <description>Applying RF circuit design techniques to dc-dc power conversion has pushed the switching frequency of power converters using discrete components well beyond 10 MHz. This paper proposes a simple solution to implement synchronous rectification for resonant dc-dc power converters operating at above 10 MHz, by using a symmetric bandpass matching network between the inverter and rectifier. The bandpass matching network enables the synchronous switch to be driven by the same clock signal as the inverter switch. Furthermore, this family of high frequency converter is able to maintain zero-voltage-switching operation over a wide load range. A 200 W 13.56 MHz 210 V-to-30 V bidirectional converter with a peak efficiency of 90% is demonstrated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Integrated RF Power Delivery and Plasma Micro-Thruster System for Nano-Satellites</title>
      <link>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/frontiers-integrated-rf-plasma-thruster_liang/</guid>
      <description>Progress in satellite technologies is ongoing and eventually finds applications back on Earth. Electric propulsion systems have been proven effective on large scale satellites (NASA DAWN) with better propellant efficiency than chemical or cold gas propulsion, and if miniaturized can be promising for long term operation of nano-satellites (e.g., CubeSats) in low Earth orbit or in deep space (NASA MarCO). Here we present a compact and efficient switched mode dc-RF power inverter integrated with an electro-thermal plasma micro-thruster for nano-satellite (e.g., Cubesats) propulsion. The integrated system can serve as side panels and structural support of CubeSats, saving precious on-board volume for propellant and/or payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide Input Range Isolated Stacked Resonant Switched-Capacitor dc-dc Converter for High Conversion Ratios</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an isolated dc-dc converter architecture for high conversion ratios using the stacked resonant switched-capacitor topology. Capacitive isolation is adopted in place of transformer isolation for saving cost and platform size. With phase shift operation, the topology can support a wide input range with a simple regulation scheme while enabling zero-voltage switching. The topology can be adapted to high conversion ratios via addition of stacking levels while keeping the same magnetics. The experimental results demonstrate a 2-Stack example achieving a peak efficiency of 92.8% and a peak power density of 283 W/inch 3 with 92% efficiency. The converter can also maintain within 3% efficiency drop over 25%-100% load range, and 50%-100% input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitance Variations on Switched Capacitor and Resonant Switched Capacitor Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the impact of Class 2 ceramic capacitance (such as X7R) variations on switched capacitor (SC) and resonant switched capacitor (ReSC) converters. Capacitance changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field are studied and modeled in LTSpice simulations. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25°C to 125°C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. Converter performance degradation is quantified in simulation and demonstrated by implementing a 1 MHz 25 W 1:4 Dickson ReSC converter. The converter efficiency decreases from 93.1% to 90.7% due to capacitance variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a bidirectional resonant converter design in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal at frequencies above 10 MHz. The proposed design enables efficient operation at &amp;gt; 10 MHz for applications which require high conversion-ratio bidirectional power delivery. We demonstrate a 200 W 13.56 MHz 210 V-to-30 V bidirectional converter with a peak efficiency of 90%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>60 V-to-35 kV input-parallel output-series DC-DC converter using multi-level class-DE rectifiers</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-35kv-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-35kv-park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a high-voltage dc-dc converter that includes inductively-isolated rectifiers. Previous work on multi-stage class-DE rectifiers only included capacitive dc isolation, limiting the output voltage to twice of the capacitor voltage rating. By adding an air-core transformer before the rectifier for inductive isolation, the maximum output voltage can be twice the breakdown voltage of the insulation between the transformer&amp;rsquo;s primary and secondary windings, thus allowing the implementation of a small, lightweight, and fast transient high-voltage dc-dc converter. We experimentally demonstrate a multi-modular converter design with 60 V input voltage and 35 kV output voltage with 73 % efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide-Input-Range High-Efficiency Step-Down Power Factor Correction Converter Using a Variable Frequency Multiplier Technique,</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a step-down power factor preregulator design that achieves a high efficiency across the entire universal input voltage range (85-265 V rms ) for an offline power supply application. The proposed circuit allows MOSFETs with lower voltage ratings and better conduction/switching characteristics to be used in both converter stages. A scaling law of power losses versus breakdown voltage requirement for boost circuit under the condition of the same output power is presented. Experimental results demonstrated a flatter high efficiency performance across a wide input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of very-high-frequency synchronous resonant DC-DC converter for variable load operation</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-syncrec-variable-load_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a simple solution to implement synchronous rectification for resonant dc-dc power converters operating in the Very-High-Frequency (VHF) range, by using a symmetric bandpass matching network between the inverter and rectifier. A bandpass matching network maintains a close-to-zero phase shift between the inverter and rectifier voltage, enabling the synchronous switch to be driven by the same clock signal as the inverter switch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact RF power inverter with reduced EMI for a CubeSat electrothermal micro-thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>TThis paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with a PCB multi-resonant input filter for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are part of an investigation seeking to add micro propulsion systems to low cost CubeSats. The proposed RF power inverter and multi-resonant input filter use only air core inductors. All inductors are toroidal and formed by PCB traces and vias allowing a planar and compact design. The PCB structure serves as structural support to save space and volume for propulsion propellant and other payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-resonant gate driver for Very-High-Frequency (VHF) resonant converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a Very-High-Frequency (VHF) multi-resonant gate drive circuit. The design procedure is greatly simplified compared with some VHF self-oscillating multi-resonant gate drivers presented in previous works. The proposed circuit has the potential to reduce long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and to better utilize fast transient capability of VHF converters. A prototype resonant gate driver is demonstrated and able to reduce 60 % of the gate driving loss of a 20 MHz 32 W Class-E power amplifier with Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Universal line input power factor preregulator using VFX technique</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-vfx-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a power factor preregulator design in which the energy buffer capacitor is placed at the output of the converter. In this implementation, a resonant LLC converter supplies power to a boost converter operating in continuous conduction mode. Here, a variable frequency (VFX) technique is used in the resonant LLC converter stage to achieve a lower variation in the overall efficiency across the universal input voltage range (85 - 265V rms ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN resonant power converter with PCB embedded resonant air core inductors and capacitors</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gan-pcb_liang/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a 27.12 MHz, 320 W, 170 V to 28 V dc-dc resonant power converter with resonant inductors and capacitors embedded into the Printed Circuit Board (PCB). Operating at 27.12 MHz allows for small value and size resonant passive components to be implemented using traces on or within a PCB. A prototype dc-dc converter was built to verify the concept and it reaches an efficiency of 73.6%. A simulated loss analysis is also presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hv_raymond/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network. Multiple stages are stacked in a way that allows for higher output voltages without suffering efficiency penalties common to traditional serial type high-voltage converter topologies such as the Crockroft-Walton Multiplier. Application of this design results in an isolated resonant dc-dc converter design that promises high efficiency, fast transient response, and high power density while providing a high-voltage isolated output from a lower-voltage input.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>27.12MHz GaN Bi-directional resonant power converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>Resonant dc-dc converter regularly use Schottky diodes for high frequency rectification. Si Schottky diodes have relatively low voltage ratings and present reverse-recovery type losses when driven hard enough. SiC Schottky diodes can operate at high frequencies, but incur higher conduction losses. This paper presents a bidirectional dc-dc resonant converter having two ground referenced switches. The prototype converter delivers 400 W between a source of 170 V and a load of 50 V while delivering 250 W in the opposite direction. The converter presented herein can potentially be used in applications such as wireless power transfer, fuel cell and battery applications, bus converters, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
