<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WPT on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/wpt/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WPT on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/wpt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Self-Resonant Coils</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</guid>
      <description>MHz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer holds the promise of increased power density and high- efficiency wireless power transfer. Unfortunately, due to high- frequency losses in wide-bandgap semiconductors and low-Q high-frequency coil designs, these systems are universally less efficient, on a dc-dc basis, than wireless power systems operating at conventional frequency regimes. This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. Particularly, we present the optimal compensation strategy for parallel compensated coils, which is a topic less frequently discussed in literature than the series compensated coils. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and an optimal design strategy, we demonstrate a 6.78 MHz, 300 W wireless power transfer system that achieves 95 % dc-dc efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Method to Eliminate Discrete Inductors in a Class-E Inverter Used in Wireless Power Transfer Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/eliminate-discrete-inductors-classe-wpt_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/eliminate-discrete-inductors-classe-wpt_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>we demonstrate a printed circuit board (PCB)-based WPT circuit operating at 40.68 MHz, utilizing no discrete inductors other than the WPT coils themselves and weighing only 7 g. This article describes the design methodology as well as the procedure to eliminate the discrete resonant inductors used in the implementation of our designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimization of a Class-E Power Amplifier With GaN HEMTs at Megahertz Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/optimization-classe-gan-mhz_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We examine the constraints that dictate when this optimization equations can and cannot be used, as well as propose a distributed loss model for the C oss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE) to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated. To verify our mathematical analysis and to demonstrate the applications of the proposed GSE-based C oss loss model, two design examples are provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an Impedance Compression Network to Compensate for Misalignments in a Wireless Power Transfer System</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-icn-wpt-choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-icn-wpt-choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an impedance compression network (ICN) design in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system to compensate for distance or alignment variations between coils. In order to reduce coil impedance variation, we propose an ICN that compresses variations in coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
