<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMPEL on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/compel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COMPEL on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/compel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 kW, Multi-MHz Wireless Charging for Electric Transportation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</guid>
      <description>We design and build a DC-DC wireless power system for electric vehicles charging at 6.78 MHz. With a gap of 34 cm, the air-core system can transfer up to 1 kW with 82% efficiency. It can operate continuously without failure even when the gap varies from 26 to 38 cm, and though the output power changes with distance, the efficiency does not vary appreciably. Due to the high operating frequency, the transfer coils are lightweight, inexpensive, and mechanically robust, even with a gap much larger than in previous literature. The systems low cost and resilience across coupling makes it amenable to mass deployment in commercial systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Self-Resonant Coils</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</guid>
      <description>MHz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer holds the promise of increased power density and high- efficiency wireless power transfer. Unfortunately, due to high- frequency losses in wide-bandgap semiconductors and low-Q high-frequency coil designs, these systems are universally less efficient, on a dc-dc basis, than wireless power systems operating at conventional frequency regimes. This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. Particularly, we present the optimal compensation strategy for parallel compensated coils, which is a topic less frequently discussed in literature than the series compensated coils. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and an optimal design strategy, we demonstrate a 6.78 MHz, 300 W wireless power transfer system that achieves 95 % dc-dc efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D Printed Air-Core Toroidal Transformer for High-Frequency Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a nested toroidal air-core transformer utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology. The first part of this work discusses design equations to achieve the target inductance matrix. Lastly, this work provides experimental demonstrations of the transformer design including a 40.68 MHz 48-to-350 V resonant dc-dc converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Compact 45 V-to-54 kV Modular DC-DC Converter</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-40to54kv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-40to54kv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design of a compact 45 V-to-54 kV dc-dc converter for high-energy beam applications with the focus on X-ray generation. We describe key design choices for a high power density including a modular structure, high-frequency switching, planar transformers and Dickson topology. High-voltage insulation and thermal management are also described in detail. The experimental data with with a 5 kV single module and a 10-module 54 kV converter indicate that the proposed structure can generate high dc voltage while achieving a several times higher power density compared to commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Investigation into the Causes of COSS Losses in GaN-on-Si HEMTs</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_zhuang/</guid>
      <description>In this work, we investigate the origin of these losses in GaN-on-Si High Electron Mobility Transistors (HEMTs) using TCAD simulation and experimental techniques, and find that COSS losses can be separated into resistive loss and GaN-stack trap related loss. From device simulation, we observe the expected dependence of substrate displacement current on dV/dt, and the importance of resistive loss is further confirmed with an experimental Sawyer-Tower test with an external resistor attached to the substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Low-Loss Gate Driving Techniques of the Cascode GaN/SiC Power Device at High Frequencies</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gatedrive-cascode-gansic_xu/</guid>
      <description>Cascoding a GaN HEMT and a SiC JFET best utilizes the advantages of both of these WBG power devices. Like GaN devices, the cascode GaN/SiC device is easy to drive at high frequencies and has low gate loss; like SiC devices, it also has relatively high voltage rating and low Coss energy loss at high frequencies. In this paper, we present our investigation of the gate loss mechanism of the SiC JFET in the cascode structure and our finding that the loss can be greatly reduced by minimizing the gate resistance of the SiC JFET (R g,Jfet ).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MRI Compatible DC Modulator for an Envelope Tracking Transmitter,</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-mri_braun/</guid>
      <description>Typical MRI power amplifiers are characterized by the requirement for high linearity and a high peak-to-average power ratio. Here we present a MRI compatible DC modulator for envelope tracking applications based on a 4-phase interleaved buck converter using air core magnetics and utilizing a FPGA based digital controller. The modulator is capable of delivering 500 W into a 2.5 Ω load at an efficiency of 95.6%, has a 3 dB modulation bandwidth of 50 kHz, and has been tested with a Class-AB linear amplifier operating at 64 MHz to produce a modulated RF envelope with a peak power of 320 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiphase GaN Class-D Resonant Amplifier for High-Intensity Focused Ultrasound</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-hifu_gu/</guid>
      <description>Focused ultrasound treats tissue deep in the body without damaging surrounding structures. Driven by large-amplitude RF electrical signals, ultrasonic transducers can generate large pressure acoustic wave. Wide-bandgap semiconductors, e.g., Gallium Nitride (GaN), greatly simplify the design and reduce the requisite size and weight of RF amplifiers, and so improves the portability of focused ultrasound device. Here, we demonstrate a compact 8-phase 5 MHz Class-D resonant amplifier for a focused ultrasound cancer therapy application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimal Input Voltage of a Class-E Power Amplifier with GaN HEMTs at MHz Frequency Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We mathematically analyze the operation of a Class-E amplifier when facing with this Coss loss term. We have found that the conventional wisdom of using the highest input voltage to get the best efficiency no longer holds above a certain frequency. Furthermore, to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated, we propose a distributed loss model for the Coss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Study on Off-State Losses in Silicon-Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/coss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/coss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>Among HF/VHF rectifiers, SiC Schottky diodes exhibit larger losses compared to those captured in simulation, with additional off-state losses stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the CJ. Because these losses are not included in manufacturer simulation models nor have they been well-studied for SiC Schottky diodes, we experimentally measured them using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and compared the losses across manufacturer, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging. Furthermore, we analyzed the performances of these devices on a class-DE rectifier and compared their power dissipation from the simulation and experimental measurements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide Input Range Isolated Stacked Resonant Switched-Capacitor dc-dc Converter for High Conversion Ratios</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-wide-input-range-stacked_resonant_li/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an isolated dc-dc converter architecture for high conversion ratios using the stacked resonant switched-capacitor topology. Capacitive isolation is adopted in place of transformer isolation for saving cost and platform size. With phase shift operation, the topology can support a wide input range with a simple regulation scheme while enabling zero-voltage switching. The topology can be adapted to high conversion ratios via addition of stacking levels while keeping the same magnetics. The experimental results demonstrate a 2-Stack example achieving a peak efficiency of 92.8% and a peak power density of 283 W/inch 3 with 92% efficiency. The converter can also maintain within 3% efficiency drop over 25%-100% load range, and 50%-100% input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Considerations for Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-powerdevice-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-powerdevice-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we extend recent work on COSS losses, which have a significant impact on high- and very-high-frequency resonant converters, from GaN HEMTs to the remainder of the core active power devices used in medium- and highvoltage power conversion. Here, we characterize COSS losses in Silicon MOSFETs - including superjunctions and traditional constructions - and Silicon Carbide MOSFETs. The measured COSS losses in SiC MOSFETs do not increase with dV/dt at frequencies from 1-35 MHz and applied voltages up to 900 V. Across the tested SiC MOSFETs, 3-10% of the energy stored in the output capacitor is dissipated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a 13.56 MHz dc-to-dc resonant converter using an impedance compression network to mitigate misalignments in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency resonant converter with an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct horizontal alignment variations between coils in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system. In order to mitigate variations in coil impedance, we propose an ICN that simultaneously compresses magnitude and phase changes of coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a GaN-Based, Inductor-less, Wireless Power Transfer System at 40.68 MHz</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>Wireless power transfer systems have attracted tremendous attention over the past decade. The design of most small size, low power, WPT systems; however, utilizes ferrite to shield and redirect the magnetic fields. This add to the weight and bulk of the system. In this paper, a small and extremely lightweight, PCB based, proof-of-concept WPT system is demonstrated. The circuit operates at 40.68 MHz and is capable of 20 W of output power. It utilizes no discrete inductors other than the WPT coils themselves and weights only 7 grams. The following paper shows the design methodology and the inductor elimination technique used to achieve such design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of Class 2 Ceramic Capacitance Variations on Switched Capacitor and Resonant Switched Capacitor Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-capacitor_xu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the impact of Class 2 ceramic capacitance (such as X7R) variations on switched capacitor (SC) and resonant switched capacitor (ReSC) converters. Capacitance changes due to aging, temperature, and electric field are studied and modeled in LTSpice simulations. The measured X7R capacitance drop is 1-2% per decade hour due to aging, 18% due to a temperature change from 25°C to 125°C, and 75% due to an applied voltage that is 80% of the rated voltage. Converter performance degradation is quantified in simulation and demonstrated by implementing a 1 MHz 25 W 1:4 Dickson ReSC converter. The converter efficiency decreases from 93.1% to 90.7% due to capacitance variations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimating the Reliability of Series-Connected Schottky Diodes for High-Frequency Rectification</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-series-diodes_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-series-diodes_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a method to predict the overvoltage failure rate of diodes connected in series under high-frequency reverse bias. Conventional approaches use balancing capacitors to ensure the reliability of series-connected diodes at high frequency. Instead, we investigate the viability of achieving voltage balance between devices solely by the match between their junction capacitances. Serializing diodes without extra balancing components increases the blocking voltage and decreases the capacitance, allowing high-voltage conversion at high frequencies for applications such as X-ray. We measure statistical properties of junction capacitances to estimate the reverse voltage limit of 2, 3, and 4 diodes in series. The predicted failure rate shows a good agreement with experimental results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-bidirectional_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-bidirectional_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper proposes a bidirectional resonant converter design in which the rectifier and the inverter switches can be driven with the same gate signal at frequencies above 10 MHz. The proposed design enables efficient operation at &amp;gt; 10 MHz for applications which require high conversion-ratio bidirectional power delivery. We demonstrate a 200 W 13.56 MHz 210 V-to-30 V bidirectional converter with a peak efficiency of 90%.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A compact RF power inverter with reduced EMI for a CubeSat electrothermal micro-thruster</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-pocketrocket_liang/</guid>
      <description>TThis paper presents a compact RF power inverter implemented with a PCB multi-resonant input filter for driving an electrothermal plasma micro-thruster, mini Pocket Rocket 3.0 (miniPR 3.0). This miniPR 3.0 and its driving electronics are part of an investigation seeking to add micro propulsion systems to low cost CubeSats. The proposed RF power inverter and multi-resonant input filter use only air core inductors. All inductors are toroidal and formed by PCB traces and vias allowing a planar and compact design. The PCB structure serves as structural support to save space and volume for propulsion propellant and other payloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A multi-resonant gate driver for Very-High-Frequency (VHF) resonant converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-multiresonant-gatedrive_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a Very-High-Frequency (VHF) multi-resonant gate drive circuit. The design procedure is greatly simplified compared with some VHF self-oscillating multi-resonant gate drivers presented in previous works. The proposed circuit has the potential to reduce long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and to better utilize fast transient capability of VHF converters. A prototype resonant gate driver is demonstrated and able to reduce 60 % of the gate driving loss of a 20 MHz 32 W Class-E power amplifier with Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A portable electrostatic precipitator to reduce respiratory death in rural environments</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-precipitator-talukder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-precipitator-talukder/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design methodology of a miniaturized, portable, and low power electrostatic precipitator (ESP) to reduce indoor air pollution (IAP) from rural cookstoves. Decreasing the concentration of aerosol particles helps reduce the incidence of respiratory tract infections that can lead to disease and even death. We trace existing technologies and standards to combat IAP in cookstoves, design an ESP that allows precipitation at lower voltages via an electrode design that utilizes sub 5 kV voltages, and explore how rapidly pulsed converters decrease the power consumption of the circuit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A unified model for high-power, air-core toroidal PCB inductors</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-aircore_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-aircore_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We present the first unified electrical model for high-power, air-core toroidal inductors implemented as PCB traces, which includes closed-form calculations for the lumped capacitance, resistance, and inductance of the structure. In this regime, the self-resonant frequency (SRF) of the inductor may be of the same order of magnitude as the circuit operating frequency, so the capacitance must be carefully modeled and tightly controlled.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of GaN transistor losses at MHz frequencies in soft switching converters</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-gan-coss_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-gan-coss_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>On paper, Gallium nitride (GaN) transistor promises exceptional performance when used in converters operating at high switching frequency; nonetheless, reduction in their performance when used in real circuits have been observed. Previous experiments show that tested GaN transistors can display excessive loss of up to three times their predicted values under certain test conditions. This paper evaluates power losses in GaN transistors when used in class Φ 2 resonant soft-switching inverter topologies at MHz frequencies. Thermometric loss calibration technique is used to calculate the power losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an impedance compression network to correct misalignment in a wireless power transfer system</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-icn-wpt_choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of an impedance compression network (ICN) to correct distance variation or misalignment between coils in wireless power transfer (WPT) systems. Magnetic resonant coupling (MRC) coils provide high efficiency for charging mid-range WPT applications. However, a distance variation or misalignment between coils causes a coil-impedance change and significantly affects performances of WPT systems. In order to mitigate a coil-impedance variation, we propose an ICN simultaneously compressing changes in magnitude and phase of impedance. The ICN consists of a resistance compression network (RCN) and phase compression network (PCN). While the RCN effectively compresses the variation in the magnitude of impedance by using one pair consisting of an inductor and a capacitor, the PCN is designed using a Smith chart to reduce a phase variation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated resonant DC-DC converters with a loosely coupled transformer</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-isolated-dcdc_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-isolated-dcdc_park/</guid>
      <description>We present a dc-dc resonant converter structure that has a pair of loosely coupled inductors in place of one filter inductor and two resonant inductors. Not only the number of inductors is reduced by one, but in this arrangment the transformer provides galvanic isolation and requires a sub-unity coupling coefficient which eases the implementation, especially at high switching frequencies. Various topologies, including class-E, DE, and Φ 2 , benefit from this structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The “Smart Dim Fuse”: A new approach to load control as a distributed energy resource</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-smart-fuse_goldin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-smart-fuse_goldin/</guid>
      <description>Aggregation of behind-the-meter distributed energy resources holds promise to provide valuable services to the grid, enabling greater penetration of intermittent renewable energy sources. We propose the Smart Dim Fuse system as an approach to utilize loads for aggregation services. The Smart Dim Fuse, installed on individual circuits at the breaker panel, enables load power control without service interruption via direct AC to AC voltage modulation, while reporting load measurement, identification, and resource a vailability forecasting to the aggregator. Using data from 131 homes, we evaluate the aggregate resource availability, and demonstrate a proof-of-concept prototype of the power electronics needed for this functionality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
