<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMPEL on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/compel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in COMPEL on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/compel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>1 kW, Multi-MHz Wireless Charging for Electric Transportation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-1kw-wpt_phan/</guid>
      <description>We design and build a DC-DC wireless power system for electric vehicles charging at 6.78 MHz. With a gap of 34 cm, the air-core system can transfer up to 1 kW with 82% efficiency. It can operate continuously without failure even when the gap varies from 26 to 38 cm, and though the output power changes with distance, the efficiency does not vary appreciably. Due to the high operating frequency, the transfer coils are lightweight, inexpensive, and mechanically robust, even with a gap much larger than in previous literature. The systems low cost and resilience across coupling makes it amenable to mass deployment in commercial systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Optimization of 6.78 MHz Wireless Power Transfer with Self-Resonant Coils</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-6m78-wpt-selfresonantcoils_gu/</guid>
      <description>MHz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer holds the promise of increased power density and high- efficiency wireless power transfer. Unfortunately, due to high- frequency losses in wide-bandgap semiconductors and low-Q high-frequency coil designs, these systems are universally less efficient, on a dc-dc basis, than wireless power systems operating at conventional frequency regimes. This letter describes the design considerations for inductive wireless power transfer systems operating at 6.78 MHz. Particularly, we present the optimal compensation strategy for parallel compensated coils, which is a topic less frequently discussed in literature than the series compensated coils. With a novel high-frequency resonant amplifier topology, a high-Q self-resonant coil structure, and an optimal design strategy, we demonstrate a 6.78 MHz, 300 W wireless power transfer system that achieves 95 % dc-dc efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
