<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News and updates on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News and updates on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Style your site typography</title>
      <link>/blog/fonts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/fonts/</guid>
      <description>As with color themes, you can completely customize your site&amp;rsquo;s fonts within minutes of creating a new site. How you do it depends on how much control and customization you need.
Embedded fonts     Hugo Apéro includes 6 embedded fonts that work &amp;ldquo;out of the box.&amp;rdquo; We selected 3 serif and 3 sans-serif options that we thought looked good with this theme, in our humble opinions. All embedded fonts include real italics so you may emphasize to your heart&amp;rsquo;s content ❤️!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using panelsets</title>
      <link>/blog/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/seedling/</guid>
      <description>Courtesy of panelset.js by Garrick Aden-Buie, from his xaringanExtra package: https://pkg.garrickadenbuie.com/xaringanExtra/#/panelset
For example, this panelset:
Hello! 👋 hello
 Goodbye 💨 goodbye
  Was created by combining this theme&amp;rsquo;s panelset and panel shortcodes:
{{&amp;lt; panelset class=&amp;#34;greetings&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Hello! :wave:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} hello {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; panel name=&amp;#34;Goodbye :dash:&amp;#34; &amp;gt;}} goodbye {{&amp;lt; /panel &amp;gt;}} {{&amp;lt; /panelset &amp;gt;}} You could also revert to HTML as well. For example, this panelset:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Rmarkdown post</title>
      <link>/blog/rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description> Air quality     with(airquality, boxplot(Temp ~ Month)) with(airquality, plot(Ozone ~ Temp)) mlev &amp;lt;- levels(with(airquality, as.factor(Month))) with(airquality, plot(Ozone ~ Temp, pch = as.numeric(mlev), col = mlev)) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Gu awarded the IEEE PELS PhD Thesis Talk Award</title>
      <link>/blog/ieeep3talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ieeep3talk/</guid>
      <description>The Selection Committee for the PELS Ph.D.Thesis Talk (P3) consisted of worldwide Distinguished Professors in the Power Electronics community. Each video submission was reviewed by a panel of three judges who have now completed their evaluations, this was a difficult task because of the high quality of nominations. I&amp;rsquo;d like to now congratulate the following winners.
2020 IEEE PELS Ph.D. Thesis Talk Award (P3) Winners:
  Design Considerations for Radio Frequency Power Converters by Lei Gu, Stanford University, USA Synchronised Control of Grid-Interactive Inverters using Stationary Frame Resonant Regulators by Afif Nazib, RMIT University, Australia Mission Profile based System-Level Lifetime Prediction of Modular Multilevel Converters by Yi Zhang, Aalborg University, Denmark Three-Layer Control Strategy for LLC Converters: Large-Signal, Small Signal, and Steady-State Operation by Mehdi Mohammadi, University of British Columbia, Canada Torque Estimation in Permanent Magnet Synchronous Machines by Maria Martinez Gomez, University of Oviedo, Spain  The Award Consists of $1000 + Certificate + up to a maximum of $500 towards travel reimbursement to attend IEEE ECCE 2020 in Detroit to receive the award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSS Grid Scaffold</title>
      <link>/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/css-grid-scaffold/</guid>
      <description>“Grid is the very first CSS module created specifically to solve the layout problems we&amp;rsquo;ve all been hacking our way around for as long as we&amp;rsquo;ve been making websites.”     — Chris House, A Complete Guide to CSS Grid Layout 1
 Overview     Since I began building websites in Y2K, I&amp;rsquo;ve lost count how many times the phrase &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip;there&amp;rsquo;s got to be a better way to do this&amp;rdquo; has passed my lips.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Built-in Contact Form</title>
      <link>/blog/built-in-contact-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/built-in-contact-form/</guid>
      <description>Formspree makes it easy to receive submissions from HTML forms on your static website.      Functional Form     This theme has a form-to-email feature built in, thanks to the simple Formspree integration. All you need to activate the form is a valid recipient email address saved in the front matter of the form (/content/forms/contact.md). Of course, the example shown below (your@email.here) must not be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zikang Tong received Outstanding Presentation Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/19apeczk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/19apeczk/</guid>
      <description>Z. Tong, S. Park and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices,&amp;rdquo; 2019 IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition (APEC), 2019, pp. 998-1003, doi: 10.1109/APEC.2019.8721907.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas received NSF award to develop high-voltage power supplies for medical, environmental, and aerospace applications.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nsfhv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nsfhv/</guid>
      <description>High-Voltage High-Power-Density Power Electronics for Emerging Medical, Environmental, and Aerospace Applications   High-voltage low-current power-electronic converters that can deliver voltages between 10s to 100s of kV and currents in the 1-100 mA range play a critical role in many medical, environmental, and aerospace applications, established or emerging. In many of those applications, a compact and lightweight high-voltage power supply is desirable if not essential. Unfortunately, conventional technologies are inefficient, heavy, and bulky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan Lab &amp; SUPERlab are one of three winners of NASA iTech’s 2018 Energy Cycle</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nasaitech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nasaitech/</guid>
      <description>knitr::include_graphics(&amp;quot;GraysonZulauf-SUPERLab.jpg&amp;quot;) Congratulations to professors Jon Fan and Juan Rivas-Davila! Two of their researchers won the 2018 NASA iTech Forum. The event is a collaborative effort between NASA and the U.S. Department (DOE) of Energy&amp;rsquo;s Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) to find and foster innovative solutions for critical energy challenges on Earth and in space.
The winning project was presented by Grayson Zulauf and Thaibao (Peter) Phan. Both are PhD candidates. Their collaborative project is developing technology for wireless charging of electric vehicles on Earth, and eventually, Mars.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
