<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News and updates on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News and updates on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>2021 IEEE MTTS Student Design Competition</title>
      <link>/blog/2021-zk-mtts-award/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2021-zk-mtts-award/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: MTTS award  IEEE Microwave Theory and Techniques Society
2021 International Microwave Symposium
2021 Student Design Competition on High-efficiency power amplifier for 13.56 MHz</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Lei Gu awarded the IEEE PELS PhD Thesis Talk Award</title>
      <link>/blog/ieeep3talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/ieeep3talk/</guid>
      <description>The Selection Committee for the PELS Ph.D.Thesis Talk (P3) consisted of worldwide Distinguished Professors in the Power Electronics community. Each video submission was reviewed by a panel of three judges who have now completed their evaluations, this was a difficult task because of the high quality of nominations. I&amp;rsquo;d like to now congratulate the following winners.
2020 IEEE PELS Ph.D. Thesis Talk Award (P3) Winners:
  Design Considerations for Radio Frequency Power Converters by Lei Gu, Stanford University, USA Synchronised Control of Grid-Interactive Inverters using Stationary Frame Resonant Regulators by Afif Nazib, RMIT University, Australia Mission Profile based System-Level Lifetime Prediction of Modular Multilevel Converters by Yi Zhang, Aalborg University, Denmark Three-Layer Control Strategy for LLC Converters: Large-Signal, Small Signal, and Steady-State Operation by Mehdi Mohammadi, University of British Columbia, Canada Torque Estimation in Permanent Magnet Synchronous Machines by Maria Martinez Gomez, University of Oviedo, Spain  The Award Consists of $1000 + Certificate + up to a maximum of $500 towards travel reimbursement to attend IEEE ECCE 2020 in Detroit to receive the award.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APEC 2019 Outstanding Presentation Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/19apeczk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/19apeczk/</guid>
      <description>Z. Tong, S. Park and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices,&amp;rdquo; 2019 IEEE Applied Power Electronics Conference and Exposition (APEC), 2019, pp. 998-1003, doi: 10.1109/APEC.2019.8721907.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas received NSF award to develop high-voltage power supplies for medical, environmental, and aerospace applications.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nsfhv/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nsfhv/</guid>
      <description>High-Voltage High-Power-Density Power Electronics for Emerging Medical, Environmental, and Aerospace Applications   High-voltage low-current power-electronic converters that can deliver voltages between 10s to 100s of kV and currents in the 1-100 mA range play a critical role in many medical, environmental, and aerospace applications, established or emerging. In many of those applications, a compact and lightweight high-voltage power supply is desirable if not essential. Unfortunately, conventional technologies are inefficient, heavy, and bulky.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fan Lab &amp; SUPERlab are one of three winners of NASA iTech’s 2018 Energy Cycle</title>
      <link>/blog/2018nasaitech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018nasaitech/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Grayson Zulauf (third from left) is an EE PhD candidate. He is a researcher in the SUPERLab, directed by Professor Juan Rivas-Davila. the Fan Lab is directed by professor Jonathan Fan.  Congratulations to professors Jon Fan and Juan Rivas-Davila! Two of their researchers won the 2018 NASA iTech Forum. The event is a collaborative effort between NASA and the U.S. Department (DOE) of Energy’s Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy (ARPA-E) to find and foster innovative solutions for critical energy challenges on Earth and in space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 COMPEL Best Paper Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/2018compel_lei/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018compel_lei/</guid>
      <description>L. Gu, K. Surakitbovorn, G. Zulauf, S. Chakraborty and J. Rivas-Davila, &amp;ldquo;High-Frequency Bidirectional Resonant Converter for High Conversion Ratio and Variable Load Operation,&amp;rdquo; 2018 IEEE 19th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics (COMPEL), 2018, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109/COMPEL.2018.8459962.
Summary:     Applying RF circuit design techniques to dc-dc resonant converters has enabled the switching frequency to be pushed well beyond 10 MHz, resulting in higher power densities and faster transient response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Student Paper Award</title>
      <link>/blog/2018ecceasia/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018ecceasia/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Kawin (North) Surakitbovorn at the award ceremony  K. Surakitbovorn and J. Rivas-Davilla, “Design of a GaN-Based Wireless Power Transfer System at 13.56 MHz to Replace Conventional Wired Connection in a Vehicle,” 2018 International Power Electronics Conference (IPEC-Niigata 2018 -ECCE Asia), 2018, pp. 3848-3854, doi: 10.23919/IPEC.2018.8507473.
Abstract Wired connections running through the doors, hatchbacks, and trunks of a vehicle are subjected to extensive mechanical wear from repeated bending caused by the open-and-close motion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SUPER-Lab undergrad intern featured in Stanford EE Spotligh</title>
      <link>/blog/2017sabera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017sabera/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Sabera J. Talukder  How did you become interested in your research area? There are two research avenues that I am extremely interested in: one is neuroengineering and the second is creating systems to help people in third world countries. For as long as I can remember I have been interested in the brain, and experiences like interning for Medtronic’s Deep Brain Stimulation division cemented my desire to pursue neuroengineering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2015 IEEE COMPEL Best Paper Award.</title>
      <link>/blog/2015compel_luke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015compel_luke/</guid>
      <description>L. Raymond, W. Liang, L. Gu and J. R. Davila, &amp;ldquo;13.56 MHz high voltage multi-level resonant DC-DC converter,&amp;rdquo; 2015 IEEE 16th Workshop on Control and Modeling for Power Electronics (COMPEL), 2015, pp. 1-8, doi: 10.1109/COMPEL.2015.7236446.
Abstract     This paper demonstrates a dc-dc converter that combines resonant rectifiers in a way to achieve impedance matching and significant voltage gains without the need for a high quality factor (Q) impedance matching network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prof. Rivas featured in Stanford EE spotlight</title>
      <link>/blog/2014eespotlight_rivas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2014eespotlight_rivas/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Electrical Engineering Professor Juan Rivas-Davila loves being in the midst of top-notch Stanford students, world-class research facilities and within a community brimming with entrepreneurial attitudes.  EE spotlight What made you decide to be a professor, and what made you want to be at Stanford? After grad school, I spent a few years working at GE Global Research. There I learned electrical engineering research can change (and has changed) the world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
