<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IEEE TPELS on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/ieee-tpels/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IEEE TPELS on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/ieee-tpels/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Single-Turn Air-Core Coils for High-Frequency Inductive Wireless Power Transfer</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>The efficiency of megahertz-frequency inductive wireless power transfer designs is currently limited by the quality factor of the resonant tanks and the coils. In this article, we use two-dimensional finite-element analysis to optimize the cross section of single-turn air-core inductors for this application and demonstrate coils for wireless power at high-frequency and very-high-frequency industrial, scientific, and medical (ISM) bands. Our resonant tanks achieve diameter-normalized quality factors (Q d ) that are 25%-70% better than the state of the art for air-core coils at 6.78 MHz (Q d = 73 cm -1 ) and 13.56 MHz (102), and we show significant improvements at the 27.12 MHz (123) and 40.68 MHz (137) ISM bands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hybrid Cockcroft–Walton/Dickson Multiplier for High Voltage Generation</title>
      <link>/publication/hybrid_cockroft-walton-dickson-hv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/hybrid_cockroft-walton-dickson-hv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a voltage multiplier topology that is a hybrid between a Cockcroft-Walton multiplier and a Dickson charge pump. The Cockcroft-Walton structure exhibits significant output voltage drop under load as the number of multiplier stage increases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to provide a road map for selecting power devices in soft-switched, megahertz (MHz) frequency power converters. Minimizing $C_{OSS}$ losses, which occur when charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor of power semiconductors, is critical to efficient operation. These losses are excluded from manufacturer-provided information, and measurements are either sparse or not reported at all in the existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing an Impedance Compression Network to Compensate for Misalignments in a Wireless Power Transfer System</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-icn-wpt-choi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-icn-wpt-choi/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents an impedance compression network (ICN) design in a wireless power transfer (WPT) system to compensate for distance or alignment variations between coils. In order to reduce coil impedance variation, we propose an ICN that compresses variations in coil impedance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duty Cycle and Frequency Modulations in Class-E DC–DC Converters for a Wide Range of Input and Output Voltages</title>
      <link>/publication/duty-cycle-fm-classe-dcdc-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/duty-cycle-fm-classe-dcdc-park/</guid>
      <description>We present an operation scheme for a dc-dc converter consisting of a class-E inverter and a class-E rectifier to always achieve zero-voltage zero-dv/dt switching at a wide range of input and output voltages. Experiments demonstrate the prototype converter maintaining the desired soft-switching condition under 80-200-V input voltage and 5-20-V output voltage variations. In an additional prototype, we implemented a similar design with synchronous rectification that achieves a peak efficiency of 92.3% at an input voltage of 80 V, an output voltage of 12 V, and an output power of 26.9 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COSS Losses in 600 V GaN Power Semiconductors in Soft-Switched, High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-coss-gan_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>We report losses from charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor, COSS , in Gallium Nitride (GaN) power devices with voltage ratings over 600 VDS. These losses are of particular importance in soft-switched circuits used at MHz switching frequencies, where the output capacitance of the device is charged and discharged once per switching cycle during the device off-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide-Input-Range High-Efficiency Step-Down Power Factor Correction Converter Using a Variable Frequency Multiplier Technique,</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a step-down power factor preregulator design that achieves a high efficiency across the entire universal input voltage range (85-265 V rms ) for an offline power supply application. The proposed circuit allows MOSFETs with lower voltage ratings and better conduction/switching characteristics to be used in both converter stages. A scaling law of power losses versus breakdown voltage requirement for boost circuit under the condition of the same output power is presented. Experimental results demonstrated a flatter high efficiency performance across a wide input range.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of a Class-DE Rectifier with Shunt Inductance and Nonlinear Capacitance for High-Voltage Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-de-rectifier-hv_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-de-rectifier-hv_park/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a design method for a resonant class-DE rectifier with a shunt inductance input network. In this paper, we propose a design procedure that begins with universal design curves that are applicable regardless of the capacitance nonlinearity. This is followed by parameter selection and a convergence check to ensure the rectifier operates at the desired output voltage. Based on the outlined procedure, we design and experimentally verify a 27-MHz 350-V current-driven rectifier, a 25-MHz 500-V voltage-driven rectifier, and a 27.12-MHz 2-kV four-stage rectifier, all of which the resonant capacitor is nonlinear and the input impedance is resistive at the switching frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
