<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resonant Power Conversion on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/resonant-power-conversion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resonant Power Conversion on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/resonant-power-conversion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimized Design of Multi-MHz Frequency Isolated Auxiliary Power Supply for Gate Drivers in Medium-Voltage Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/mhz-isolated-auxps-gatedrive_spro/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/mhz-isolated-auxps-gatedrive_spro/</guid>
      <description>This article presents the design and optimization of a suitable topology for an isolated dc–dc auxiliary power supply with high isolation voltage and low coupling capacitance. The converter consists of a GaN HEMT inverter operating at 6.78 MHz, an LCC resonance tank, and a class-E low dv/dt rectifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Fabrication of Three-Dimensional Printed Air-Core Transformers for High-Frequency Power Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</guid>
      <description>This article presents various designs of toroidal air-core transformers utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
