<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kawin Surakitbovorn on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/kawin-surakitbovorn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kawin Surakitbovorn on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/kawin-surakitbovorn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Kawin Surakitbovorn</title>
      <link>/labpeople/kawin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/kawin/</guid>
      <description>Doctoral Dissertation   On the design and optimization of RF power amplifiers using wide bandgap devices      Presented March 2021 Manuscript available here.  Summary     Compact radio-frequency (RF) power amplifiers are essential building blocks in various applications, including radio transmission, medical imaging, wireless power transfer, industrial plasma generation, and micro-satellite propulsion. Over the past decades, new wide bandgap (WBG) semiconductor devices, particularly gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), were successfully commercialized.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing a high-efficiency RF power amplifier for plasma generation</title>
      <link>/project/daihensystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/daihensystemx/</guid>
      <description>   Figure 1: Photograph of a 40.68MHz PA develped for this project  Summary There are two main objectives centering around making the previously proposed technology viable for generating plasma The first goal is to develop the control technology for multilevel pulsing and arbitrary waveform envelope. The second goal is to improve and expand the mismatch load range of the amplifier.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modular ON/OFF and Phase-Shifting for High-Speed Radio Frequency Power Modulation</title>
      <link>/publication/modular-onoff-phaseshift-rfpm_north/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/modular-onoff-phaseshift-rfpm_north/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we present an alternative power modulation method to create a high-efficiency high-speed RF amplifier system. This control technique utilizes two mechanisms, modular on/off and phase-shifting. In modular on/off, a different number of sub-circuits are turned “on” or “off” to crudely adjust the output power.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
