<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jason Poon on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/jason-poon/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Jason Poon on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/jason-poon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dr. Jason Poon</title>
      <link>/labpeople/jasonpoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/jasonpoon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Selective Harmonic Minimization using a Hybrid Analog/Digital Computing Method</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-harmonic-analog-digital-computing_poon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-harmonic-analog-digital-computing_poon/</guid>
      <description>We present a hybrid analog/digital computing circuit to solve a selective harmonic minimization problem. The approach leverages favorable attributes of digital and analog controllers to yield a fast and scalable optimization solver. We present a specific realization of the computing circuit that solves for eight independent switching angles for a quarter-wave symmetric PWM driven two-level single-phase inverter. Seven undesired harmonics are minimized while retaining control over modulation index. The proposed computing circuit is verified with simulations and a PCB hardware implementation. The experimental results demonstrate that the proposed circuit can converge to the optimal solution in less than 5 ms, which is substantially faster than existing methods and facilitates real-time implementation. Moreover, the steady-state power consumption of the PCB implementation is approximately 750 mW, which is also significantly lower than published methods for comparable applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mixed-signal computing for online optimization of power electronics systems</title>
      <link>/project/mixedsignalcomputing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/mixedsignalcomputing/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: PCB prototype  Mixed-signal computing for online optimization of power electronics systems Online optimization and optimal control techniques can substantially improve the efficiency, performance, and reliability of many power electronics systems. Some examples include model predictive direct torque control for motor drives, maximum power point tracking for renewable energy applications, and the optimal power flow problem for electric grids. Moreover, there are emerging trends towards increasingly advanced optimization techniques based on machine learning and artificial intelligence that can provide further benefit to many applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Carrier Phase Shifting for Optimal Harmonic Minimization in Asymmetric Parallel-Connected Inverters</title>
      <link>/publication/decentralized-harmonic-minimization-parallel-inverters_poon/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/decentralized-harmonic-minimization-parallel-inverters_poon/</guid>
      <description>This article presents a carrier phase shifting technique for minimizing the aggregate harmonics in networks of asymmetric parallel-connected inverters for distributed power generation system applications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
