<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Resonant Converters on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/resonant-converters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Resonant Converters on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/resonant-converters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to provide a road map for selecting power devices in soft-switched, megahertz (MHz) frequency power converters. Minimizing $C_{OSS}$ losses, which occur when charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor of power semiconductors, is critical to efficient operation. These losses are excluded from manufacturer-provided information, and measurements are either sparse or not reported at all in the existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duty Cycle and Frequency Modulations in Class-E DC–DC Converters for a Wide Range of Input and Output Voltages</title>
      <link>/publication/duty-cycle-fm-classe-dcdc-park/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/duty-cycle-fm-classe-dcdc-park/</guid>
      <description>We present an operation scheme for a dc-dc converter consisting of a class-E inverter and a class-E rectifier to always achieve zero-voltage zero-dv/dt switching at a wide range of input and output voltages. Experiments demonstrate the prototype converter maintaining the desired soft-switching condition under 80-200-V input voltage and 5-20-V output voltage variations. In an additional prototype, we implemented a similar design with synchronous rectification that achieves a peak efficiency of 92.3% at an input voltage of 80 V, an output voltage of 12 V, and an output power of 26.9 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wide-Input-Range High-Efficiency Step-Down Power Factor Correction Converter Using a Variable Frequency Multiplier Technique,</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-wide-input-step-down-pfc-variable-freq_gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper demonstrates a two-stage implementation of a step-down power factor preregulator design that achieves a high efficiency across the entire universal input voltage range (85-265 V rms ) for an offline power supply application. The proposed circuit allows MOSFETs with lower voltage ratings and better conduction/switching characteristics to be used in both converter stages. A scaling law of power losses versus breakdown voltage requirement for boost circuit under the condition of the same output power is presented. Experimental results demonstrated a flatter high efficiency performance across a wide input range.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
