<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patent on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/categories/patent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patent on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/patent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apparatuses and methods involving power conversion using multiple rectifier circuits</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us11228252_hv-rect/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us11228252_hv-rect/</guid>
      <description>An apparatus including direct-current (DC)-alternating-current (AC) inverter circuitry, first and second circuits, and output circuitry. The DC-AC inverter circuitry inverts a DC input signal corresponding to an input voltage to an AC signal. The first circuit and second circuits respectively include inductive isolation circuits driven in response to power from the at least one AC signal, and rectifier circuits that responds to the inductive isolation circuits by outputting first and second rectified signals, where at least one of the first and second rectifier circuits characterized as being limited by a voltage breakdown rating. The output circuitry provides a DC output voltage signal and to cascade a plurality of signals, including the first and second rectified signals, to provide a voltage source that is dependent on the first and second rectified signals and greater than voltage breakdown rating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Circuitry and methodology benefiting from reduced gate loss</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us11101792b2_sic-gan-cascode/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us11101792b2_sic-gan-cascode/</guid>
      <description>In specific examples, aspects are directed towards eliminating, mitigating or reducing gate loss in circuits including, for example, WBG power devices. One such example is directed towards an apparatus including first and second types of field-effect transistor (FET), where the first type is characterized as being a normally-on FET in a switching-circuit operation with a high-voltage rating, and the second type of FET is characterized as being a normally-off FET in a switching-circuit operation with a voltage rating that is much less than the high-voltage rating of the first type of FET circuit. The FET are arranged in a cascode manner so that, in response to a switching control signal received by the second type of FET circuit, the second type of FET circuit is active to drive the first type of FET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Passive components for electronic circuits using conformal deposition on a scaffold</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us11031179/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us11031179/</guid>
      <description>Precision fabrication of 3D objects is used for fabricating passive electrical components. A 3D scaffold is fabricated and then electrically conductive and/or insulating layers are deposited on the scaffold to form the electrical component.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bipolar DC-DC converter topology using passive voltage reversal</title>
      <link>/publication/patent-us10998823/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/patent-us10998823/</guid>
      <description>A resonant DC-DC converter for generating high voltage MHz bi-polar DC pulses includes a left multi-level resonant rectifier bank [100] connected to a positive electrode [104] and coupled via capacitive isolation to a left RF amplifier terminal [128]; a right multi-level resonant rectifier bank [102] connected to a negative electrode [106] and coupled via capacitive isolation to a right RF amplifier terminal [130]. Each multi-level resonant rectifier bank comprises multiple resonant rectifier stages [112-122], where each stage comprises two capacitors for capacitively isolating the stage, an output capacitor, a MOSFET switch connected to an adjacent MOSFET switch of an adjacent stage, and a gating resonant circuit connected to the MOSFET switch, whereby MOSFET switches in the banks can be passively controlled by RF signals from a left RF amplifier and a right RF amplifier.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolated multi-level resonant topologies for wide-range power conversion and impedance matching</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-pcb-converter_liang/</guid>
      <description>Resonant power converters that replace the conventional impedance matching stage with series or parallel connections between resonant inverters and resonant rectifiers are provided. Two or more resonant rectifiers can be connected in series or in parallel to the resonant inverter to provide impedance matching. Similarly, two or more resonant inverters can be connected in series or in parallel to the resonant rectifier to provide impedance matching. Electrical isolation of DC voltage between input and output is provided using only capacitors.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
