<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Class E on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/class-e/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Class E on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/class-e/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Miniature High-Voltage DC-DC Power Converters for Space and Micro-Robotic Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-hvdc-space-micro-robots_park/</guid>
      <description>We develop a small and lightweight high-voltage high-gain power converter for applications where weight and size are premium. By driving a Dickson and Cockcroft-Walton voltage multiplier with a megahertz-frequency class-E inverter, we implement two converters, one that achieves 40 V-to-2 kV conversion with 16 cm 3 box volume and the other that achieves 3.7 V-to-2.9 kV conversion with 0.2 cm 3 box volume and 0.49 g weight. Presented converters achieve comparable or better power density and specific power to those of commercial high-voltage power supplies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Optimal Input Voltage of a Class-E Power Amplifier with GaN HEMTs at MHz Frequency Operation</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-classe-optimalvoltage_surakitbovorn/</guid>
      <description>We mathematically analyze the operation of a Class-E amplifier when facing with this Coss loss term. We have found that the conventional wisdom of using the highest input voltage to get the best efficiency no longer holds above a certain frequency. Furthermore, to allow this new loss term to be easily simulated, we propose a distributed loss model for the Coss loss based on a generalized Steinmetz equation (GSE).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
