<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zikang Tong on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/zikang-tong/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zikang Tong on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/zikang-tong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zikang Tong</title>
      <link>/labpeople/zikangtong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/zikangtong/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiC, GaN and Si technology comparison for high power RF plasma generators</title>
      <link>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</guid>
      <description>   Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Summary We are studying the electric properties of SiC and GaN devices to design high power, high frequency RF plasma generators
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The modeling and understanding high frequency losses in SiC and GaN devices</title>
      <link>/project/onsemisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/onsemisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs The origin of Coss and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origins of Soft-switching Coss Losses in SiC Power MOSFETs and Diodes for Resonant Converter Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</guid>
      <description>The recent development and commercialization of wide bandgap (WBG) power semiconductors, specifically gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), has driven the increase in switching frequency for soft-switching power converters like the Class E, Class Φ2, and Class DE resonant inverters and rectifiers. However, prior literature has characterized numerous commercial GaN and SiC devices using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and discovered significant large-signal charge-voltage hysteresis of the Coss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Fabrication of Three-Dimensional Printed Air-Core Transformers for High-Frequency Power Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</guid>
      <description>This article presents various designs of toroidal air-core transformers utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
