<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zikang Tong on SUPER-Lab</title>
    <link>/tags/zikang-tong/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zikang Tong on SUPER-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/zikang-tong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zikang Tong</title>
      <link>/labpeople/zikangtong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/labpeople/zikangtong/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wideband PPT Class Φ2 Inverter using Phase-Switched Impedance Modulation and Reactance Compensation</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-wideband-pp2-phi2-reactance-compensatoin_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-wideband-pp2-phi2-reactance-compensatoin_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper we experimentally demonstrate a 300 W PA for a 50 Ω load impedance using silicon (Si) devices. The PA achieves above 90% efficiency over approximately a 30% fractional bandwidth. In addition, the PA can also operate across broadband with light loads, where above 80% efficiency is maintained for up to 5 times higher load resistances. This switch-mode PA is one of the first to demonstrate such performance under load variation across a wide bandwidth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SiC, GaN and Si technology comparison for high power RF plasma generators</title>
      <link>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/lamresearchsystemx/</guid>
      <description>   Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Summary We are studying the electric properties of SiC and GaN devices to design high power, high frequency RF plasma generators
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The modeling and understanding high frequency losses in SiC and GaN devices</title>
      <link>/project/onsemisystemx/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/onsemisystemx/</guid>
      <description>Figure 1: Electrostatic potential contours under large-signal excitation at 1 MHz. (a) Deep buffer traps added at 0.98 eV. (b) Shallow buffer traps added at 0.5 eV.  Small- and Large-Signal Dynamic Output Capacitance and Energy Loss in GaN-on-Si Power HEMTs The origin of Coss and the energy dissipation due to output capacitance can be roughly separated into two types: resistive loss and capacitive hysteresis loss. The resistive losses are due to the resistance of gallium nitride (GaN) buffer layers and Si-substrate.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origins of Soft-switching Coss Losses in SiC Power MOSFETs and Diodes for Resonant Converter Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ss-coss-sic-resonant_tong/</guid>
      <description>The recent development and commercialization of wide bandgap (WBG) power semiconductors, specifically gallium nitride (GaN) and silicon carbide (SiC), has driven the increase in switching frequency for soft-switching power converters like the Class E, Class Φ2, and Class DE resonant inverters and rectifiers. However, prior literature has characterized numerous commercial GaN and SiC devices using the Sawyer-Tower circuit and discovered significant large-signal charge-voltage hysteresis of the Coss.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inductorless Soft Switching DC-DC Converter with an Optimized Piezoelectric Resonator</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-inductorless-softswitching-piezoelectric-resonator_braun/</guid>
      <description>The inductor presents one of the biggest obstacles in miniaturizing power electronics. In this paper we present a piezoelectric resonator for power conversion fabricated out of lithium niobate, a material that has several advantages for high frequency power conversion compared to the more commonly used PZT ceramics. The piezoelectric resonator is used in a step-down dc-dc converter that achieves zero voltage soft switching and a continuously variable conversion ratio without the use of magnetic components. The converter operates at 6.3MHz and has a maximum power output of 30W at an efficiency of 92.7%, achieving a power density of 16.7 W/cm 3</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design and Fabrication of Three-Dimensional Printed Air-Core Transformers for High-Frequency Power Applications</title>
      <link>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/3d-aircore-xfm_tong/</guid>
      <description>This article presents various designs of toroidal air-core transformers utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gate Drive for Very Fast Resonant Conversion using SiC Switch</title>
      <link>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/ecce-gatedrive-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high-frequency: namely, the issue of the ability to drive and enhance the MOSFET at these frequencies. We offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multi-resonant gate driver, and use this scheme to drive a SiC MOSFET at 30 MHz in a class-E inverter. The inverter delivers 50 W of RF power, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3-D Printed Air-Core Toroidal Transformer for High-Frequency Power Conversion</title>
      <link>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/compel-3d-aircore-transformer_tong/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents a nested toroidal air-core transformer utilizing a 3-D printing and electroplating fabrication methodology. The first part of this work discusses design equations to achieve the target inductance matrix. Lastly, this work provides experimental demonstrations of the transformer design including a 40.68 MHz 48-to-350 V resonant dc-dc converter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical Circuit Model for Output Capacitance Losses in Silicon Carbide Power Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/apec-coss-sic_tong/</guid>
      <description>In recent reports, a variety of power devices, including wide-bandgap transistors, SiC diodes, and Si superjuction MOSFETs, exhibit losses occurring from hysteretic charging and discharging of their output capacitance (COSS for MOSFETs and CJ for Schottky diodes). Manufacturer SPICE models and datasheets do not report these losses, and are why device power dissipation in simulation significantly contrasts with that in actual converters. However, we propose a viable empirical circuit model that incorporates these losses, with capabilities to integrate into circuit simulation tools such as SPICE.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On the Techniques to Utilize SiC Power Devices in High- and Very High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/singleturn-aircore-hf-wpt_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>n this paper, we explore the challenges of implementing resonant converters using silicon carbide (SiC) power devices at high frequency: namely, the issue of high parasitic inductance packages and the ability to drive and enhance the mosfet at these frequencies. Although power circuit designers have many alternative device technologies to choose from, such as silicon and gallium nitride materials, SiC devices have several advantageous attributes especially in high power applications. As a solution, we study the device performance and parasitics of SiC mosfets in different packaging schemes. We further offer a solution to the challenges of driving SiC devices by demonstrating a multiresonant gate driver and use this scheme to drive an SiC mosfet at 30 MHz and a SiC JFET at 13.56 MHz in a class-E inverter, achieving 85.7% drain efficiency for the mosfet and 93.8% for the JFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Output Capacitance Loss Characterization of Silicon Carbide Schottky Diodes</title>
      <link>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/jestpe-coss-loss-sic-diodes_tong/</guid>
      <description>In high-frequency (HF) and very-high-frequency (VHF) rectifiers, silicon carbide (SiC) Schottky diodes exhibit higher losses compared to what is reported in manufacturer-provided simulation models, with additional power loss stemming from energy dissipation during the charging and discharging of the junction output capacitance (CJ). Here, we compare measured losses across manufacturers, current rating, generation, voltage rating, and packaging of variouis SiC Schottkey diodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Multiresonant Gate Driver for High-Frequency Resonant Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tie-multiresonant-gatedrive-gu/</guid>
      <description>This paper presents the design and implementation of a high-frequency/very high frequency (VHF) multiresonant gate drive circuit. The proposed circuit can reduce the long start-up time required in a self-oscillating resonant gate drive circuit and utilize the fast transient capability of VHF converters better. We demonstrate a prototype resonant gate driver, which reduces up to 60% of the gate-driving power in a 20-MHz 32-W Class-E power amplifier using a Si MOSFET.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Active Power Device Selection in High- and Very-High-Frequency Power Converters</title>
      <link>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/tpels-active-power-device-selection_zulauf/</guid>
      <description>This paper aims to provide a road map for selecting power devices in soft-switched, megahertz (MHz) frequency power converters. Minimizing $C_{OSS}$ losses, which occur when charging and discharging the parasitic output capacitor of power semiconductors, is critical to efficient operation. These losses are excluded from manufacturer-provided information, and measurements are either sparse or not reported at all in the existing literature.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
